<bill session="115" type="s" number="478" updated="2017-09-22T19:45:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hunter and Farmer Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hunter and Farmer Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Migratory Bird Treaty Act to prohibit baiting exemptions on certain land.</title>
    <title type="display">Hunter and Farmer Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2017-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2017-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2017-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3668"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1514"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Hunter and Farmer Protection Act of 2017

This bill amends the Migratory Bird Treaty Act to revise standards for determining what constitutes baiting for purposes of the prohibition on taking migratory game birds.

A baited area, in the case of waterfowl, cranes, and coots, includes a standing, unharvested crop that has been manipulated through activities such as mowing, discing, or rolling, unless the activities are normal agricultural practices. An area is not considered to be a baited area if it: (1) has been treated with a normal agricultural practice, (2) has standing crops that have not been manipulated, or (3) has standing crops that have been or are flooded.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) must submit to the Department of the Interior a report on changes to normal agricultural practices across the range of crops grown by agricultural producers in each region of the United States in which USDA harvest practice recommendations are provided to agricultural producers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
