<bill session="115" type="h" number="2233" updated="2017-09-28T19:15:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Jobs First Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Jobs First Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to improve the H-1B visa program, to repeal the diversity visa lottery program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Jobs First Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2017-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000607" joined="2017-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">American Jobs First Act of 2017

This bill amends the the Immigration and Nationality Act to revise the H-1B nonimmigrant visa (specialty occupation) program, including by declaring that a petitioner employer:

 is offering an annual wage to the H-1B nonimmigrant that is the greater of the annual wage paid to the U.S. citizen or lawful permanent resident employee who did identical or similar work during the previous two years, or $110,000, if offered not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act; will not require an H-1B nonimmigrant to pay a penalty for ending employment before the agreed on date; will not replace or contract to replace a U.S. citizen or lawful permanent resident with one or more nonimmigrants; has not displaced, furloughed, terminated without cause, or otherwise involuntarily separated a U.S. citizen or lawful permanent resident employee during the four-year period beginning two years before the H-1B visa petition was filed; and shall attest in the H-1B application that during the previous two-year period there has not been an employee-initiated strike or an employer-initiated lockout, and that no employee in the same or substantially similar occupational classification has been displaced, terminated without cause, or otherwise involuntarily separated without cause. The bill also revises penalty and transparency requirements and eliminates the H-1B-dependent employer category.

The Department of Labor shall establish a process for the receipt, investigation, and disposition of complaints respecting an employer's: (1) failure to meet an application condition, or (2) misrepresentation of material facts in an application.

No nonimmigrant foreign student present in the United States may be provided U.S. employment authorization under the optional practical training program without an express Act of Congress authorizing such program.

An employer may not require a U.S. citizen or lawful permanent resident employee to sign any nondisparagement or nondisclosure agreement that conditions receipt of any financial or nonfinancial benefit from the employer upon the nondisclosure of the employer's potential misuse of the H-1B visa program.

A U.S. district court shall have jurisdiction to address civil actions by any person claiming H-1B program misuse. A U.S. court of appeals shall have jurisdiction over related appeals for cases originating from a U.S. district court within that circuit. The Supreme Court shall have jurisdiction to address appeals of civil actions by any person claiming H-1B program misuse for cases originating from any U.S. court of appeals.

The bill eliminates the diversity visa lottery program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
