<bill session="115" type="h" number="2590" updated="2017-07-29T07:17:23Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Computer Science for All Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Computer Science for All Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Education to carry out a program to increase access to prekindergarten through grade 12 computer science education.</title>
    <title type="display">Computer Science for All Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2017-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Computer Science for All Act of 2017

This bill establishes a program through which the Department of Education (ED) shall award grants to states, local educational agencies, and eligible tribal schools to serve as models for national replication of computer education expansion efforts. A grant application shall include specified plans that demonstrate the applicant's ability to carry out an ambitious expansion effort for all students, including traditionally underrepresented students.

A grant recipient&#160;shall use the grant funds to:

 train teachers to teach computer science; expand access to high-quality learning materials and online learning options; create plans for expanding overall access to science, technology, engineering, arts, and mathematics (STEAM) classes; utilize computer science as a catalyst for increased interest in STEAM more broadly; reduce course equity gaps for all students; and ensure additional support and resources. A grantee may also use grant funds to:

 build effective regional collaborations, recruit and hire instructional personnel, prepare for effectively sustaining project activities after the grant period ends, and disseminate information about effective practices. At least semi-annually, a grantee must report to ED on specified data related to the number of&#160;students served through program activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
