<bill session="115" type="s" number="832" updated="2017-10-06T04:54:35Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">African Growth and Opportunity Act and Millennium Challenge Act Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">African Growth and Opportunity Act and Millennium Challenge Act Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AGOA and MCA Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AGOA and MCA Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the transparency and accelerate the impact of programs under the African Growth and Opportunity Act and the Millennium Challenge Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">AGOA and MCA Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2017-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-10-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3445"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">African Growth and Opportunity Act and Millennium Challenge Act Modernization Act or the AGOA and MCA Modernization Act

 This bill directs the President to establish a website for the collection and dissemination of information regarding the African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA).

 The Department of State is urged to encourage eligible sub-Saharan African countries to use the benefits available under the African Growth and Opportunity Act.

 The President is urged to:

 facilitate trans-boundary trade among eligible sub-Saharan African countries; provide training for business and government trade officials on accessing AGOA benefits; provide capacity building for African entrepreneurs and trade associations on production strategies, quality standards, and market development; provide capacity building training to promote product diversification and value-added processing; and provide capacity building and technical assistance funding to help African businesses and institutions comply with U.S. counter-terrorism policies. The Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 is amended to permit an eligible country that has entered into a Millennium Challenge Compact to enter into one additional compact under specified conditions.

The bill establishes, beginning with FY2013, new assistance criteria for a low-income or a lower-middle-income candidate country eligible to enter into a Millennium Challenge Compact with the United States.

The Millennium Challenge Corporation shall: (1) before selecting a compact country, provide the Board of Directors with information regarding the country's treatment of civil society; and (2) submit an assessment of the feasibility of developing partnerships at the subnational level within candidate countries.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
