<bill session="115" type="h" number="536" updated="2017-08-07T20:45:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protection From Obamacare Mandates and Congressional Equity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protection From Obamacare Mandates and Congressional Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that the salaries of Members of a House of Congress will be held in escrow if that House has not agreed to a concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2018 by April 15, 2017, and to withhold the salary of the Director of OMB upon failure to submit the President's budget to Congress as required by section 1105 of title 31, United States Code.</title>
    <title type="display">Protection From Obamacare Mandates and Congressional Equity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="429"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protection From Obamacare Mandates and Congressional Equity Act 

This bill withholds the salaries of Members of a house of Congress that has not agreed to a budget resolution for FY2018 by April 15, 2017, as required by the Congressional Budget Act of 1974.

Salaries are withheld from April 16, 2017, until the house of Congress agrees to a budget resolution or the last day of the 115th Congress, whichever is earlier.

The Inspector General of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), by three days after the President's budget is due, shall: (1) make an annual determination of whether the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and the President are in compliance with statutory requirements for the President's annual budget submission to Congress, and (2) provide a written notification of such determination to specified congressional committees.

No funds may be appropriated or otherwise be made available from the Treasury for the pay of the Director, Deputy Director, and Deputy Director for Management of the OMB during any period of noncompliance determined by the OPM Inspector General. Such officials may not receive pay for any period of noncompliance at any time after the end of that period.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
