<bill session="115" type="h" number="1774" updated="2017-09-11T03:02:57Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Developing the Next Generation of Small Businesses Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Developing the Next Generation of Small Businesses Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">SCORE for Small Business Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">SCORE for Small Business Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Small Business Development Centers Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Small Business Development Centers Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Women's Business Centers Improvements Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Women&#8217;s Business Centers Improvements Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to provide for improvements to small business development centers, the women's business center program, the SCORE program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Developing the Next Generation of Small Businesses Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2017-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1680"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1700"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1702"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2810"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Developing the Next Generation of Small Businesses Act of 2017

Small Business Development Centers Improvement Act of 2017

 This bill amends the Small Business Act to revise the authority of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to use certain SBA programs, including the small business development center (SBDC) program, to provide grants, financial assistance, loans, export assistance, and subcontracting opportunities on federal contracts to specified small businesses, organizations, state governments, universities, companies, and other entities that assist smaller enterprises.

The SBA shall:

 use such programs only to deliver entrepreneurial development services, entrepreneurial education, support for the development and maintenance of clusters, or business training (excepts services provided to assist small businesses owned by an Indian tribe); not prohibit SBDC grant recipients from marketing and advertising their services to individuals and small business concerns; and establish a Data Collection Working Group. The SBA may not award SBDC grants to entities other than those that received them before September 30, 2015, and that seek to renew them after that date, with an exception for not-for-profit institutions of higher education.

Women's Business Centers Improvements Act of 2017

 The bill revises the duties of the Office of Women's Business Ownership and declares it is the Office's mission to assist women entrepreneurs to start, grow, and compete in global markets by providing quality support with access to capital, access to markets, job creation, growth, and counseling.

 The SBA shall establish standards for a program to accredit specified eligible entities receiving a grant to operate one or more women's business centers.

SCORE for Small Business Act of 2017

 The bill reauthorizes the SCORE program (Service Corps of Retired Executives) for FY2018-FY2019. The program is renamed as simply the SCORE program.

 The SBA shall award a grant to the SCORE Association (or any successor group) to manage the program.

 The bill prescribes duties of volunteers participating in, and requirements of, the program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
