<bill session="115" type="s" number="1099" updated="2017-09-27T04:45:53Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-03">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the identification and prevention of improper payments and the identification of strategic sourcing opportunities by reviewing and analyzing the use of Federal agency charge cards.</title>
    <title type="display">Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2017-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2017-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson without amendment. With written report No. 115-129.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="169">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 169.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-08-03">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4891" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2017-08-03" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04T12:07:03-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s771"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-08-03T15:12:41Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2017

(Sec. 3) This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to develop a strategy to expand the use of data analytics in managing government purchase and travel charge card programs for the purpose of:

 identifying questionable transactions and developing enhanced tools and methods for agency use in identifying questionable transactions and recovering improper payments; identifying potential opportunities for agencies to further leverage administrative process streamlining and cost reduction from purchase and travel card use; developing a set of purchase and travel card metrics and benchmarks for high risk activities to assist agency purchase and travel card management and oversight activities; and developing a plan to create a library of analytics tools and data sources for use by agencies. (Sec. 4) The OMB must issue guidance on improving information sharing by government agencies, including by:

 requiring relevant officials to identify and communicate information about high-risk activities; requiring appropriate agency officials to review the reports issued by charge card-issuing banks on questionable transaction activity and suspicious timing or amounts of cash withdrawals or advances; providing for the appropriate sharing of information related to potential questionable transactions, fraud schemes, and high risk activities with GSA and appropriate federal officials; and considering the recommendations made by Inspectors General or the best practices Inspectors General have identified. (Sec. 5) The GSA and the OMB must establish a purchase and travel charge card data management group to develop and share best practices.

(Sec. 6) The GSA shall report on: (1) the implementation of this bill, including the metrics used in determining whether the analytic and benchmarking efforts have reduced, or contributed to the reduction of, questionable or improper payments, as well as improved utilization of card-based payment products; and (2) further potential savings opportunities for government agencies under the federal charge card programs.

Each federal agency that issues and uses purchase cards and convenience checks shall report to the OMB on that agency's activities to implement this bill. The OMB must submit to Congress a consolidated report of agency activities to implement this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-129</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
