<bill session="115" type="h" number="2424" updated="2017-09-19T22:00:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Interior to issue new resource management plans applicable to the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area and the Red Cliffs National Conservation Area and a new amendment to the St. George Field Office Resource Management Plan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To require the Secretary of the Interior to issue new resource management plans applicable to the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area and the Red Cliffs National Conservation Area and a new amendment to the St. George Field Office Resource Management Plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="1053"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill prohibits the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) from implementing or enforcing: (1) the resource management plans for the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area or the Red Cliffs National Conservation Area in Utah; or (2) the amendment to the St. George Field Office Resource Management Plan described in the notice of the BLM titled "Notice of Availability of the Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plans for the Beaver Dam Wash and Red Cliffs National Conservation Areas; and Approved Amendment to the St. George Field Office Resource Management Plan in Washington, County, Utah" (published in the Federal Register on December 21, 2016).

In their place the BLM shall issue new resource management plans and a new amendment that are prepared: (1) in accordance with the requirements for comprehensive plans for the long-term management of such conservation areas under the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009, and (2) in coordination with affected local governments in accordance with certain criteria for the development and revision of land use plans under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
