<bill session="115" type="s" number="750" updated="2017-06-19T21:45:34Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep It in the Ground Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep It in the Ground Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit drilling in the outer Continental Shelf, to prohibit coal leases on Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Keep It in the Ground Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2242"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Keep It in the Ground Act of 2017

 This bill amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to prohibit the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management (BOEM) from issuing, renewing, reinstating, or extending any nonproducing lease, or issuing any authorization for the exploration or production of oil, natural gas, or any other fossil fuel in the Arctic Ocean, Atlantic Ocean, Pacific Ocean, Gulf of Mexico, or any other area of the Outer Continental Shelf. BOEM shall also cancel within 60 days any lease issued in the Beaufort Sea, Cook Inlet, or Chukchi Sea (three of the five bodies of water that encompass the Alaska Outer Continental Shelf).

The Bureau of Land Management (BLM) must not issue, renew, reinstate, or extend any nonproducing lease for the exploration or production of any onshore fossil fuels, including coal, oil, tar sands, oil shale, and gas, on land subject to the Mineral Leasing Act.

The bill provides for exceptions if there is an imminent national security threat that would be significantly reduced by granting an exception.

In addition, BOEM and the BLM may allow a nonproducing lease to be renewed or extended if the lease contract was signed before this bill, and giving effect to any provision of this bill is likely to lead to a material breach of contract.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
