<bill session="115" type="h" number="397" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Members of Congress Tax Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Members of Congress Tax Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require Members of Congress to disclose delinquent tax liability and to require an ethics inquiry into, and the garnishment of the wages of, a Member with Federal tax liability.</title>
    <title type="display">Members of Congress Tax Accountability Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000592" joined="2017-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Members of Congress Tax Accountability Act of 2017

This bill amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require Members of Congress to include in their annual financial disclosure reports the amount of any delinquent tax liability owed to the United States or any state or local government entity.

The appropriate congressional ethics committee is required to open an inquiry immediately into the tax delinquency of that Member to determine: (1) his or her total delinquent tax liability and reason for such delinquency, (2) whether the Member has a plan to eliminate it, and (3) whether it has reflected poorly on Congress.

Such Member shall arrange with the Secretary of the Senate or the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, as appropriate, and the Internal Revenue Service to have an appropriate amount of his or her salary designated to pay the taxes owed to the United States within a reasonable time period.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
