<bill session="115" type="h" number="1975" updated="2017-09-19T20:45:07Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cluster Munitions Civilian Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cluster Munitions Civilian Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect civilians from cluster munitions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cluster Munitions Civilian Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000312"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2017-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="897"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Cluster Munitions Civilian Protection Act of 2017

This bill prohibits federal agency funds from being obligated or expended to purchase, transfer, export, or use any cluster munitions unless: (1) the submunitions of such munitions, after arming, do not result in more than 1% unexploded ordnance across the range of intended operational environments; and (2) the policy applicable to the export or transfer of such munitions specifies that they will be used only against clearly defined military targets and not in areas normally inhabited by civilians or where civilians are known to be present.

Expresses the sense of Congress that:

 the Department of Defense should ensure that the July 2008 Gates policy on cluster munitions is being fully implemented and that the United States will no longer use such munitions by the end of 2018 except in compliance with the 1% unexploded ordnance limit; the U.S. government should adopt a policy and develop a strategy to phase out the transfer, export, and use of such munitions; any alternatives that the government develops to replace cluster munitions should be compliant with the Convention on Cluster Munitions; and the United States should take all steps necessary to accede to such convention.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
