<bill session="115" type="s" number="64" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe and Affordable Drugs from Canada Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe and Affordable Drugs from Canada Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to allow for the personal importation of safe and affordable drugs from approved pharmacies in Canada.</title>
    <title type="display">Safe and Affordable Drugs from Canada Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="92"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1480"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safe and Affordable Drugs from Canada Act of 2017

This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to promulgate regulations within 180 days permitting individuals to import a prescription drug purchased from an approved Canadian pharmacy that:

 is dispensed by a pharmacist licensed in Canada; is purchased for personal use in quantities not greater than a 90-day supply; is filled using a valid prescription issued by a physician licensed to practice in the United States; and has the same active ingredients, route of administration, dosage form, and strength as a prescription drug approved under the FFDCA. Certain medications may not be imported, including controlled substances and biological products.

 The bill establishes a certification process for approving Canadian pharmacies. HHS must publish a list of approved Canadian pharmacies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
