<bill session="115" type="s" number="12" updated="2017-09-11T02:36:33Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing the Department of Veterans Affairs Accountability to Veterans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing the Department of Veterans Affairs Accountability to Veterans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Increasing the Department of Veterans Affairs Accountability to Veterans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Increasing the Department of Veterans Affairs Accountability to Veterans Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the accountability of employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Increasing the Department of Veterans Affairs Accountability to Veterans Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-01-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Senate Committee on Veterans' Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3189-3190" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2017-05-25" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3189-3190" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26T10:02:08-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s218"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Increasing the Department of Veterans Affairs Accountability to Veterans Act of 2017

 This bill requires the reduction of the federal annuities of individuals removed from the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) Senior Executive Service (SES) if they are convicted of a felony that was related to their performance while employed in such position.

 The VA may order the reduction of the federal annuities of individuals who were convicted of such a felony and were subject to removal or transfer from the SES, but who left the VA before final action was taken.

 Such annuities are reduced by excluding the covered service performed after the activity that subjects such an individual to transfer or removal.

 Any individual whose annuity is reduced may appeal to the Office of Personnel Management.

 The VA shall conduct an annual performance plan for each political appointee that is similar to the plan conducted for career appointee SES employees.

Evaluation of VA managers shall include actions taken to address employee performance.

The supervisor of a probationary VA employee shall determine during the 30-day period ending on the date on which the probationary period ends whether the employee has demonstrated successful performance and should continue past the probationary period. Such supervisor's performance plan shall include feedback on his or her actions during an employee's probationary period.

Before terminating VA employment an official who has participated personally and substantially during the past year in a VA acquisition that exceeds $10 million shall obtain a written opinion from a VA ethics counselor regarding any restrictions on activities that the official may undertake on behalf of a contractor during the two-year period after the official terminates VA employment.

A contractor may not knowingly provide compensation to such an individual during the two-year period unless the contractor determines that the individual has obtained or requested such written opinion.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
