<bill session="115" type="h" number="1347" updated="2017-06-19T21:15:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ALERT Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ALERT Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Amplifying Local Efforts to Root out Terror Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Amplifying Local Efforts to Root out Terror Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide counter-radicalization training to Department of Homeland Security representatives at State and local fusion centers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">ALERT Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001073" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000601" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2017-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Counterterrorism and Intelligence" code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Amplifying Local Efforts to Root out Terror Act of 2017 or the ALERT Act of 2017

This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to provide training at state and major urban area fusion centers for the purpose of administering community awareness briefings and related activities in furtherance of its efforts to counter radicalization, identify and report suspicious activities, and increase awareness of and more quickly identify terrorism threats, including the travel or attempted travel of individuals from the United States to support a foreign terrorist organization abroad. (A "fusion center" serves as a focal point within the state and local environment for the receipt, analysis, gathering, and sharing of threat-related information between the federal government and state, local, tribal, territorial and private sector partners.)

The bill directs DHS to assess its efforts to support countering radicalization at the state, local, tribal, and territorial levels. Such assessment shall include:

 a cataloging of DHS efforts to assist state, local, tribal, and territorial governments in countering radicalization; a review of cooperative agreements between DHS and such governments relating to countering radicalization; and an evaluation of DHS plans and any potential opportunities to better support such governments that are in furtherance of DHS's countering radicalization objectives and consistent with all relevant constitutional, legal, and privacy protections. DHS shall notify Congress of the number of employees of state, local, tribal, and territorial governments with security clearances sponsored by DHS, including a detailed list of the agencies that employ such employees, the levels of clearance held, and whether such employees are assigned as representatives to state and major urban area fusion centers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
