<bill session="115" type="s" number="570" updated="2017-06-19T21:30:31Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's weather research through a focused program of investment on affordable and attainable advances in observational, computing, and modeling capabilities to support substantial improvement in weather forecasting and prediction of high impact weather events, to expand commercial opportunities for the provision of weather data, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="353"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017

This bill authorizes a number of programs to enhance weather forecasting and alerts at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).

NOAA's Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research must conduct a program to improve forecasting of weather events and their effects, with a special focus on high impact weather events.

The National Weather Service must collect and utilize information to make reliable and timely foundational forecasts of subseasonal and seasonal temperature and precipitation. Subseasonal forecasting is forecasting weather between two weeks and three months and seasonal forecasting is between three months and two years.

The bill provides for technology transfers between the National Weather Service and private sector weather companies and universities to improve forecasting.

NOAA must complete and operationalize the Constellation Observing System for Meteorology, Ionosphere, and Climate (a weather satellite program which develops observational techniques using global navigation systems).

Additionally, NOAA may contract with the private sector to obtain data for weather forecasting.

NOAA must continue its Environmental Information Services Working Group, which advises NOAA on weather research and opportunities to improve communications between weather stakeholders.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
