<bill session="115" type="s" number="929" updated="2017-10-03T04:30:38Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Invest in Rural Small Business Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Invest in Rural Small Business Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Invest in Rural Small Business Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Invest in Rural Small Business Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the HUBZone program.</title>
    <title type="display">Invest in Rural Small Business Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2017-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-26">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-58.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-08-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Risch with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-08-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="197">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 197.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Invest in Rural Small Business Act of 2017

This bill amends the Small Business Act to modify the definition of qualified Historically Underutilized Business Zone (HUBZone) small business concern to reduce from 35% to 33% the number of a small firm's employees required to live within a HUBZone.

The HUBZone program is expanded to include a qualified area located outside of an urbanized area with a population of 50,000 or less (covered area) designated by the Small Business Administration (SBA) in response to a petition by the governor of a state, the District of Columbia, or a U.S. Territory.

The SBA:

 may designate as a HUBZone, in response to a governor's petition, a covered area that has an average unemployment rate at least 120% of the average U.S. or state unemployment rate, whichever is less; shall establish procedures to ensure that it accepts petitions from all states each fiscal year and give an interested governor technical assistance before a petition is filed; and must approve or deny, within 60 days upon receipt, a small business concern's application for certification as a qualified HUBZone small business concern.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
