<bill session="115" type="hr" number="223" updated="2017-06-15T21:00:09Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Calling on the People's Republic of China (PRC) to cease its retaliatory measures against the Republic of Korea in response to the deployment of the U.S. Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD) to U.S. Forces Korea (USFK), and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Calling on the People's Republic of China (PRC) to cease its retaliatory measures against the Republic of Korea in response to the deployment of the U.S. Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD) to U.S. Forces Korea (USFK), and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2017-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2017-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2017-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2017-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000575" joined="2017-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" code="HSFA05" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Strategic Forces" code="HSAS29" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Condemns North Korea's recent ballistic missile tests and its announcement of being in the final stages of a potential intercontinental ballistic missile test. Urges the U.S. government to take all necessary measures to protect its citizens and allies in the region and closely cooperate with the international community to eliminate North Korea's nuclear and ballistic missile programs.

Supports the prompt deployment of the Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD) system to counter the North Korean threat and welcomes the arrival of its first elements into U.S. Forces Korea in South Korea. Commends the South Korean government for its commitment to and cooperation in the effective deployment of THAAD.

Condemns China's retaliatory measures against South Korea in response to such deployment.

Urges the Chinese government to: (1) immediately cease its diplomatic intimidation and economic coercion against South Korea, and (2) pressure North Korea to give up its nuclear and ballistic missile programs instead of undermining South Korea's sovereign right to defend itself.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
