<bill session="115" type="h" number="614" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Our Schools from Tax Delinquents Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Our Schools from Tax Delinquents Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require each owner of a dwelling unit assisted under the section 8 rental assistance voucher program to remain current with respect to local property and school taxes and to authorize a public housing agency to use such rental assistance amounts to pay such tax debt of such an owner, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protect Our Schools from Tax Delinquents Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2017-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2017-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000462" joined="2017-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-23T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect Our Schools from Tax Delinquents Act of 2017

This bill amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to require that each housing assistance payments contract entered into under the Section 8 rental assistance voucher program by a public housing agency (PHA) and the owner of a dwelling unit provide that such owner pay, on a timely basis, all covered taxes validly assessed against the property in which the unit is located.

A "covered tax" is any tax under state or local law assessed upon real property or the revenue of which is dedicated for use only for schools or for costs of education.

The bill allows a contract to provide that, upon notification and identification of a tax delinquency by a taxing authority, the PHA shall abate all of the rental assistance amounts for the property, transferring them monthly to the taxing authority, until the delinquency is eliminated.

The bill does not authorize or establish any cause or grounds for the termination of the tenancy of any tenant from any dwelling unit assisted under the rental assistance voucher program.

The Department of Housing and Urban Development must maintain a database of information regarding owners of dwelling units: (1) assisted under the program whose housing assistance payments contracts have been terminated for noncompliance with the requirements of this bill, and (2) with respect to whom assistance amounts have been abated and transferred to a taxing authority.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
