<bill session="115" type="h" number="47" updated="2017-07-28T07:15:46Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Effective and Humane Treatment of Youth Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Effective and Humane Treatment of Youth Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kalief's Law</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kalief&#8217;s Law</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide for the humane treatment of youths who are in police custody, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Kalief's Law</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2017-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Effective and Humane Treatment of Youth Act of 2017 or Kalief's Law

This legislation amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to reauthorize the Juvenile Accountability Block Grant (JABG) program for FY2018-FY2022.

 It requires a state or local government that receives JABG funding to implement policies that, with respect to youth: (1) provide a right to speedy trial; (2) provide a right to timely bail consideration; and (3) restrict solitary confinement. The term "youth" means an individual who is 21 years of age or younger.

 Additionally, it requires a state or local government that receives funding under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program or the Community Oriented Policing Services program to implement policies and training on police-youth interaction.

 The legislation amends the federal criminal code to: (1) require youth custodial interrogations to be recorded; (2) prohibit youth solitary confinement, except as a temporary response to serious and harmful behavior; and (3) prohibit youth restraints during courtroom proceedings, except in certain circumstances.

DOJ must report to Congress on youth solitary confinement, including: (1) types and conditions; and (2) number of instances broken down by age, race, ethnicity, gender, and unique circumstances.

The bill directs DOJ to award grants to states and local governments to record youth custodial interrogations.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
