<bill session="115" type="s" number="1022" updated="2017-09-27T05:22:36Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Injury Surgical Systems Integrated Operationally Nationwide to Achieve ZERO Preventable Deaths Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Injury Surgical Systems Integrated Operationally Nationwide to Achieve ZERO Preventable Deaths Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MISSION ZERO Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MISSION ZERO Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to facilitate assignment of military trauma care providers to civilian trauma centers in order to maintain military trauma readiness and to support such centers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">MISSION ZERO Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2017-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2017-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2017-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="880"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-03T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Military Injury Surgical Systems Integrated Operationally Nationwide to Achieve ZERO Preventable Deaths Act or the MISSION ZERO Act

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response to award grants to certain trauma centers to enable military trauma care providers and trauma teams to provide trauma care and related acute care at those trauma centers. Funds may be used to train and incorporate military trauma care providers into the trauma center, including expenditures for malpractice insurance, office space, information technology, specialty education and supervision, trauma programs, and state license fees. Grantees must allow the military trauma care providers to be deployed for military operations, training, or response to a mass casualty incident.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
