<bill session="115" type="s" number="319" updated="2017-07-20T16:56:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Veterans Exposed to Burn Pits Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Veterans Exposed to Burn Pits Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish within the Department of Veterans Affairs a center of excellence in the prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits.</title>
    <title type="display">Helping Veterans Exposed to Burn Pits Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2017-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2017-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1279"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Helping Veterans Exposed to Burn Pits Act

 This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a center of excellence in the prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures in Afghanistan or Iraq.

The VA shall, in selecting the center's site, consider entities that:

 are equipped with the specialized equipment needed to study, diagnose, and treat health conditions relating to such exposure; have a track record of publishing information on post-deployment health exposures among veterans who served in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom; have access to animal models and in vitro models of dust immunology and lung injury consistent with the injuries of members of the Armed Forces who served in support of such operations; and have expertise in allergy, immunology, and pulmonary diseases. The VA shall ensure that the center collaborates with the Department of Defense (DOD), institutions of higher education, and other appropriate public and private entities to:

 provide for dissemination within the VA of best practices for the treatment of such conditions and the training of health professionals, provide guidance for the VA and DOD health systems in determining the personnel required to provide quality health care for members of the Armed Forces and veterans with such conditions, establish, and oversee a program to train VA and DOD health professionals in the treatment of such conditions, facilitate advancements in the study of the short-term and long-term effects of such exposure, conduct basic science and translational research on such conditions for the purposes of understanding the etiology of such conditions and developing preventive interventions and new treatments, and provide medical treatment to veterans diagnosed with medical conditions specific to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures. The center shall have access to and make use of the data accumulated by the burn pits registry.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
