<bill session="115" type="h" number="268" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:23Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Neighborhood Noise Barriers Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Neighborhood Noise Barriers Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Highway System Designation Act of 1995 to permit the construction of certain noise barriers with funds from the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Neighborhood Noise Barriers Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000287"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Neighborhood Noise Barriers Act of 2017

This bill amends the National Highway System Designation Act of 1995 to allow the use of funds out of the Highway Trust Fund to construct a Type II noise barrier along a federal-aid highway if such barrier:

 is part of a project approved by the Department of Transportation before November 28, 1995; or separates a highway or other noise corridor from a group of structures of which the majority of those closest to the highway or noise corridor are residential in nature and which either were constructed before the construction or most recent widening of the highway or noise corridor or are at least 10 years old. The bill makes the planning, design, or construction of a Type II noise barrier eligible for surface transportation block grant program funding.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
