<bill session="115" type="sr" number="162" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:35Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution reaffirming the commitment of the United States to promoting religious freedom, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution reaffirming the commitment of the United States to promoting religious freedom, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2017-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2017-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001202" joined="2017-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2920-2921" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to promoting religious freedom as a fundamental human right.

Calls for the President to: (1) strengthen U.S. foreign policy on behalf of individuals persecuted in foreign countries on account of religion; (2) develop an action plan on international religious freedom and integrate that plan into U.S. diplomatic, development, and national security strategies; and (3) develop a strategic plan to direct grants for implementing innovative programs in key countries to train and work with local religious leaders on the importance of pluralistic societies, rights guaranteed under international law, and reporting mechanisms available within international institutions.

Urges the State Department to: (1)&#160; implement Frank Wolf International Religious Freedom Act provisions that direct the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center to conduct training on religious freedom for all Foreign Service officers and all outgoing deputy chiefs of mission and ambassadors, and&#160; (2) develop a training curriculum for American diplomats in international religious freedom policy.

Urges: (1) the President, the State Department, and relevant agencies to develop a comprehensive response to protect victims of genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes and to provide humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery assistance to affected individuals from religious and ethnic groups in Iraq and Syria; (2) the President and the State Department to reestablish the Religion and Foreign Policy Working Group; and (3) the President, State Department, and U.S. Trade Representative to ensure that trade negotiations include religious freedom conditions mandated by the Bipartisan Congressional Trade Priorities and Accountability Act of 2015.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
