<bill session="115" type="hj" number="98" updated="2017-07-17T13:15:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000601"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2017-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hj" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1"/>
    <bill type="hj" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
    <bill type="hj" session="115" relation="unknown" number="14"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Constitutional Amendment This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment prohibiting total outlays for a fiscal year from exceeding total receipts for that fiscal year unless Congress authorizes the excess by a two-thirds roll call vote of each chamber. The prohibition excludes outlays for repayment of debt principal and receipts derived from borrowing. The amendment also:

 prohibits total outlays for any fiscal year from exceeding 18% of the economic output of the United States unless two-thirds of each chamber of Congress provides a specific increase in outlays above this amount; requires a three-fourths roll call vote of each chamber of Congress to increase the public debt limit; requires a two-thirds roll call vote of each chamber of Congress to increase revenue; requires the President to transmit to Congress a proposed balanced budget each year and prohibits the President from being compensated if the requirement is not met; and requires Congress to consider and approve a balanced budget each year and prohibits Members of Congress from being compensated if the requirement is not met. Congress may waive these requirements when a declaration of war is in effect or if the United States is engaged in a military conflict which causes an imminent and serious military threat to national security.

The amendment prohibits a court from entering an order in any action that results in an increase in the collection of revenue.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
