<bill session="115" type="h" number="413" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Early Pell Promise Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Early Pell Promise Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an Early Federal Pell Grant Commitment Program.</title>
    <title type="display">Early Pell Promise Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000581"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Early Pell Promise Act

This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Department of Education to carry out a program of grants to state educational agencies under which a student who is in eighth grade and is eligible for a free or reduced price lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act may be provided a commitment to receive a Federal Pell Grant early in the student's academic career.

Pursuant to such a commitment, the student shall receive a Pell Grant during the first two years of attendance at an institution of higher education (IHE) as an undergraduate if the student:

 files the FAFSA form during the senior year of secondary school and the succeeding year, and enrolls at the IHE not later than three years after receiving a secondary school diploma or after release from the Armed Forces. A student may not receive the early Pell Grant for a succeeding year if the expected family contribution for either year is more than twice the threshold amount for Pell Grant eligibility for that year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
