<bill session="115" type="h" number="2802" updated="2017-06-19T22:37:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">First-Time Homebuyer Savings Account Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">First-Time Homebuyer Savings Account Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a tax-preferred savings account for first-time homebuyers.</title>
    <title type="display">First-Time Homebuyer Savings Account Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001185" joined="2017-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">First-Time Homebuyer Savings Account Act of 2017

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for tax-preferred savings accounts for first-time homebuyers. An individual may make up to $14,000 per year in after-tax contributions to the account, subject to a $50,000 lifetime contribution limit, a $150,000 limit on the fair market value of the account, and adjustments for inflation after 2018.

Distributions from the account that are used to pay the qualified principal residence purchase expenditures of the designated beneficiary are excluded from gross income. A "qualified principal residence purchase expenditure" is, with respect to a designated beneficiary who is a first-time homebuyer, any amount: (1) paid toward the purchase price of a principal residence of the beneficiary, (2) required to be paid to settle the purchase of such residence, or (3) required to be paid by the beneficiary to obtain acquisition indebtedness with respect to the residence.

Excess contributions to the account, distributions that exceed the qualified principal residence purchase expenditures of the beneficiary, and distributions that are not used for first-time homebuyer purposes are subject to specified taxes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
