<bill session="115" type="s" number="88" updated="2017-09-11T02:36:35Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-03">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DIGIT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DIGIT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">DIGIT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure appropriate spectrum planning and interagency coordination to support the Internet of Things.</title>
    <title type="display">DIGIT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2017-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-01-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-01-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-06-05">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune without amendment. With written report No. 115-90.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="113">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 113.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-08-03">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4819" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-08-03" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04T13:06:33-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="686"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s769"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-06-05T14:43:36Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act or the DIGIT Act

(Sec. 2) This bill expresses the sense of Congress that policies governing the Internet of Things (IoT) should maximize the potential and development of the growing number of connected and interconnected devices to benefit businesses, governments, and consumers.

(Sec. 4) The Department of Commerce must convene a working group of federal stakeholders to provide recommendations and a report to Congress regarding the IoT. The bill establishes a steering committee to be composed of stakeholders outside the federal government to advise the working group.

The working group must: (1) identify federal laws and regulations, grant practices, budgetary or jurisdictional challenges, and other sector-specific policies that inhibit IoT development; (2) consider policies or programs that encourage and improve coordination among federal agencies with IoT jurisdiction; (3) implement recommendations from the steering committee; (4) examine how federal agencies can benefit from, use, prepare for, and secure the IoT; and (5) consult with nongovernmental stakeholders.

The steering committee must advise the working group about laws, budgets, spectrum needs, individual privacy, security, small business challenges, and any international proceedings or negotiations affecting the IoT.

Within 18 months after enactment of this bill, the working group must report its findings and recommendations, its reasons for inaction on steering committee recommendations, and an accounting of any progress by federal agencies to implement recommendations.

(Sec. 5) The Federal Communications Commission must: (1) seek public comment on the IoT's spectrum needs, regulatory barriers, and growth with licensed and unlicensed spectrum; and (2) submit a summary of those comments to Congress.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-90</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
