<bill session="115" type="h" number="572" updated="2017-06-22T07:15:40Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the export of United States agricultural products to Cuba as authorized by the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000, to remove impediments to the export to Cuba of medical devices and medicines, to allow travel to Cuba by United States legal residents, to establish an agricultural export promotion program with respect to Cuba, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2017-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000127" joined="2017-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, the Judiciary, Agriculture, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Trade" code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2017

 This bill prohibits the President from restricting direct transfers from a Cuban depository institution to a U.S. depository institution in payment for a product authorized for sale under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000.

The Department of Agriculture shall provide information and technical assistance to U.S. agricultural producers, cooperative organizations, or state agencies to promote U.S. agricultural exports products to Cuba.

The bill authorizes the issuance of temporary entry visas to Cuban nationals to facilitate purchase of U.S. agricultural products.

The Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 is amended to repeal the prohibition on enforcement of rights to certain U.S. intellectual properties and such properties' transfer.

The bill prohibits the regulation or prohibition of travel to or from Cuba by U.S. citizens or legal residents, or any of the transactions ordinarily incident to such travel, if such travel would be lawful in the United States.

The President shall rescind all regulations in effect on the date of the enactment of this bill that regulate or prohibit such travel or transactions.

 Included in such transactions are: (1) accompanied personal baggage; (2) payment of living expenses and the acquisition of personal-use goods or services; (3) travel arrangements; (4) nonscheduled air, sea, or land voyage transactions; and (5) normal banking transactions.

Such provision shall not apply in time of war or armed hostilities between the United States and Cuba or when there is imminent danger to the public health or the physical safety of U.S. citizens or legal residents.

The bill amends: (1) the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992 to repeal the requirement for onsite verification of certain medical exports to Cuba, and (2) the Internal Revenue Code to increase the airport ticket tax for transportation between the United States and Cuba by $1 and to establish the Agricultural Export Promotion Trust Fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
