<bill session="115" type="s" number="1610" updated="2017-09-11T03:02:07Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Walter Scott Notification Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Walter Scott Notification Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require law enforcement agencies to report the use of lethal force, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Walter Scott Notification Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2017-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Walter Scott Notification Act of 2017

This bill requires a state that receives funding under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant (JAG) program to report certain data on deadly shootings by law enforcement officers. It reduces by 10% the JAG allocation of a state that fails to comply.

Additionally, the bill amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to modify requirements under the Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS) program. During the four-year period following enactment, the Department of Justice (DOJ) may give preference to a COPS program grant applicant from a state that reports data on deadly shootings by law enforcement. Beginning in the fifth year, DOJ must reduce by 20% the COPS allocation of a state that fails to report such data.

DOJ, in coordination with the Federal Bureau of Investigation, must issue guidance to standardize data collection on deadly shootings by law enforcement. DOJ must also audit and review data reports, determine compliance with requirements, and publish such data.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
