<bill session="115" type="s" number="500" updated="2017-08-10T13:24:04Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing our Agriculture and Food Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing our Agriculture and Food Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Securing our Agriculture and Food Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Securing our Agriculture and Food Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to make the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security for Health Affairs responsible for coordinating the efforts of the Department of Homeland Security related to food, agriculture, and veterinary defense against terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Securing our Agriculture and Food Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000307"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2017-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2017-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-04-24">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson without amendment. With written report No. 115-29.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-04-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="38">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 38.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1238"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="General agriculture matters"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-24T13:02:55Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Securing our Agriculture and Food Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Assistant Secretary for Health Affairs for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to carry out a program to coordinate DHS efforts relating to defending the food, agriculture, and veterinary systems of the United States against terrorism and other high-consequence events that pose a high risk to homeland security.

Such program shall:

 provide oversight and management of DHS's responsibilities under Homeland Security Presidential Directive 9 - Defense of United States Agriculture and Food; provide oversight and integration of DHS activities relating to veterinary public health, food defense, and agricultural security; lead DHS policy initiatives relating to food, animal, and agricultural incidents and to overall domestic preparedness for, and collective response to, agricultural terrorism; coordinate with other DHS components on activities relating to food and agriculture security and screening procedures for domestic and imported products; and coordinate with appropriate federal departments and agencies.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-29</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
