<bill session="115" type="h" number="3471" updated="2017-09-12T07:16:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Job Creation and Investment Into Public Works Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Job Creation and Investment Into Public Works Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to implement new reforms, and to reauthorize the EB-5 Regional Center Program, in order to promote and reform foreign capital investment and job creation in communities in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Job Creation and Investment Into Public Works Reform Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001154" joined="2017-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">American Job Creation and Investment Into Public Works Reform Act of 2017

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to revise EB-5 (alien immigrant investor) provisions, including regional center program provisions.

The bill prescribes E-B5 requirements regarding: (1) fund sources; (2) threats to the national interest; and (3) fraud, misrepresentation, and criminal misuse.

Future program participation is barred for a person who knowingly participated in conduct that caused a program center's termination.

The EB-5 regional center program is extended through September 30, 2022.

EB-5 investors must be at least 18 years old.

The bill: (1) provides initial conditional permanent resident status for an alien investor (and the investor's spouse and children), and (2) sets aside 2,000 EB-5 visas for immigrants who invest in rural areas, 2,000 for immigrants who invest in priority urban investment areas, and 2,000 for immigrants who invest in infrastructure projects.

A regional center shall operate within a defined geographic area and shall be consistent with the purpose of concentrating pooled investment within such area.

The bill prescribes job creation requirements.

Approved regional centers must give advance notice to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) of significant proposed changes to their organizational structure, ownership, or administration.

U.S. nationals are included in the minimum of 10 U.S. persons for whom an EB-5 project must provide employment.

Only a U.S. national or lawfully admitted permanent resident may be involved with a regional center.

A regional center shall monitor and supervise all offers, purchases, and sales of securities made by associated parties to ensure compliance with U.S. securities laws.

The bill establishes the EB-5 Integrity Fund.

The bill prescribes fund source and gift restrictions.

Minimum investment amounts are increased.

The bill authorizes concurrent filing of EB-5 petitions and applications for adjustment to conditional lawful permanent resident status.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
