<bill session="115" type="s" number="432" updated="2017-08-10T13:24:04Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cerros del Norte Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cerros del Norte Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Cerros del Norte Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Cerros del Norte Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate the Cerro del Yuta and Rio San Antonio Wilderness Areas in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cerros del Norte Conservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2017-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-03">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 115-40.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="54">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 54.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-03T14:42:19Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Cerros del Norte Conservation Act

 (Sec. 3) This bill designates the Cerro del Yuta Wilderness (comprising approximately 13,420 acres) and Rio San Antonio Wilderness (comprising approximately 8,120 acres) within the Rio Grande del Norte National Monument in New Mexico as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

 The bill sets forth requirements for the management of the wilderness areas regarding: (1) livestock grazing, (2) the creation of protective perimeters and buffer zones, and (3) the jurisdiction of the state of New Mexico respecting fish and wildlife located on public land in New Mexico.

 The bill releases specified public land within the San Antonio Wilderness Study Area not designated as wilderness by this bill from further study for such a designation.

 The bill requires the wilderness areas to be administered as components of the National Landscape Conservation System.

 The bill withdraws any federal land within the wilderness areas, including any acquired land or interest, from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.

 The bill declares that nothing in this bill enlarges, diminishes, or otherwise modifies any treaty rights.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-40</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
