<bill session="115" type="h" number="736" updated="2017-09-11T03:02:52Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Black Box Privacy Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Black Box Privacy Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require automobile manufacturers to disclose to consumers the presence of event data recorders, or "black boxes", on new automobiles, and to require manufacturers to provide the consumer with the option to enable and disable such devices on future automobiles.</title>
    <title type="display">Black Box Privacy Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001037"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Digital Commerce and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3568"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-30T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Black Box Privacy Protection Act

This bill amends the Automobile Information Disclosure Act to require manufacturers of new automobiles to disclose on the information label affixed to the window of the automobile: (1) the presence and location of an event data recorder (commonly referred to as a "black box"), (2) the type of information recorded and how such information is recorded, and (3) that the recording may be used in a law enforcement proceeding.

The bill sets forth similar requirements for motorcycle manufacturers.

An "event data recorder" is any device or means of technology installed in an automobile that records information such as automobile or motorcycle speed, seatbelt use, application of brakes, or other information pertinent to the operation of the automobile or motorcycle.

The bill prohibits the manufacture, sale, offering for sale, or import into the United States of an automobile manufactured after 2015 (bearing a model year of 2016 or later) that is equipped with an event data recorder, unless the consumer can control the recording of information. Violators are liable to the U.S. government for a civil penalty of up to $5,000 for each violation with a maximum penalty of $35 million for a related series of violations.

The event data recorder in an automobile or motorcycle, and any data recorded, shall be considered the property of the owner of the automobile or motorcycle. Retrieval or downloading of recorded data by any other person is unlawful, except: (1) with the owner's consent, (2) in response to a court order, or (3) by a dealer or automotive technician to service the vehicle.

Certain violations are to be treated as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
