<bill session="115" type="h" number="2799" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:22Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Western Water Recycling and Drought Relief Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Western Water Recycling and Drought Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize certain recycled water projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Western Water Recycling and Drought Relief Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001166"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2017-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Power and Oceans" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Western Water Recycling and Drought Relief Act

This bill amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Department of the Interior to participate in the design, planning, and construction of recycled water system facilities in California in cooperation with:

 the cities of Benicia, Brentwood, Redwood City, Pleasanton, Hayward, Mountain View, Palo Alto, Sunnyvale, and Turlock; the Dublin San Ramon Services District and the Dublin San Ramon Services District/East Bay Municipal Utility District Recycled Water Authority; the Santa Clara Valley Water District; the Central Contra Costa Sanitary District; the Delta Diablo; the Ironhouse Sanitary District; the Monterey Regional Water Pollution Control Agency; the San Jose Water Company; and the West Bay Sanitary District. The bill also authorizes Interior to participate in the design, planning, and construction of recycled water system facilities in Hawaii in cooperation with Hawaii Water Service Company, Waikoloa.

The federal share of each project is limited to 25%.

Interior must: (1) enter into individual agreements with the Western Recycled Water Coalition participating agencies to fund such projects (as well as existing projects done in cooperation with the California cities of Palo Alto, Mountain View, Pittsburg, Antioch, Redwood City, and San Jose and the Delta Diablo Sanitation District, the North Coast County Water District, the South County Regional Wastewater Authority, and the Santa Clara Valley Water District); and (2) include in such agreements a provision for the reimbursement of design, planning, and construction costs.

The bill increases the authorization of appropriations for the recycled water system facilities of: (1) Antioch and the Delta Diablo Sanitation District, and (2) the South County Regional Wastewater Authority and the Santa Clara Valley Water District.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
