<bill session="115" type="h" number="1226" updated="2017-06-19T21:15:27Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Uncompensated Survivors Today (JUST) Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Uncompensated Survivors Today (JUST) Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require reporting on acts of certain foreign countries on Holocaust era assets and related issues, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Justice for Uncompensated Survivors Today (JUST) Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2017-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000480" joined="2017-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2017-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="447"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Justice for Uncompensated Survivors Today (JUST) Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of State, with respect to covered countries, to annually include within either the relevant Annual Country Report on Human Rights Practices, the International Religious Freedom Report, or other appropriate report an assessment of the nature and extent of national laws or enforceable policies regarding the identification, return, or restitution of wrongfully seized or transferred Holocaust era assets and compliance with the goals of the Terezin Declaration on Holocaust Era Assets and Related Issues, including:

 the return to the rightful owner of wrongfully seized or transferred property, including religious or communal property, or the provision of comparable substitute property or the payment of equitable compensation to the rightful owner; the use of the Washington Conference Principles on Nazi-Confiscated Art and the Terezin Declaration in settling claims involving publicly and privately held movable property; the restitution of heirless property to assist needy Holocaust survivors; and progress on the resolution of claims for U.S. citizen Holocaust survivors and family members. "Covered countries" means signatories to the Terezin Declaration that are determined by the Special Envoy for Holocaust Issues to be countries of particular concern with respect to such restitution.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
