<bill session="115" type="h" number="3217" updated="2017-09-11T02:54:37Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Outsourcing and Create American Jobs Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Outsourcing and Create American Jobs Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the identification of corporate tax haven countries and increased penalties for tax evasion practices in haven countries that ship United States jobs overseas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Outsourcing and Create American Jobs Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001166"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5770-5771"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Outsourcing and Create American Jobs Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to develop and publish a list of countries that are tax havens for corporations.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the penalties on corporations for: (1) underpayment of tax involving an undisclosed foreign financial asset located in a tax haven country; (2) reportable transaction understatements involving transactions in a tax haven country; and (3) fraud, tax evasion, or false statements involving transactions in a tax haven country.

The bill also: (1) permits federal departments and agencies to grant a preference in the award of federal contracts to contractors who have not engaged in outsourcing, (2) requires federal departments and agencies to request outsourcing information from potential contractors, and (3) defines "outsourcing" as the laying off of a U.S. worker from a job and the hiring or contracting for the same job to be performed in a foreign country.

Revenues generated by this bill must be set aside for the reduction of the public debt.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
