<bill session="115" type="h" number="2171" updated="2017-06-19T22:00:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce taxpayer burdens and enhance taxpayer protections, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Taxpayer Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001038" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2017-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Taxpayer Protection Act of 2017

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish additional requirements and procedures for collecting taxes, regulating tax preparers, responding to identity theft, and assisting low-income taxpayers.

The bill repeals the authority of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to contract with private companies to collect federal tax debts. It also excludes from the gross income of an individual up to $10,000 of income from the discharge of a debt over the individual's lifetime.

The bill requires the statute of limitations for a taxpayer's case to continue to run during a pending application for assistance from the National Taxpayer Advocate.

The bill also:

 establishes limitations on IRS levies of retirement accounts, suspends the time limit for returning wrongfully levied property if a taxpayer is financially disabled, increases the grace period for withdrawing a frivolous return, and repeals the requirement to submit a partial payment with an offer-in-compromise to settle a tax liability. The IRS must: (1) notify taxpayers regarding suspected identity theft and related criminal charges, (2) establish a single point of contact for identity theft victims, (3) permit its employees to refer taxpayers to low-income taxpayer clinics, and (4) notify taxpayers who are eligible for the Earned Income Tax Credit.

The IRS may regulate paid tax return preparers and disclose returns or return information necessary to publish decisions related to tax return preparer misconduct.

The bill provides additional funding to the IRS for Taxpayer Services and increases the funding that the IRS may allocate to low-income taxpayer clinics.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
