<bill session="115" type="s" number="513" updated="2017-08-10T13:24:05Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area Designation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special ManagementArea Designation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area Designation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area Designation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate the Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area in the State of Oregon.</title>
    <title type="display">Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area Designation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2017-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1581" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1581-1582" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 115-66.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="84">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 84.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1308"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-16T12:31:37Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area Designation Act

 (Sec. 4) This bill designates approximately 99,653 acres of Forest Service land in Oregon as the "Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area."

The special management area shall be administered by the Forest Service to:

 conserve and enhance the natural character, scientific use, and the botanical, recreational, ecological, fish and wildlife, scenic, drinking water, and cultural values of the special management area; maintain and seek to enhance the wild salmonid habitat of the special management area; maintain or enhance the watershed as a thermal refuge for wild salmonids; and preserve opportunities for recreation, including primitive recreation. The bill withdraws the federal land within the boundaries of the special management area's river segments from:

 entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-66</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
