<bill session="115" type="h" number="2870" updated="2017-09-26T07:16:54Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gigabit Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gigabit Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax benefits for investments in gigabit opportunity zones.</title>
    <title type="display">Gigabit Opportunity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2017-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2017-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001071" joined="2017-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000297" joined="2017-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001194" joined="2017-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001195" joined="2017-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001195" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000475" joined="2017-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2017-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="1013"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Gigabit Opportunity Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to authorize the designation of qualified gigabit opportunity zones in low-income communities and to provide tax incentives for investments in the zones.

Governors may submit nominations for a limited number of qualified gigabit opportunity zones in low-income communities to the Department of the Treasury for certification and designation. Governors must give particular consideration to areas that:

 are facing obstacles to economic development due to a lack of geographic broadband coverage or speed; are the focus of mutually reinforcing state, local, or private economic development initiatives; are poised for economic growth that requires access to high speed broadband for commercial purposes; and represent the areas of a state where such service would result in the highest return on investment. For eligible taxpayers that sell certain broadband services, the bill allows: (1) deferrals, reductions, or exemptions from taxes on capital gains invested in certain property used to provide broadband services in a zone (depending on how long the property is held), and (2) immediate expensing of the costs of the property.

The bill also allows tax-exempt private activity bonds to be used for certain broadband projects in the zones.

Within one year of enactment of this bill, the Federal Communications Commission must publish a Uniform Model Broadband Deployment Act containing laws for the state regulation of the deployment of broadband services. Qualified zones must adopt either the Act or laws comparable to the Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
