<bill session="115" type="s" number="507" updated="2017-06-30T04:56:22Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blackfoot Clearwater Stewardship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blackfoot Clearwater Stewardship Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to sustain economic development and recreational use of National Forest System land in the State of Montana, to add certain land to the National Wilderness Preservation System, to designate new areas for recreation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Blackfoot Clearwater Stewardship Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Blackfoot Clearwater Stewardship Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to complete a landscape assessment of the Seeley Lake Ranger District of the Lolo National Forest in Montana to: (1) assess the ecological condition of its forests and watersheds; and (2) identify actions needed to facilitate ecosystem sustainability, resilience, and health by assisting in the recovery of its forest ecosystems.

A collaboratively developed restoration project within the district may be carried out according to certain provisions &#160;applicable to authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects under the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003.

The bill designates specified federal land in the forest as: (1) the Otatsy Recreation Management Area, and (2) the Spread Mountain Recreation Area.

USDA shall, if, a local collaborative group submits a proposal to improve motorized and nonmotorized recreational trail opportunities within the district, analyze the proposal in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. It&#160;may also&#160;provide for the construction of any of the routes included in such proposal.

The bill designates specified wilderness additions in the forest as wilderness areas and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
