<bill session="115" type="h" number="2395" updated="2017-06-19T22:15:23Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Predatory Bail Contracts Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Predatory Bail Contracts Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Federal Trade Commission to issue regulations to prohibit any bail bond agent or person who underwrites or insures the provision of a bail bond who require a bonded individual to wear an ankle monitor or other homing device as a condition on issuing such a bond from charging any fee associated with such monitor or device that exceeds the cost to the bail bond agent or person who underwrites or insures the provision of a bail bond of maintaining and operating such monitor or device.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Predatory Bail Contracts Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000474"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2017-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Digital Commerce and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Predatory Bail Contracts Act

This bill requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to limit the fee that bail bond agents or persons underwriting or insuring the provision of a bail bond may charge for an ankle monitor or homing device that they require an accused individual to wear as a condition on issuing a bond for his or her appearance in court. The fee may not exceed the cost of maintaining and operating such monitor or device.

The bill provides the FTC with authority to enforce against violations, which shall be treated as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under Federal Trade Commission Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
