<bill session="115" type="h" number="659" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clayton Act and the Federal Trade Commission Act to provide that the Federal Trade Commission shall exercise authority with respect to mergers only under the Clayton Act and only in the same procedural manner as the Attorney General exercises such authority.</title>
    <title type="display">Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000289" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2017-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-04-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 16 - 10.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Standard Merger and Acquisition Reviews Through Equal Rules Act of 2017

This bill amends the Clayton Act with respect to notice to a state by the Department of Justice (DOJ) about federal actions brought for violations of antitrust laws.

The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) shall exercise the same authority and procedures as DOJ under the Clayton Act if the FTC has brought an action under Section 7 of the same Act with respect to the prohibition against acquisition by one corporation of the stock of another (merger) that may substantially lessen competition or tend to create a monopoly.

The Federal Trade Commission Act (FTCA) is amended to exclude proposed mergers, acquisitions, joint ventures, or similar transactions from ordinary FTC proceedings, except in cases where the FTC approves an agreement with the parties to the transaction that contains a consent order.

U.S. district courts shall have jurisdiction to issue writs of mandamus commanding compliance with the FTCA or any FTC order, if the FTC applies to such courts with respect to any activity related to consummation of a merger, acquisition, joint venture, or similar transaction that may result in an unfair method of competition.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
