<bill session="115" type="h" number="2574" updated="2017-06-22T14:23:29Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building a Health Care Workforce for the Future Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building a Health Care Workforce for the Future Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to help build a stronger health care workforce.</title>
    <title type="display">Building a Health Care Workforce for the Future Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000599"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Building a Health Care Workforce for the Future Act

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award matching grants to enable states to implement scholarship programs to ensure an adequate supply of health professionals. Scholarships must cover tuition and educational expenses and provide a cost-of-living stipend. Scholarship recipients must agree to serve as providers in shortage areas in the state for one year for each year they receive the scholarship.

HHS may award grants to assist medical schools in developing and strengthening primary care mentorship programs and cultivating leaders in primary care among its students.

In order to foster curricular innovations to improve the education and training of health care providers, HHS must award grants to medical and other health professions schools to promote priority competencies that are selected annually by the Advisory Committee on Training in Primary Care Medicine and Dentistry.

The National Academy of Medicine (formerly known as the Institute of Medicine) must study the documentation requirements for cognitive services under Medicare, Medicaid, and private health insurers, including whether the requirements are overly burdensome.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
