<bill session="115" type="h" number="940" updated="2017-08-17T20:15:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCOUTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCOUTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Communications of Utilities from Terrorist Threats</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Communications of Utilities from Terrorist Threats</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To secure communications of utilities from terrorist threats, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SCOUTS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Counterterrorism and Intelligence" code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies" code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing Communications of Utilities from Terrorist Threats or the SCOUTS Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to work with critical infrastructure owners and operators and state, local, tribal, and territorial entities to seek voluntary participation of sector-specific agencies to determine how DHS can best serve cybersecurity needs to manage risk and strengthen the security and resilience of the nation's critical infrastructure against terrorist attacks. A "sector-specific agency" is a federal agency designated as such by Presidential Policy Directive 21 relating to critical infrastructure security and resilience.

DHS: (1) shall seek to reduce vulnerabilities, minimize consequences, identify and disrupt terrorism threats, and hasten response and recovery efforts related to impacted critical infrastructures; (2) may investigate the best means for engaging sector-specific agencies in a voluntary cybersecurity information sharing, emergency support, and emerging threat awareness program; and (3) shall establish voluntary opportunities for such agencies and critical infrastructure owners and operators to inform DHS of sector-specific challenges to cybersecurity.

DHS shall: (1) establish terrorism prevention policy to engage with international partners to strengthen the security and resilience of domestic critical infrastructure and critical infrastructure located outside of the United States or in its territorial waters, and (2) facilitate the timely exchange of terrorism threat and vulnerability information as well as information that allows for the development of a situational awareness capability for federal civilian agencies during terrorist incidents.

DHS shall implement an integration and analysis function for critical infrastructure that includes: (1) operational and strategic analysis on terrorism incidents, threats, and emerging risks; and (2) integration of data sharing capabilities with Fusion Centers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
