<bill session="115" type="h" number="2538" updated="2017-06-24T07:13:00Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intern Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intern Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide certain workplace protections to interns relating to discriminatory practices.</title>
    <title type="display">Intern Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001188"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, Oversight and Government Reform, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Intern Protection Act

This bill prohibits certain employers from refusing to employ, discriminating against, or harassing interns because of age, race, religion, color, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, military status, disability, gender identity, predisposing genetic characteristics, marital status, or status as a victim of domestic violence.

The bill bars employers from compelling a pregnant intern to take a leave of absence, unless the intern is prevented by such pregnancy from performing internship activities in a reasonable manner.

The bill prohibits employers from engaging in certain unwelcome sexual advances or other verbal or physical conduct of a sexual nature to an intern when: (1) submission is a condition for continuing the internship or a basis for employment decisions; or (2) the conduct unreasonably interferes with work performance by creating an intimidating, hostile, or offensive working environment.

The age discrimination prohibitions of this bill apply only to individuals who are at least 40 years of age.

The bill authorizes the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Library of Congress, the Board of Directors of Congress's Office of Compliance, the Department of Justice, the President, the Merit Systems Protection Board, and U.S. courts to enforce this bill under specified provisions of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991, the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, and other laws granting rights and protections to certain applicants and employees.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
