<bill session="115" type="s" number="1286" updated="2017-10-07T04:28:50Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom to Export to Cuba Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom to Export to Cuba Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to lift the trade embargo on Cuba.</title>
    <title type="display">Freedom to Export to Cuba Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2017-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2017-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Freedom to Export to Cuba Act of 2017

This bill amends: (1) the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to repeal the prohibition on assistance to Cuba and the President's authority for the embargo on Cuba, (2) the Trading with the Enemy Act to repeal the President's authority to continue direct restrictions on trade with Cuba, and (3) the Export Administration Act of 1979 to repeal the prohibitions on exports to Cuba.

 The bill authorizes the President to: (1) impose export controls with respect to Cuba, and (2) exercise certain authorities under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act only on account of an unusual and extraordinary threat to U.S. national security.

The Cuban Democracy Act of 1992 is amended to eliminate:

 presidential authority to impose sanctions against Cuban trading partners, restrictions on transactions between U.S.-owned or controlled firms and Cuba, limitations on direct shipping between Cuban and U.S. ports, and restrictions on remittances. The Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1996 is amended to eliminate provisions concerning:

 the enforcement of an economic embargo of Cuba; the prohibition on indirect financing of Cuba; opposition to Cuban membership in international financial institutions; opposition to ending Cuban suspension from the Organization of American States; certain import restrictions, including sugar restrictions; family remittance and travel to Cuba, news bureaus in Cuba, and extradition of persons sought by the Department of Justice for crimes committed in the United States; and assistance to a free and independent Cuba. The Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 is amended to:

 remove Cuba from the list of state sponsors of terrorism subject to agricultural and medical export restrictions; and repeal the prohibition on the U.S. entry of merchandise that is of Cuban origin, that is or has been located in or transported from or through Cuba, or that is made or derived in whole or in part of any article which is the growth, produce, or manufacture of Cuba.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
