<bill session="115" type="h" number="472" updated="2017-10-03T07:15:48Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Recovery and Community Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Recovery and Community Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Housing Act to better protect persons with disabilities and communities.</title>
    <title type="display">Safe Recovery and Community Empowerment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2017-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2017-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001048" joined="2017-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2017-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2017-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2017-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000820" joined="2017-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe Recovery and Community Empowerment Act

This bill amends the Fair Housing Act to provide that nothing in federal law relating to protections for persons with disabilities prohibits a local, state, or federal government body from:

 requiring a reasonable minimum distance between residential recovery facilities within a particular area zoned for residential housing if such requirement is necessary to preserve the residential character of the area and allows for some of such facilities to be located within such area; and requiring that such a facility obtain an operating license or use permit or satisfy a set of consumer protection standards, which may include a maximum capacity requirement. A residential recovery facility is a residence that provides housing to individuals in recovery from drug or alcohol addiction with the promise of providing a clean and sober environment in return for direct or indirect payment to an owner, operator, or compensated staff person.

Facilities receiving payments from a federal health care program, or via private insurance purchased on a federal exchange or federally subsidized, for either housing, recovery services, or testing or monitoring for drugs or alcohol shall ensure that residents: (1) are provided a safe living environment completely free from illicit drugs, alcohol, firearms, harassment, abuse, or harm; and (2) live in a licensed or registered residence that has committed to following standards approved by states and localities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
