<bill session="115" type="s" number="328" updated="2017-06-19T21:00:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Justice Under Law Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Justice Under Law Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enforce the Sixth Amendment right to the assistance of effective counsel at all stages of the adversarial process, to confer jurisdiction upon the district courts of the United States to provide declaratory and injunctive relief against systemic violations of such right, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Equal Justice Under Law Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="968"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Equal Justice Under Law Act of 2017

This bill states that an indigent individual facing criminal prosecution or juvenile delinquency in a state court is entitled to the effective assistance of counsel, as guaranteed by the Sixth and Fourteenth Amendments, at the state's expense.

It authorizes a federal class action lawsuit against a state for its systemic failure to guarantee the right to effective assistance of counsel. The assistance of counsel is ineffective when a class of individuals demonstrates that counsel's performance was not reasonable under prevailing professional norms.

Additionally, the bill amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to modify the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant (JAG) program. Specifically, it requires a state or local government to consult with public defenders before distributing JAG funds to community organizations and local governments.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
