<bill session="115" type="h" number="55" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:32Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Breath of Fresh Air Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Breath of Fresh Air Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program for nebulizers in elementary and secondary schools.</title>
    <title type="display">Breath of Fresh Air Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Breath of Fresh Air Act

This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a grant program for local educational agencies (LEAs) to purchase, and train school personnel to use,&#160;nebulizers.

Each grant recipient&#160;must&#160;demonstrate that, with respect to each of its schools that is to use the nebulizers: (1) a full-time certified nurse is on staff, (2) trained personnel and other resources necessary for nebulizer use are in place, (3) emergency services personnel are notified of nebulizer locations, (4) nebulizers are integrated into the school's emergency response procedures, and (5) procedures are in place to notify parents of the availability of nebulizers and to inform them how to provide the school with their child's prescription asthma medication and authorization to use a nebulizer to assist their child.

The bill gives grant priority to LEAs that: (1) serve areas where the prevalence of asthma is at least 10% higher than the national average; (2) do not already have at least one nebulizer in each of their schools; (3) serve schools that typically have a significant number of students, staff, and visitors present during the day; and (4) have not received funds under the Rural Access to Emergency Devices Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
