<bill session="115" type="s" number="225" updated="2017-08-10T13:24:01Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mount Hood Cooper Spur Land Exchange Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mount Hood Cooper Spur Land Exchange Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Mount Hood Cooper Spur Land Exchange Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Mount Hood Cooper Spur Land Exchange Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to modify provisions relating to certain land exchanges in the Mt. Hood Wilderness in the State of Oregon.</title>
    <title type="display">Mount Hood Cooper Spur Land Exchange Clarification Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2017-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 115-52.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="65">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 65.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="699"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-09T13:49:16Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Mount Hood Cooper Spur Land Exchange Clarification Act

 (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to revise details of the Cooper Spur-Government Camp land exchange between the United States and Oregon.

After the final appraised value of the federal and nonfederal lands is determined and approved by Department of Agriculture (USDA), the USDA shall not be required to reappraise or update that value for a period of up to three years, unless the condition of any of the lands is significantly and substantially altered by fire, windstorm, or other events.

The bill revises conveyance conditions regarding reservation of a conservation easement to protect identified wetland, reservation of a nonexclusive trail easement, and equalization of values of the exchange properties.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-52</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
