<bill session="115" type="s" number="1061" updated="2017-10-11T17:15:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assuring Contracting Equity Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assuring Contracting Equity Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to assure equity in contracting between the Federal Government and small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Assuring Contracting Equity Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2017-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2362"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Assuring Contracting Equity Act of 2017

This bill increases from: (1) 23% to 25% the government-wide small business procurement contract goal, (2) 5% to 10% the government-wide procurement goal for small disadvantaged businesses and women-owned businesses, and (3) 3% to 6% the government-wide procurement goal for service-disabled veteran-owned small businesses and HUBZone (Historically Underutilized Business Zone) small businesses. The number of categories is limited for which a small business may qualify under such goals.

The Small Business Administration (SBA) must include in its annual report to the President and Congress on these goals the percentage of participation by small businesses for the total value of all prime contracts and subcontracts awards for a fiscal year, including the value of each contract awarded.

The SBA must consult with the heads of other federal agencies to develop and implement standards for procurement officers to take into consideration the past compliance of potential contractors with small business subcontracting goals when making contract awards.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
