<bill session="115" type="h" number="423" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:17Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-23T18:52:17-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-01-23T18:52:17-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Anti-Spoofing Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Anti-Spoofing Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Spoofing Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Spoofing Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to expand and clarify the prohibition on provision of misleading or inaccurate caller identification information, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Anti-Spoofing Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000213" joined="2017-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2017-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000567" joined="2017-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2017-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T16:16:06-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Blackburn moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T16:16:18-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H576-579" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T16:16:21-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 423.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T16:30:30-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T18:31:10-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H591" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="60" datetime="2017-01-23T18:52:17-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 398 - 5 (Roll no. 60).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H576-577" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T18:52:18-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="134"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-23T14:19:02Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Anti-Spoofing Act of 2017

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to expand the prohibition against knowingly transmitting misleading or inaccurate caller identification information to apply to: (1) persons outside the United States if the recipient is within the United States, and (2) text messages.

Existing caller identification requirements that apply to calls made using a telecommunications service or IP-enabled voice service are revised to apply to: (1) services interconnected with the public switched telephone network and that furnish voice communications using resources from the North American Numbering Plan; and (2) transmissions from a telephone facsimile machine, computer, or other device to a telephone facsimile machine.

The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) must coordinate with the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to regularly update education materials that help consumers identify: (1) scams and fraudulent activity that rely upon misleading or inaccurate caller identification information, and (2) existing technologies that consumers can use to protect against such fraud.

The Government Accountability Office must report on: (1) actions taken, or actions that could be taken, by the FCC or the FTC to combat the fraudulent provision of misleading or inaccurate caller identification information; and (2) any recommendations to combat the fraudulent provision of such information.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
