<bill session="115" type="s" number="1239" updated="2017-06-27T04:32:58Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Length of Service Award Program Cap Adjustment Priority Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Length of Service Award Program Cap Adjustment Priority Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LOSAP CAP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LOSAP CAP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the rules applicable to length of service award plans.</title>
    <title type="display">LOSAP CAP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2017-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3216-3217" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Length of Service Award Program Cap Adjustment Priority Act or the LOSAP CAP Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to deferred compensation plans, to increase the limit on accruals that is required for length of service award plans (LOSAPs) for bona fide volunteers to be exempt from treatment as a deferred compensation plan.

(Under current law, plans paying solely length of service awards to bona fide volunteers or their beneficiaries on the account of firefighting and prevention services, emergency medical services, and ambulance services performed by the volunteers are not treated as deferred compensation plans if they meet certain requirements. One of the requirements is a limit on the aggregate amount of length of service awards that may accrue with respect to any year of service for any bona fide volunteer.)

The bill modifies the limit on accruals to: (1) increase the limit from $3,000 to $6,000; (2) provide for a cost-of-living adjustment to the limit after 2017; and (3) specify that, in the case of LOSAPs that are defined benefit plans, the limit applies to the actuarial present value of the aggregate amount of length of service awards accruing with respect to any year of service.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
