<bill session="115" type="h" number="1597" updated="2017-09-11T03:02:56Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commercial Market Representatives Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">The Commercial Market Representatives Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to clarify the responsibilities of commercial market representatives, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Commercial Market Representatives Clarification Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001290"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2017-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2017-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2810"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1773"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Commercial Market Representatives Clarification Act

This bill amends the Small Business Act to specify the principal duties of Commercial Market Representatives, government contracting staff stationed at area Small Business Administration (SBA) offices and reporting to specified senior SBA officers.

 Such duties shall include:

 helping prime federal government contractors to find small business concerns capable of performing subcontracts; counseling such contractors on their responsibility to maximize subcontracting opportunities for small business concerns; instructing such contractors on methods and tools to identify potential subcontractors that are small business concerns; assisting such constractors to increase awards to small business subcontractors through visits, training, and reviews of past performance; giving counseling on how a small business concern may promote its capacity to such contractors; and conducting periodic reviews of such contractors to assess compliance with required subcontracting plans regarding small business subcontractors.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
