<bill session="115" type="h" number="2202" updated="2017-07-18T18:45:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chiropractic Membership in the Public Health Service Commissioned Corps Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chiropractic Membership in the Public Health Service Commissioned Corps Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize appointment of Doctors of Chiropractic to regular and reserve corps of the Public Health Service Commissioned Corps, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Chiropractic Membership in the Public Health Service Commissioned Corps Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000410"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Chiropractic Membership in the Public Health Service Commissioned Corps Act of 2017

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to make certain doctors of chiropractic (chiropractors) eligible for appointment to the United States Public Health Service Commissioned Corps. To be appointed, a chiropractor must be eligible for licensure in a majority of the states or approved by a body acceptable to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). HHS and the Surgeon General must ensure that such chiropractors are trained, equipped, and otherwise prepared to fulfill public health and emergency response service responsibilities in the Commissioned Corps.

The President must appoint at least six chiropractors to the commissioned Regular Corps and the Ready Reserve Corps.

The Surgeon General must report to Congress on measures taken by the President, Surgeon General, and HHS to carry out this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
