<bill session="115" type="h" number="590" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-23T15:56:48-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-01-23T15:56:48-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Advanced Nuclear Technology Development Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Advanced Nuclear Technology Development Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advanced Nuclear Technology Development Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advanced Nuclear Technology Development Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To foster civilian research and development of advanced nuclear energy technologies and enhance the licensing and commercial deployment of such technologies.</title>
    <title type="display">Advanced Nuclear Technology Development Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000482" joined="2017-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2017-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2017-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2017-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2017-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-20">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-20">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T15:49:38-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Upton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T15:49:50-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H569-571" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T15:49:52-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 590.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-01-23T15:56:48-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H569-570" label="text of measure as passed"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T15:56:53-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-23T14:18:02Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Advanced Nuclear Technology Development Act of 2017

(Sec.4)This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to enter into a memorandum of understanding to:

 ensure that DOE has sufficient technical expertise to support the civilian nuclear industry's timely development and commercial deployment of safe, innovative advanced reactor technology; ensure that the NRC has sufficient technical expertise to support the evaluation of requests for regulatory approval for advanced reactors; use computers and software codes to calculate the behavior and performance of advanced reactors based on mathematical models of their physical behavior; and ensure that the DOE maintains and develops the facilities to support the civilian nuclear industry's timely development and commercial deployment of safe, innovative reactor technology and ensuring that the NRC has access to such facilities, as needed. (Sec.5)In addition, the NRC is required to develop a regulatory framework for licensing advanced nuclear reactors. The plan must include options to expedite and streamline the licensing process for advanced reactors, cost estimates, budgets, and specific milestones for implementing the framework by the end of FY2019.

(Sec.6) This bill amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 to require that the aggregate amount of fees collected by the NRC from licensees and certificate holders in a fiscal year be decreased by the amount of appropriations for activities related to the development of regulatory infrastructure for advanced nuclear reactor technologies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
