<bill session="115" type="s" number="502" updated="2017-08-10T13:24:05Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the boundary of Voyageurs National Park in the State of Minnesota, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to modify the boundary of Voyageurs National Park in the State of Minnesota, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000457"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 115-64.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="82">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 82.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1350"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-16T12:30:10Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

(Sec. 1) This bill modifies the boundaries of Voyageurs National Park in Minnesota.

 The bill transfers to the National Park Service of the Department of the Interior administrative jurisdiction over:

 any land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) within the boundaries of the park, and any additional public land identified by the BLM as appropriate for transfer within the boundaries of the park. Any land located within or adjacent to the boundaries of the park that is owned by Minnesota (or a political subdivision) may be acquired by Interior through donation or exchange only.

Upon completion of any such acquisition from Minnesota, Interior shall revise the park's boundaries to reflect the acquisition.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-64</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
