<bill session="115" type="s" number="1364" updated="2017-10-06T04:49:30Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Museum of the American Latino Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Museum of the American Latino Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish within the Smithsonian Institution the National Museum of the American Latino, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Museum of the American Latino Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2911"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Museum of the American Latino Act

This bill establishes the National Museum of the American Latino in the Smithsonian Institution.

The purposes of the museum are to: (1) illuminate Latino contributions to the story of the United States; (2) provide for the collection, study, research, publication, and establishment of exhibitions and programs related to Latino life, art, history, and culture; and (3) provide for collaboration with Smithsonian Institution museums and research centers and other museums and educational institutions in the United States and abroad to promote the study and appreciation of Latino life, art, history, culture, and its impact on society in the United States.

The bill establishes a Board of Trustees for the museum to advise and assist the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian on all matters related to the administration and preservation of the museum.

The Director of the museum shall manage the museum and may carry out educational and liaison programs in support of its goals.

The Board of Regents shall designate a site for the museum and is authorized to design and construct it.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
