<bill session="115" type="s" number="798" updated="2017-09-11T03:06:28Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Yellow Ribbon Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Yellow Ribbon Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to expand the Yellow Ribbon G.I. Education Enhancement Program to apply to individuals pursuing programs of education while on active duty, to recipients of the Marine Gunnery Sergeant John David Fry scholarship, and to programs of education pursued on half-time basis or less, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Yellow Ribbon Improvement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2017-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2103"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Yellow Ribbon Improvement Act of 2017

This bill revises the Department of Veterans Affairs' (VA) Yellow Ribbon G.I. Education Enhancement Program (public-private contributions for educational assistance in addition to post-9/11 educational assistance) to make such program available to: (1) the spouse or child of a service member who, on or after after September 11, 2001, dies in the line of duty while serving on active duty (Marine Gunnery Sergeant John David Fry scholarship recipients); and (2) a service member or veteran who serves at least 36 months on active duty beginning on or after such date.

The bill provides educational assistance to individuals pursuing a degree while on active duty on more than, or less than, a half-time basis.

The program permits colleges and universities to voluntarily enter into an agreement with the VA to cover a portion of certain higher education expenses, which shall be matched by the VA.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
