<bill session="115" type="s" number="277" updated="2017-06-19T21:00:29Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Telecommunications and Broadband Service Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Telecommunications and Broadband Service Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Rural Telecommunications and Broadband Advisory Committee within the Federal Communications Commission.</title>
    <title type="display">Rural Telecommunications and Broadband Service Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001183"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Telecommunications and Broadband Service Act of 2017

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to establish within the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) a Rural Telecommunications and Broadband Advisory Committee to:

 provide advice to the FCC, and reports to Congress, on the deployment of advanced and next-generation telecommunications services in rural areas, the advancement of universal service principles for nationwide access to affordable and quality telecommunications and information services, and other policies relating to telecommunications in rural areas; define what constitutes a rural area that has access to telecommunications and information technologies and services in accordance with universal service principles; and advise on the impact of FCC agenda items on the provision of such services in rural areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
