<bill session="115" type="h" number="2078" updated="2017-09-12T19:00:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jump Start America Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jump Start America Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to simplify individual income and corporate tax rates, to set a maximum on the capital gains rate, to make permanent the deduction for dividends received for repatriated foreign earnings, to reduce the rate of payroll and self-employment taxes, to make 100-percent bonus depreciation permanent, and to repeal the Federal estate and gift taxes.</title>
    <title type="display">Jump Start America Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000816"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="30"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="198"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Jump Start America Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to several corporate and individual income tax policies, to:

 revise individual income tax rates to establish a 20% rate on taxable income of $1 million or less and a 30% rate on taxable income over $1 million, with an adjustment for inflation after 2016; revise the income tax rates on corporations to impose a single 20% rate on corporate taxable income; modify the formula for calculating the tax on the net capital gains of individual taxpayers to provide for a maximum 15% rate on the adjusted net capital gain of such taxpayers; reduce the tax rate on current and accumulated foreign earnings of U.S. corporations reinvested in the United States and make the lower rate permanent; increase the additional depreciation allowance (bonus depreciation) from 50% to 100% of the adjusted basis of qualifying business property and to make such increased allowance permanent; reduce Social Security and Medicare payroll taxes for employers, employees, and the self-employed; and repeal the federal estate, gift, and generation-skipping transfer taxes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
