<bill session="115" type="h" number="145" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:31Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Citizen Legislature Anti-Corruption Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Citizen Legislature Anti-Corruption Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLEAN Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To terminate pensions for Members of Congress, to prohibit a single bill or joint resolution presented by Congress to the President from containing multiple subjects, to require the equal application of laws to Members of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">CLEAN Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000466"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1935"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="322"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts and representation"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Citizen Legislature Anti-Corruption Reform Act or the CLEAN Act

 This bill amends the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) and the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS) to exclude Members of Congress, except the Vice President, from further CSRS and FERS retirement coverage.

The bill prohibits further government contributions or deductions from such Member's basic pay for deposit in the Treasury to the credit of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund.

Nothing in this bill shall: (1) be considered to nullify, modify, or otherwise affect any right, entitlement, or benefit under CSRS or FERS for any Member covering any period before enactment of this bill; or (2) affect the eligibility of a Member to participate in the Thrift Savings Plan (TSP) in accordance with otherwise applicable law.

The bill requires that each bill, order, resolution, or vote submitted by Congress to the President be limited to one subject which shall be clearly expressed in the measure's or vote's title.

 Any provision of law that provides an exception in its application to a Member of Congress or an employee of such Member shall have no effect.

Each state must conduct congressional redistricting, beginning with the decennial census conducted during 2020, using a redistricting plan developed by a nonpartisan independent redistricting commission (NIRC). After such redistricting, no state may use federal funds directly for election administration purposes unless it certifies to the Election Assistance Commission (EAC) that it conducts redistricting for its legislative districts using an NIRC redistricting plan.

Each state must hold open primaries for elections for federal office. A state may not use any federal funds provided directly for election administration purposes unless it certifies to the EAC that it holds open primaries for elections for state and local office.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
