<bill session="115" type="h" number="1790" updated="2017-08-30T19:45:18Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Health Care Trust Fund Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Health Care Trust Fund Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish, in the event of any war, a war tax to be collected and deposited in a trust fund for the payment of benefits and compensation to veterans of that war.</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans Health Care Trust Fund Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2017-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2017-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2017-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Health Care Trust Fund Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), upon the commencement of any war, to establish a trust fund to be named for that war.

Amounts collected pursuant to a war tax (required by this bill) shall be deposited into such fund and may be used by the VA to provide for veterans who serve on active duty during that war programs and benefits directly related to their health care.

For any fiscal year during which the VA makes a withdrawal from such a fund, the Government Accountability Office shall conduct an audit of the consolidated financial statements relating to the fund.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for the imposition upon individuals who have not served on active duty in the Armed Forces of a graduated income tax with respect to each war occurring at any time during the taxable year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
