<bill session="115" type="h" number="2471" updated="2017-09-21T04:29:58Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-12T13:28:11-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-09-12T13:28:11-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Release Announcements to Counter Extremist Recidivism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Release Announcements to Counter Extremist Recidivism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRACER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Terrorist Release Announcements to Counter Extremist Recidivism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Terrorist Release Announcements to Counter Extremist Recidivism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">TRACER Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to share with State, local, and regional fusion centers release information from a Federal correctional facility, including name, charging date, and expected place and date of release, of certain individuals who may pose a terrorist threat, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Terrorist Release Announcements to Counter Extremist Recidivism Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000609"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T13:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McCaul moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T13:20:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7247-7248" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T13:20:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2471.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-09-12T13:28:11-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7247" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T13:28:12-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Counterterrorism and Intelligence" code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Terrorist Release Announcements to Counter Extremist Recidivism Act or the TRACER Act

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to share with state, local, and regional fusion centers through the DHS State, Local, and Regional Fusion Center Initiative, for homeland security purposes, release information from a federal correctional facility, including the name, charging date, and expected place and date of release, of individuals convicted of a federal crime of terrorism.

A fusion center serves as a focal point within the state and local environment for the receipt, analysis, gathering, and sharing of threat-related information between the federal government and state, local, tribal, territorial, and private sector partners.

 DHS shall coordinate with appropriate federal officials to provide state, local, and regional fusion centers with periodic assessments regarding the overall threat from known or suspected terrorists currently incarcerated in a federal correctional facility.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
