<bill session="115" type="h" number="2866" updated="2017-09-13T19:30:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-20T19:01:29-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-06-20T19:01:29-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Barriers for Relative Foster Parents Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Barriers for Relative Foster Parents Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Reducing Unnecessary Barriers for Relative Foster Parents Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Reducing Unnecessary Barriers for Relative Foster Parents Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To review and improve licensing standards for placement in a relative foster family home.</title>
    <title type="display">Reducing Unnecessary Barriers for Relative Foster Parents Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2017-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2017-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2017-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2017-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2017-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kelly (PA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20T16:03:13-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4955-4958" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20T16:03:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2866.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20T16:26:17-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20T18:52:16-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4979" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="310" datetime="2017-06-20T19:01:29-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 382 - 19 (Roll no. 310).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4955" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20T19:01:30-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Human Resources" code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="253"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-20T13:24:39Z" status="Passed House amended">Reducing Unnecessary Barriers for Relative Foster Parents Act

(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to identify reputable model standards for the licensing of foster family homes.

Part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act is amended to require state plans for foster care and adoption assistance to require submission to HHS of information addressing:

 whether the state licensing standards are in accord with HHS-identified model standards, and if not, the reason for the specific deviation and a description of why having a standard that is reasonably in accord with the corresponding national model standards is not appropriate for the state; whether the state has elected to waive certain standards for relative foster family homes, a description of standards most commonly waived, and if the state has not so elected, the reason why; if the state has elected to waive such standards, how caseworkers are trained to use the waiver authority and whether the state has developed a process or offered tools to assist caseworkers in waiving nonsafety standards to quickly place children with relatives; and a description of the steps the state is taking to improve caseworker training or the process, if any.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
