<bill session="115" type="s" number="585" updated="2017-10-13T11:57:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-12T15:39:41-04:00">PASSED:BILL</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-10-12T15:39:41-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide greater whistleblower protections for Federal employees, increased awareness of Federal whistleblower protections, and increased accountability and required discipline for Federal supervisors who retaliate against whistleblowers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2017-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with amendments. With written report No. 115-44.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="57">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 57.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2017-05-25" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3190" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3192-3194" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26T10:02:07-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-10T18:44:36-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 562 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of S. 585 with 1 hour of general debate. Bill is closed to amendments. The resolution provides for proceedings during the period from October 16, 2017, through October 20, 2017; and provides for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-11T13:51:36-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 562 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T13:15:54-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 562.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7998-8004" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T13:15:59-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of S. 585 with 1 hour of general debate. Bill is closed to amendments. The resolution provides for proceedings during the period from October 16, 2017, through October 20, 2017; and provides for consideration of motions to suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T13:16:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on S. 585.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T13:41:34-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T13:42:34-04:00">
      <text>Mr. O'Halleran moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8003" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T13:42:47-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the O'Halleran motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House forthwith with an amendment to add a new section at the end of title I related to Disclosure of Violations Relating to Air Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T13:47:49-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T13:48:21-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the O'Halleran motion to recommit, the Chair put the question on the motion, and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. O'Halleran demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion to recommit until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T15:24:30-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8010-8012" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T15:32:40-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 190 - 232 (Roll no. 567).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="568" datetime="2017-10-12T15:39:41-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 420 - 0 (Roll no. 568).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7989" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12T15:39:43-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" code="HSVR08" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="562"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3042"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Office of Special Counsel"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T12:46:08Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on May 4, 2017 . The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Dr. Chris Kirkpatrick Whistleblower Protection Act of 2017

TITLE I--EMPLOYEES GENERALLY

(Sec. 102) This bill directs federal agencies (excluding any entity that is an element of the intelligence community) to give priority to an employee transfer request if the Merit Systems Protections Board (MSPB) grants a stay of a personnel action at the request of: (1) the Office of Special Counsel (OSC) if the OSC determines the personnel action was taken, or is to be taken, as a result of a prohibited personnel practice; or (2) the employee if the individual is in probationary status and seeks corrective action.

The Government Accountability Office (GAO) shall report to Congress on retaliation against employees in probationary status.

(Sec. 103) The bill: (1) prohibits any employee who has the authority to take a personnel action to access the medical records of another employee or applicant for employment, (2) authorizes disciplinary action against supervisors for retaliation against whistleblowers.

(Sec. 105) Agencies must: (1) refer information about employee suicides to the OSC, (2) train supervisors on responding to complaints alleging whistleblower protections violations, (3) provide information regarding whistleblower protections to new employees during probationary periods, (4) inform employees of the role of the OSC and the MSPB with regard to whistleblower protection, and (5) make information about such protections available on agency websites.

TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS EMPLOYEES

(Sec. 201) The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) must: (1) submit a plan to prevent unauthorized access to the medical records of VA employees; (2) conduct an outreach program to inform its employees of available mental health services, including telemedicine options; and (3) ensure protocols are in effect to address threats against VA employees providing health care.

(Sec. 204) The GAO shall assess the reporting, staffing, accountability, and chain of command structure of the VA police officers at VA medical centers.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-44</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
