<bill session="115" type="h" number="3251" updated="2017-09-12T07:16:08Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Discovery Trails Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Discovery Trails Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Trails System Act to include national discovery trails and to designate the American Discovery Trail, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Discovery Trails Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2017-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2017-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">National Discovery Trails Act

 This bill amends the National Trails System Act to establish as part of the national trails system national discovery trails, which shall be extended, continuous interstate trails located to provide for outdoor recreation and travel and to connect representative examples of America's trails and communities.

The bill authorizes the designation of such trails on federal lands and, with the owner's consent, on nonfederal lands.

 The 6,000-mile American Discovery Trail extending from Cape Henlopen State Park in Delaware to Point Reyes National Seashore in California, splitting into northern and southern routes at Cincinnati, Ohio, and rejoining at Denver, Colorado, is designated as a national discovery trail.

The bill sets forth requirements for designation of a trail as a national discovery trail.

 The appropriate federal department for each national discovery trail shall: (1) administer the trail in cooperation with a competent trailwide volunteer-based organization; and (2) submit a comprehensive plan for the trail's protection, management, development, and use.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
