<bill session="115" type="s" number="489" updated="2017-06-19T21:15:17Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pension Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pension Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to participant votes on the suspension of benefits under multiemployer plans in critical and declining status.</title>
    <title type="display">Pension Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2017-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pension Accountability Act

This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code to revise rules for voting on the suspension of pension benefits under multiemployer plans in endangered or critical status. The bill changes the voting procedure for suspending plan benefits to provide that a suspension shall go into effect unless a majority of plan participants and beneficiaries who cast a vote (currently, a majority of all plan participants and beneficiaries) reject the suspension. The bill also eliminates the authority of the Department of the Treasury, in the case of systemically important plans, to override a vote of plan participants to reject a suspension. A plan is systemically important if projected financial assistance to the plan will exceed $1 billion if suspensions are not implemented.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
