<bill session="115" type="h" number="2468" updated="2017-09-21T04:29:58Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-12T12:52:13-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-09-12T12:52:13-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish a homeland intelligence doctrine for the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:45:48-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Perry moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:45:59-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7241-7242" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:46:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2468.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-09-12T12:52:13-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7241" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:52:14-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Counterterrorism and Intelligence" code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) Chief Intelligence Officer (CIO) to develop and disseminate written DHS-wide guidance for the processing, analysis, production, and dissemination of homeland security information and terrorism information.

 The guidance shall include:

 a description of guiding principles and purposes of DHS's intelligence enterprise; a summary of the roles and responsibilities of each DHS intelligence component and component program in the processing, analysis, production, or dissemination of such information; rules and regulations for the processing, analysis, production, and dissemination of such information; and an assessment of how the dissemination of such information assists intelligence community and federal law enforcement entities in carrying out their missions. DHS shall: (1) for each of the next five fiscal years, review and revise such guidance; and (2) provide a staff having appropriate expertise and experience to assist the CIO.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
