<bill session="115" type="h" number="612" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:30Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-31T16:52:45-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-01-31T16:52:45-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">United States-Israel Cybersecurity Cooperation Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">United States-Israel Cybersecurity Cooperation Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Israel Cybersecurity Cooperation Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Israel Cybersecurity Cooperation Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program at the Department of Homeland Security to promote cooperative research and development between the United States and Israel on cybersecurity.</title>
    <title type="display">United States-Israel Cybersecurity Cooperation Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000601" joined="2017-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T16:36:04-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Ratcliffe moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T16:36:28-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H798-800" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T16:36:30-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 612.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-01-31T16:52:45-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H798-799" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T16:52:47-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="719"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Scientific communication"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-31T13:53:03Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

United States-Israel Cybersecurity Cooperation Enhancement Act of 2017&#160;

(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a grant program to support cybersecurity research and development, and the demonstration and commercialization of cybersecurity technology, in accordance with the Agreement between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the State of Israel on Cooperation in Science and Technology for Homeland Security Matters, dated May 29, 2008, or a successor agreement.

Grants may be awarded for social science research and technology intended to identify, protect against, respond to, and recover from cybersecurity threats.

To be eligible for a grant, a project must be a joint venture between: (1) for-profit, nonprofit, or academic entities (including U.S. national laboratories) in the United States and Israel; or (2) the governments of the United States and Israel.

Grants shall be awarded only for projects considered unclassified by both the United States and Israel.

DHS must require cost sharing of at least 50% from nonfederal sources for grant activities, but it may reduce the nonfederal percentage if necessary on a case-by-case basis.

DHS must establish an advisory board to monitor the impartial scientific and technical merit method by which grants are awarded and provide periodic reviews of the actions taken to carry out the program.

The grant program terminates seven years after this bill's enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
