<bill session="115" type="h" number="1140" updated="2017-08-25T19:46:00Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WMATA Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WMATA Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide additional funding for the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority and improve upon the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">WMATA Improvement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000620"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">WMATA Improvement Act of 2017

This bill authorizes the Department of Transportation to provide additional grants for each of FY2018-FY2028 to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) for financing approved capital and preventive maintenance projects.

No grants may be provided until:

 the WMATA Board of Directors certifies that amendments have been made to the existing collective bargaining agreement between WMATA and a collective bargaining unit allowing WMATA to implement necessary operational changes required to provide a high level of service, reliability, and safety as well as lower costs through competitive bidding for certain capital improvements; and the WMATA Compact includes amendments requiring WMATA Board members to have a primary fiduciary obligation to WMATA, newly appointed Board members to have at least one of specified expert qualifications, and the Board to be composed of nine voting members, including the CEO of the Transit Authority and two appointed by each of the District of Columbia, Virginia, Maryland, and the Secretary of Transportation. Congressional consent for the Compact shall be withdrawn if Compact signatories (the District of Columbia, Virginia, and Maryland) fail to enact such amendments.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
