<bill session="115" type="h" number="829" updated="2017-10-06T12:45:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prioritizing the Most Vulnerable Over Lottery Winners Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prioritizing the Most Vulnerable Over Lottery Winners Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to clarify the treatment of lottery winnings and other lump sum income for purposes of income eligibility under the Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Prioritizing the Most Vulnerable Over Lottery Winners Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000031"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 20 - 11 .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3921"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1628"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Prioritizing the Most Vulnerable Over Lottery Winners Act of 2017

This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) to specify how a state must treat&#160;qualified lottery winnings and lump sum income for purposes of determining an individual's income-based eligibility for a state Medicaid program. Specifically, a state shall include such winnings or income as income received: (1) in the month in which it was received, if the amount is less than $80,000; (2) over a period of two months, if the amount is at least $80,000 but less than $90,000; (3) over a period of three months, if the amount is at least $90,000 but less than $100,000; and (4) over an additional one-month period for each increment of $10,000 received, not to exceed 120 months.

An individual whose income exceeds the applicable eligibility threshold due to qualified lump sum income shall continue to be eligible for medical assistance to the extent that the state determines that denial of eligibility would cause undue medical or financial hardship.

With respect to an individual who loses eligibility due to qualified lump sum income, a state must provide specified notice and assistance related to the individual's potential enrollment in a qualified health plan under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.

Qualified lump sum income includes: (1) monetary winnings from gambling; (2) damages&#160;received&#160;in lump sums or periodic payments,&#160;excluding monthly payments, on account of causes of action other than those arising from personal physical injuries or sickness; and (3) income received as liquid assets from the estate of a deceased individual.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
