<bill session="115" type="s" number="709" updated="2017-09-11T02:57:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Assistance Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Assistance Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency from taking administrative action to recover certain payments for disaster or emergency assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Disaster Assistance Improvement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1678"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Disaster Assistance Improvement Act of 2017

This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to prohibit the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) from taking administrative action to recover any payment made to a state or local government for disaster or emergency assistance initiated in any forum (with exceptions for fraud) after three years following the transmission of the final expenditure report for project completion, as certified by the grantee (currently, after three years following the transmission of the final expenditure report for the disaster or emergency).

The bill makes the same change with respect to the deadline: (1) for any dispute arising under such Act for which there shall be a presumption that accounting records were maintained that adequately identify the source and application of funds provided for financially assisted activities, and (2) by which the inability of the government to produce source documentation supporting expenditure reports shall not constitute evidence to rebut such presumption.

With respect to a payment for disaster or emergency assistance provided to a state or local government on or after January 1, 2004, FEMA may not take administrative action to recover such payment after the date of enactment of this bill if the action is prohibited under such Act as amended by this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
