<bill session="115" type="s" number="760" updated="2017-09-11T02:58:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">OPEN Government Data Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Open, Public, Electronic, and Necessary Government Data Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Open, Public, Electronic, and Necessary Government Data Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">OPEN Government Data Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Open, Public, Electronic, and Necessary Government Data Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Open, Public, Electronic, and Necessary Government Data Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the Government's use and administration of data to facilitate transparency, effective governance, and innovation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Open, Public, Electronic, and Necessary Government Data Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2017-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001197" joined="2017-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-07-24">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with amendments. With written report No. 115-134.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="180">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 180.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1770"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Open, Public, Electronic, and Necessary Government Data Act or the OPEN Government Data Act 

This bill requires open government data assets made available by federal agencies (excluding the Government Accountability Office, the Federal Election Commission, and certain other government entities) to be published as machine-readable data. When not otherwise prohibited by law, and to the extent practicable, public data assets and nonpublic data assets maintained by the federal government must be available: (1) in an open format that does not impede use or reuse and that has standards maintained by a standards organization; and (2) under open licenses with a legal guarantee that the data be available at no cost to the public with no restrictions on copying, publishing, distributing, transmitting, citing, or adapting.

 If published government data assets are not available under an open license, the data must be considered part of the worldwide public domain. Agencies may engage with outside organizations and citizens to leverage public data assets for innovation in public and private sectors.

Agencies must: (1) make their enterprise data inventories available to the public on Data.gov, and (2) designate a point of contact to assist the public and respond to complaints about adherence to open data requirements. For privacy, security, confidentiality, or regulatory reasons, agencies may maintain a nonpublic portion of their inventories.

The General Services Administration must maintain a single public interface online as a point of entry dedicated to sharing open government data with the public.

The Office of Management and Budget must develop and maintain an online repository of tools, best practices, and schema standards to facilitate the adoption of open data practices.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-134</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
