<bill session="115" type="h" number="675" updated="2017-09-15T07:16:22Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering Parents to Invest in Choice Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering Parents to Invest in Choice Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand the coverage of qualified tuition programs and increase the limitation on contributions to Coverdell education savings accounts.</title>
    <title type="display">Empowering Parents to Invest in Choice Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2017-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Empowering Parents to Invest in Choice Act of 2017

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow the payment of qualified elementary and secondary education expenses from a tax-exempt qualified tuition program (known as a 529 plan). (Currently, such plans only pay qualified higher education expenses.)

Included as qualified elementary and secondary education expenses are expenses for: (1) tuition, fees, academic tutoring, special needs services, books, and supplies; (2) room and board, uniforms, transportation, and supplementary items and services; and (3) and computer technology or equipment, including Internet access.

The bill also increases from $2,000 to $12,000 the limit on the amount that may be contributed to a tax-exempt Coverdell education savings account. The new contribution limit is adjusted for inflation in each taxable year beginning after 2014.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
