<bill session="115" type="h" number="1383" updated="2017-06-19T21:15:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Recognizing Officers and Enlisted Men of the Korean Constabulary Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Recognizing Officers and Enlisted Men of the Korean Constabulary Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct certain actions of the United States Government with respect to recognizing the service and sacrifice of veterans of the Korean Constabulary, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Recognizing Officers and Enlisted Men of the Korean Constabulary Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2017-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2017-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000477" joined="2017-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" code="HSFA05" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Recognizing Officers and Enlisted Men of the Korean Constabulary Act of 2017

This bill commends the veterans of the Korean Constabulary and thanks them for their support during the difficult times leading to the establishment of South Korea. (The Korean Constabulary undertook internal security tasks on behalf of the U.S. military government in Korea and the South Korean people from November 1945 to January 1949.)

The Department of State shall seek to urge the South Korean government to: (1) reexamine Article 16-9 of South Korea's Military Pension Act, and (2) expeditiously locate the records and remains of 7,235 combat dead of the Korean Constabulary. (Article 16-9 of South Korea's Military Pension Act denies veterans of the Korean Constabulary coverage for their service prior to the establishment of South Korea.)

The Department of Defense shall submit a report that: (1) describes potential awards and recognition for officers and enlisted men of the Korean Constabulary, and (2) examines the possibility of establishing new awards and recognition for those individuals if no awards or recognition currently apply.

The bill includes among persons who are eligible for interment in national cemeteries any veteran of the Korean Constabulary who, at the time of death, resided in the United States and was a citizen of, or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in, the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
