<bill session="115" type="h" number="1335" updated="2017-07-20T16:56:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cybersecurity Responsibility Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cybersecurity Responsibility Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Federal Communications Commission to issue rules to secure communications networks against cyber risks, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cybersecurity Responsibility Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001067"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Cybersecurity Responsibility Act of 2017

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to issue cybersecurity rules for communications networks (wireline or mobile telephone service, Internet access service, radio or television broadcasting, cable service, direct broadcast satellite service, or other communications service) to: (1) secure networks through managing, assessing, and prioritizing cyber risks and actions to reduce such risks; and (2) address the treatment of critical infrastructure information relating to such networks that is submitted to the FCC.

The bill requires communications networks to be treated as critical infrastructure and protected systems under the Homeland Security Act of 2002. The FCC is subject to the same requirements as the Department of Homeland Security concerning the protection of critical infrastructure information relating to communications networks that is voluntarily submitted to the FCC.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
