<bill session="115" type="s" number="467" updated="2017-07-27T04:49:39Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mohave County Federal Land Management Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mohave County Federal Land Management Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the disposal of certain Bureau of Land Management land in Mohave County, Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Mohave County Federal Land Management Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mohave County Federal Land Management Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to conduct sales of eligible lands in Mohave County, Arizona, which are administered by the Bureau of Land Management and have been designated for disposal by Interior.

Interior and Mohave County shall jointly select which parcels of eligible land to offer for sale.

Before carrying out a sale, Mohave County shall certify to Interior that qualified bidders have agreed to comply with:

 local zoning ordinances; and any master plan for the area approved by the county. Each sale of eligible land shall be:

 through a competitive bidding process, under which adjoining landowners are offered the first option, unless otherwise determined by Interior; for not less than fair market value, based on an appraisal; and conducted in accordance with the requirements regarding the administration of a sale of such land pursuant to this bill. The bill sets forth requirements for the disposition of proceeds from the sales of eligible lands under this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
