<bill session="115" type="s" number="1199" updated="2017-08-12T04:28:44Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Enforcement Security Task Force Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Enforcement Security Task Force Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to reauthorize the Border Enforcement Security Task Force program within the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Border Enforcement Security Task Force Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2017-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2281"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Border Enforcement Security Task Force Reauthorization Act of 2017

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), before establishing a Border Enforcement Security Task Force (BEST) unit, to apply risk-based criteria that takes into consideration specified factors, including:

 whether the area in which the unit would be established is significantly impacted by threats posed by transnational criminal organizations; the extent to which the unit would advance DHS's homeland and border security strategic priorities and related objectives; and whether departmental Joint Task Force operations would be enhanced, improved, or otherwise assisted by the unit. A BEST unit with a port security nexus must be composed of at least one member of: (1) the Coast Guard Investigative Service, and (2) the geographically responsible Coast Guard Sector Intelligence Office.

The bill requires DHS to submit an annual report on the BEST program for the next five years, and such report must include:

 a description of the effectiveness of BEST in disrupting and dismantling transnational criminal organizations; an assessment of how BEST enhances information-sharing, including the dissemination of homeland security information, among federal, state, local, tribal, and foreign law enforcement agencies; a description of how BEST advances DHS's homeland and border security strategic priorities and effectiveness of BEST in achieving related objectives; and an assessment of BEST's joint operational efforts with departmental Joint Task Force operations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
