<bill session="115" type="h" number="2184" updated="2017-09-11T02:46:07Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cyber Scholarship Opportunities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cyber Scholarship Opportunities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support meeting our Nation's growing cybersecurity workforce needs by expanding the cybersecurity education pipeline.</title>
    <title type="display">Cyber Scholarship Opportunities Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000601" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000588" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000238" joined="2017-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="754"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Cyber Scholarship Opportunities Act of 2017

This bill amends the Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2014 to require the federal cyber scholarship-for-service program that the National Science Foundation (NSF) coordinates with the Department of Homeland Security to include scholarship recipients who are students pursuing an associate's degree in a cybersecurity field without the intent of transferring to a bachelor's degree program and who either have a bachelor's degree already or are veterans of the Armed Forces.

The post-award employment obligations of scholarship recipients pursuing a doctoral or master's degree may include work at an institution of higher education or for a local educational agency teaching cybersecurity skills.

Scholarship eligibility factors are revised to include: (1) an individual's skills and abilities under the National Institute of Standards and Technology's national cybersecurity awareness and education program, and (2) students pursuing a degree on a less than full-time but not less than half-time basis.

The NSF must work with the Office of Personnel Management to consolidate information about cyber scholarships programs and job opportunities into a single online resource center.

The NSF may carry out a program to improve cybersecurity education at the K-12 level.

The NSF may: (1) grant exceptions from the post-award employment obligations to students who agree to work in a critical infrastructure mission at a federal government corporation or a state, local, or tribal government-affiliated component of a critical infrastructure sector; or (2) develop a pilot program to enhance critical infrastructure protection training for students pursuing careers in cybersecurity.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
