<bill session="115" type="s" number="799" updated="2017-09-29T04:34:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dynamic Repayment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dynamic Repayment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to simplify and improve the Federal student loan program through income-contingent repayment to provide stronger protections for borrowers, encourage responsible borrowing, and save money for taxpayers.</title>
    <title type="display">Dynamic Repayment Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Dynamic Repayment Act of 2017

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to replace several existing federal student loan programs with a single repayment plan that caps annual debt repayments based on income and forgives remaining balances after 20 or 30 years of payments.

The bill terminates the authority of the Department of Education (ED) to make federal Direct Stafford Loans, Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loans, and Direct PLUS loans, subject to exceptions for existing student borrowers, PLUS loans made to parents of undergraduates, and Direct Consolidation Loans.

To replace the programs, the bill establishes the Income Dependent Education Assistance (IDEA) Loan Program and the IDEA Loan Repayment Program, which:

 limit annual repayments based on the borrower's income; forgive remaining balances after either 20 or 30 years of payments, depending on the amount of the loan; and prohibit the accrual of interest on loans for active duty service members. The bill amends the Social Security Act (SSAct) to require ED and the Department of Health and Human Services to exchange information necessary to use the National Directory of New Hires to assist in the collection of student loans.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) require the Department of the Treasury to disclose to ED tax return information necessary to carry out the IDEA Loan Repayment Program, and (2) to exclude loan forgiveness under the program from gross income.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
