<bill session="115" type="h" number="1296" updated="2017-05-18T07:16:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide appropriate rules for the application of the deduction for income attributable to domestic production activities with respect to certain contract manufacturing or production arrangements.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide appropriate rules for the application of the deduction for income attributable to domestic production activities with respect to certain contract manufacturing or production arrangements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000462"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2017-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000289" joined="2017-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2017-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2017-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000015" joined="2017-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000594" joined="2017-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000586" joined="2017-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001195" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2017-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="638"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to specify rules for applying the deduction for income from domestic production activities to contract manufacturing or production arrangements.

In a contract manufacturing or production arrangement, a person contracts with one or more unrelated persons for the manufacture, production, growth, or extraction of an item of qualifying production property (tangible personal property, computer software, and sound recordings) or film. The qualifying production property must be manufactured, produced, grown, or extracted in whole or significant part within the United States.

In an arrangement in which any person makes a substantial contribution through the activities of its employees within the United States to the manufacture, production, growth, or extraction of qualifying production property: (1) the person shall be treated as engaging in the activity, and (2) the domestic production gross receipts of the person shall include the gross receipts received under the arrangement for the activities.

The Internal Revenue Service must prescribe regulations that include specified factors for determining a substantial contribution.

A person with an economic risk of loss of more than 50% of the direct material costs necessary to the manufacture, production, growth, or extraction of the qualifying production is deemed to make a substantial contribution.

The parties to an arrangement may agree in writing to: (1) make only one person eligible for the deduction, or (2) apply the rules retroactively to tax years in which only one person claimed the deduction.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
