<bill session="115" type="h" number="1259" updated="2017-08-23T04:44:47Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-16T17:59:13-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-16T17:59:13-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">VA Accountability First Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">VA Accountability First Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Accountability First Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Accountability First Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">VA Accountability First Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">VA Accountability First Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the removal or demotion of employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs based on performance or misconduct, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">VA Accountability First Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000375" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001301" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001289" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000626" joined="2017-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000621" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001045" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000174" joined="2017-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2017-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000611" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000586" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000592" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2017-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2017-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000815" joined="2017-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-10">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 115-34, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-10">
      <text>Committee on Oversight and Government discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-10" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="16">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 16.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T15:17:54-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 198.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2114-2135" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T15:18:48-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 198 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T15:18:49-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Harold Rogers to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T15:18:57-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1259.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T16:25:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 198, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roe (TN) Part A amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T16:26:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 198, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walz Part A amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T16:35:12-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Walz Part A amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Walz demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T16:35:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 198, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kuster(NH) Part A amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T16:40:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 198, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Taylor Part A amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T16:45:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 198, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tenney Part A amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T16:50:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 198, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kuster(NH) Part A amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T16:55:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 198, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Takano Part A amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T17:04:24-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Takano Part A amendment No. 9, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Takano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T17:05:27-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T17:35:13-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1259.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T17:36:53-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T17:37:10-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2122-2125" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T17:39:08-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Kihuen moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2133" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T17:39:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add language to the bill further defining protections to whistleblowers who file complaints.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T17:46:27-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T17:53:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 189 - 229 (Roll no. 167).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="168" datetime="2017-03-16T17:59:13-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 237 - 178 (Roll no. 168).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16T17:59:15-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="198"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="493"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1690"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h87"/>
    <amendment number="h86"/>
    <amendment number="h85"/>
    <amendment number="h84"/>
    <amendment number="h83"/>
    <amendment number="h82"/>
    <amendment number="h81"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-02-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">VA Accountability First Act of 2017

This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to remove, demote by a reduction in grade and pay, or suspend a VA employee, including a member in a senior executive position, for reasons of performance or misconduct.

The bill prescribes VA removal and employee appeals procedures.

Whistle-blower protections are revised, including by prohibiting VA from taking any such action against a person who has a pending whistle-blower complaint.

This bill provides for the reduction of federal annuities of VA employees and retirees convicted of a felony that influenced their performance while employed in such position.

The VA may recoup certain bonuses, awards, and reallocation expenses.

The VA may directly appoint qualifying individuals to the positions of Medical Center Director and Director of Veterans Integrated Service Network.

The bill revises time periods for adverse action reviews with respect to physicians, dentists, podiatrists, chiropractors, optometrists, registered nurses, physician assistants, and expanded-function dental auxiliaries.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-34</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
