<bill session="115" type="h" number="1933" updated="2017-07-27T22:15:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Options Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Options Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals to receive a premium assistance credit for insurance not purchased on an Exchange, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Health Care Options Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000533"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001273" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000616" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001056" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000392" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2017-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2516"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="761"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2086"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Care Options Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to temporarily permit certain individuals to use the premium assistance tax credit to purchase health insurance outside of an exchange established under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care (PPACA).

The bill applies to individuals who reside in a rating area or county that the Department of Health and Human Services has certified has no qualified health plans offered through an exchange established under PPACA.

Individuals residing in the areas or counties may use the premium assistance tax credit through 2019 to enroll in a plan outside of an exchange if the plan is: (1) authorized by the state in which the taxpayer resides to be offered in the individual market, or (2) is a not-for-profit membership organization that is organized and authorized under state law to accept member contributions to fund health care benefits for members and their families.

The bill prohibits advance payments of the credit from being made with respect to the off-exchange plans and specifies reporting requirements for the plans.

Through 2019, the bill also exempts the individuals residing in the counties or areas from the requirement to maintain minimum essential health coverage (commonly referred to as the individual mandate).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
