<bill session="115" type="hr" number="17" updated="2017-05-03T23:47:24Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing concern over the disappearance of Austin Tice, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing concern over the disappearance of Austin Tice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000553"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and North Africa.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Middle East and North Africa" code="HSFA13" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent)" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses concern about the disappearance of Austin Tice in Damascus, Syria, in August 2012.

Encourages the Department of State and the intelligence community to jointly continue investigations and consider all plausible explanations for Tice's disappearance and to coordinate investigations with the Syrian government and solicit information from appropriate regional affairs and law enforcement experts.

Encourages: (1) the State Department to work with foreign governments known to have diplomatic influence with the Syrian government, and (2) the intelligence community to assess the possibility of the Syrian government's involvement in Tice's disappearance and to possibly seek his recovery.

Requests the State Department and the intelligence community to continue to work with and inform Congress and Tice's family on efforts to recover Tice and resolve his disappearance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
