<bill session="115" type="h" number="844" updated="2017-10-03T07:15:53Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Deportation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Deportation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to facilitate the removal of aliens identified in the terrorist screening database, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Terrorist Deportation Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000615"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000374" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001290" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000362" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2017-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000609" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2017-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2017-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Terrorist Deportation Act of 2017

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to make an alien, other than a lawful permanent resident, who is identified in the terrorist screening database inadmissible or deportable on terrorist grounds.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS), with the unanimous concurrence of the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of National Intelligence, and the Department of State, may grant an individual a national security waiver to enter the United States temporarily as a nonimmigrant.

An identified alien shall be ineligible for asylum, withholding or cancellation of removal, voluntary departure, adjustment of status, or acquisition of legal permanent residency through the registry provisions.

DHS shall revise specified regulations implementing the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Forms of Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment to: (1) exclude identified aliens from the protection of such regulations, and (2) make such aliens ineligible for withholding or deferral of removal under INA.

The bill provides that, with respect to an alien who has not been granted a waiver under this bill and who either is not lawfully admitted for permanent residence or has been granted conditional resident status: (1) DHS shall determine inadmissibility or deportability and issue an order of removal for an identified alien; and (2) in the case of an alien not issued an order of removal, DHS may determine inadmissibility or deportability and issue an order of removal based upon terrorist activity. Such expedited proceedings shall include specified protections for the alien in removal.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
