<bill session="115" type="s" number="904" updated="2017-07-27T04:49:31Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening State and Local Cyber Crime Fighting Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening State and Local Cyber Crime Fighting Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the National Computer Forensics Institute, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening State and Local Cyber Crime Fighting Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2017-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000320" joined="2017-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001202" joined="2017-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2017-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1616"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening State and Local Cyber Crime Fighting Act of 2017

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish within the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) a National Computer Forensics Institute, to be operated by the U.S. Secret Service.

The institute:

 shall disseminate homeland security information related to the investigation and prevention of cyber and electronic crime and related threats; shall educate, train, and equip state, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers, prosecutors, and judges; shall ensure that timely, actionable, and relevant expertise and homeland security information related to cyber and electronic crime and related threats is shared with such officers and prosecutors; may provide such officers with computer equipment, hardware, software, manuals, and tools necessary to conduct cyber and electronic crime and related threat investigations and computer and mobile device forensic examinations; and shall facilitate the expansion of the network of Electronic Crime Task Forces of the Secret Service through the addition of such officers educated and trained at the institute.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
