<bill session="115" type="h" number="3262" updated="2017-09-14T07:15:37Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-28T11:23:52-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-28T11:23:52-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to provide educational assistance to certain former members of the Armed Forces for education and training as physician assistants of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to establish pay grades and require competitive pay for physician assistants of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to provide educational assistance to certain former members of the Armed Forces for education and training as physician assistants of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001301" joined="2017-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 115-267.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-28" calendar="Union" number="192">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 192.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28T11:12:28-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Roe (TN) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28T11:12:58-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6540-6543" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28T11:12:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3262.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-07-28T11:23:52-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6540-6542" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28T11:23:54-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28T11:23:56-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="426"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out the Grow Our Own Directive or G.O.O.D. pilot program to provide educational assistance to certain former members of the Armed Forces for education and training as VA physician assistants.

An individual is eligible to participate in the program if the individual:

 has medical or military health experience gained while serving in the Armed Forces; has received a certificate, associate degree, baccalaureate degree, master's degree, or postbaccalaureate training in a science relating to health care; has participated in the delivery of health care services or related medical services; and does not have a degree of doctor of medicine, doctor of osteopathy, or doctor of dentistry. The VA shall:

 provide educational assistance to program participants for the costs of obtaining a master's degree in physician assistant studies or a similar master's degree, ensure that mentors are available for program participants at each VA facility at which a participant is employed, and seek to partner with specified government programs and with appropriate educational institutions that offer degrees in physician assistant studies. The VA shall:

 establish specified standards to improve the education and and hiring of VA physician assistants, and implement a national plan for the retention and recruitment of VA physician assistants that includes the adoption of competitive pay standards. VA physician assistant pay grades are established.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-267</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
