<bill session="115" type="h" number="3650" updated="2017-10-10T20:00:17Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-08-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-08-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lumbee Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lumbee Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the recognition of the Lumbee Tribe of North Carolina, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Lumbee Recognition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000606"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2017-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2017-08-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000819" joined="2017-08-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2017-08-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-08-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2352"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1047"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-08-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Lumbee Recognition Act

This bill amends the Act of June 7, 1956, to extend federal recognition to the Lumbee Tribe of North Carolina and make its members eligible for the services and benefits provided to members of federally recognized tribes.

Members of the tribe residing in Robeson, Cumberland, Hoke, and Scotland Counties in North Carolina are deemed to be within the delivery area for such services.

The Department of Health and Human Services must develop, in consultation with the tribe, a determination of needs to provide the services for which members of the tribe are eligible.

The Department of the Interior may take land into trust for the tribe.

The tribe may not conduct gaming activities.

North Carolina must exercise jurisdiction over all criminal offenses committed, and all civil actions that arise, on North Carolina lands owned by, or held in trust for, the Lumbee Tribe or any dependent Indian community of the tribe unless jurisdiction is transferred to the United States pursuant to an agreement between the tribe and the state.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
