<bill session="115" type="h" number="1635" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:09Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering Students Through Enhanced Financial Counseling Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering Students Through Enhanced Financial Counseling Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the loan counseling requirements under the Higher Education Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Empowering Students Through Enhanced Financial Counseling Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000558"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2017-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2017-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2017-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2017-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2017-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2017-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2017-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000592" joined="2017-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000580" joined="2017-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2017-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000798" joined="2017-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Empowering Students Through Enhanced Financial Counseling Act

This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify loan counseling requirements for an institution of higher education (IHE) that participates in federal student aid programs.

Currently, an IHE must provide entrance counseling to a student who is a first-time federal student loan borrower. This bill replaces required entrance counseling with required annual counseling. Also, it expands the required recipients of such annual counseling to include, in addition to student borrowers, Federal Pell Grant recipients and parent PLUS Loan borrowers.

Each annual counseling recipient must receive comprehensive information on the terms, conditions, and responsibilities with respect to a grant or loan and general information on a typical student budget, the right to request an annual credit report, average income and employment data, and financial management resources. Additionally, the bill revises, expands, or establishes specific annual counseling information requirements for student borrowers, Pell Grant recipients, or parent PLUS Loan borrowers.

The bill revises and expands exit counseling information requirements to include an outstanding loan balance summary, the anticipated monthly payments under standard and income-based repayment plans, an explanation of the grace period preceding repayment, the option to pay accrued interest before it capitalizes, the right to request an annual credit report, and loan servicer contact information.

It directs the Department of Education to maintain a consumer-tested online counseling tool that provides annual and exit counseling.

 The Institute of Education Sciences must study the impact and effectiveness of exit counseling, annual counseling, and the online counseling tool.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
