<bill session="115" type="h" number="1461" updated="2017-10-05T21:45:18Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VET Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VET Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans, Employees, and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans, Employees, and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">VET Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">VET Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Veterans, Employees, and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Veterans, Employees, and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit an annual report to Congress relating to the use of official time by employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to limit the instances in which official time may be granted for certain purposes to employees of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">VET Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000375"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 13 - 11.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 115-146, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Oversight and Government discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-23" calendar="Union" number="94">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 94.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans, Employees, and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2017 or the VET Protection Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) track the use of official time by VA employees accurately; and (2) submit to the Office of Personnel Management and Congress, by October 1 of each fiscal year, a report on such use. "Official time" means any period of time granted to an employee under federal labor-management provisions to perform representational or consultative functions during which the employee would otherwise be in a duty status.

The bill prohibits: (1) a VA employee from using official time to carry out political activities or activities relating to lobbying; (2) a VA physician, dentist, podiatrist, chiropractor, or optometrist from using official time for any purpose; (3) other VA employees involved with direct patient care and other employees whose rate of basic pay is equal to or higher than a GS-13 from spending more than 25 percent of the time such employee would otherwise be in a duty status on official time; and (4) any VA employee from spending more than 50 percent of the time such employee would otherwise be in a duty status on official time.

Any exclusive bargaining agreement entered into by the VA shall allow a VA employee to terminate a voluntary allotment for the payment of dues at any time.

The appointment of a covered VA employee shall become final only after such employee has served a probationary period of 18 months. "Covered employee": (1) means any individual appointed to a permanent position within the competitive service or as a career appointee within the Senior Executive Service, and (2) does not include any individual with a probationary period prescribed by a provision applicable to specified health care practitioners. An employee's supervisor shall determine whether an employee's appointment becomes final by 90 days before the expiration such probationary period.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-146</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
