<bill session="115" type="h" number="1972" updated="2017-09-29T07:16:02Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Billing Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Billing Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to waive the requirement of certain veterans to make copayments for hospital care and medical services in the case of an error by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">VA Billing Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000594" joined="2017-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2017-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">VA Billing Accountability Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to waive the requirement that a veteran make copayments for medications, hospital care, nursing home care, and medical services if:

 an error committed by the VA or a VA employee was the cause of delaying copayment notification to the veteran, and the veteran received such notification later than 120 days (18 months in the case of a non-VA facility) after the date on which the veteran received the care or services. In requiring a veteran to make a copayment for care or services provided at a VA or a non-VA medical facility, the VA shall notify the veteran not later than 120 days (18 months in the case of a non-VA facility) after the date on which the veteran received the care or services. If the VA does not provide notification by such date, it may not collect the payment, including through a third-party entity, unless the veteran is provided with:

 information about applying for a waiver and establishing a payment plan with the VA, and an opportunity to make a waiver or establish a payment plan. The VA shall review and improve its copayment billing internal controls and notification procedures.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
