<bill session="115" type="s" number="516" updated="2017-06-19T21:15:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Cyber Resiliency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Cyber Resiliency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide grants to assist States in developing and implementing plans to address cybersecurity threats or vulnerabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">State Cyber Resiliency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1344"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">State Cyber Resiliency Act

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to administer a State Cyber Resiliency Grant Program to assist state, local, and tribal governments in preventing, preparing for, protecting against, and responding to cyber threats.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) may award states with planning and biennial implementation grants under the program to:

 adopt cybersecurity best practices; mitigate talent gaps in government workforces; protect public safety answering points, emergency communications, and continuity of communications during catastrophic disruption; mitigate threats to critical infrastructure or key resources; coordinate with neighboring states or countries, National Guard units, or information sharing and analysis organizations; and establish scholarships or apprenticeships to provide financial assistance to state residents pursuing cybersecurity education who commit to working for state government. The bill sets forth requirements for distribution of awarded amounts to local and tribal governments within states and for consultation with local and regional officials.

The Committee for Cyber Resiliency Grants is established to: (1) promulgate guidance for states to develop applications for such cyber resiliency grants; (2) provide DHS and states with recommendations regarding the approval of state plans or applications; and (3) evaluate, and report to Congress regarding, the progress of states in implementing plans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
