<bill session="115" type="h" number="497" updated="2017-08-29T04:28:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-27T16:21:29-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-06-27T16:21:29-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Santa Ana River Wash Plan Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Santa Ana River Wash Plan Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Santa Ana River Wash Plan Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Santa Ana River Wash Plan Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Santa Ana River Wash Plan Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Santa Ana River Wash Plan Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain public lands in San Bernardino County, California, to the San Bernardino Valley Water Conservation District, and to accept in return certain exchanged non-public lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal lands in San Bernardino County, California, to the San Bernardino Valley Water Conservation District, and to accept in return certain non-Federal lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Santa Ana River Wash Plan Land Exchange Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000371" joined="2017-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-04-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-02">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-155.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-02" calendar="Union" number="102">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 102.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-06-27T13:59:46-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cook moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-27T13:59:59-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5202-5204" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-27T14:00:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 497.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-27T14:08:46-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-27T16:15:07-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5217-5218" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="329" datetime="2017-06-27T16:21:29-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 424 - 0 (Roll no. 329).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5202-5203" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-06-27T16:21:30-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-27T16:32:01-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="357"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-27T12:55:53Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on June 2, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Santa Ana River Wash Plan Land Exchange Act

(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Department of the Interior: (1) to convey to the San Bernardino Valley Water Conservation District in California approximately 327 acres of identified federal land administered by the Bureau of Land Management and any portion of an identified federal parcel necessary to equalize the values of the lands exchanged; and (2) to accept in exchange approximately 310 acres of district land and any portion of an identified nonfederal parcel necessary to equalize the values of the lands exchanged.

To the extent an equalization payment is necessary pursuant to the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, the amount of such payment shall first be made by way of an in-kind transfer as may be necessary to equalize the fair market values of the properties exchanged. If after such in-kind transfer: (1) the value of the federal lands exceeds the value of the nonfederal lands, the district may make a payment equal to the remaining amount to the United States (if the district opts not to make such payment, the exchange shall not proceed); or (2) the value of the nonfederal lands exceeds the value of the federal lands, Interior shall order the exchange to proceed without requiring any additional payment by the United States to the district.

The values of the lands to be exchanged shall be determined by independent and qualified appraisers according to nationally recognized appraisal standards.

The district shall pay any costs related to such conveyance.

(Sec. 4) The land exchange shall be subject to continuing rights of the district to use, maintain, operate, construct, or relocate or expand groundwater recharge facilities on the nonfederal land exchanged to accommodate groundwater recharge of the Bunker Hill Basin to the extent that those activities are not in conflict with any Habitat Conservation Plan or Habitat Management Plan under which such nonfederal land may be held or managed.

(Sec. 5) The bill terminates Secretarial Order 241, dated November 11, 1929 (relating to the withdrawal of a portion of the federal land for an unconstructed transmission line) and revokes the withdrawal effected by such order.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-155</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
