<bill session="115" type="s" number="618" updated="2017-06-19T21:30:26Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lawful Interstate Transportation of Firearms Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lawful Interstate Transportation of Firearms Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to more comprehensively address the interstate transportation of firearms or ammunition.</title>
    <title type="display">Lawful Interstate Transportation of Firearms Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2017-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2017-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2017-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2017-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2017-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2017-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="358"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Lawful Interstate Transportation of Firearms ActThis bill amends the federal criminal code to revise provisions related to the interstate transportation of firearms and ammunition. An individual may transport a firearm between two places (e.g., states) where it is legal to possess, carry, or transport the firearm. During transport, the firearm must be unloaded and secured or securely stored. Additionally, an individual may transport ammunition, or a detachable magazine or feeding device, between two places where it is legal to possess, carry, or transport the ammunition, magazine, or feeding device. During transport, the ammunition, magazine, or feeding device must not be loaded into a firearm and must be securely stored. This bill prohibits the arrest or detention of an individual for a state or local firearm or ammunition violation unless there is probable cause to believe the individual failed to comply with the provisions of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
