<bill session="115" type="h" number="1668" updated="2017-06-19T21:30:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau of Land Management Foundation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau of Land Management Foundation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Bureau of Land Management Foundation as a charitable and nonprofit corporation to encourage, accept, obtain, administer, and use private gifts, devises, and bequests for the benefit of activities and services of the Bureau of Land Management, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Bureau of Land Management Foundation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2017-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Bureau of Land Management Foundation Act

 This bill establishes the Bureau of Land Management Foundation as a charitable, nonprofit organization to encourage, accept, obtain, administer, and use private gifts of money, devises, and bequests of real and personal property for the benefit of, or in connection with, the activities and services of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM).

The foundation shall conduct and encourage programs and activities, including by awarding grants, that support:

 educational, technical, scientific, and other assistance or activities to support the management of BLM lands with regard to wild free-roaming horses and burros, fish and wildlife and their habitats, National Conservation Lands, and recreation, cultural, and historic resources; and activities that support the reclamation and remediation of specified abandoned mine lands, specified orphaned oil and gas well sites, or public lands impacted by development connected to mineral exploration and development activities. Reclamation activities are to include the remediation of soil and water contamination; the restoration of wildlife habitat in order to restore the natural, scenic, historic, cultural, and ecological values of those areas; or promotion of the areas' economic potential.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
