<bill session="115" type="h" number="1269" updated="2017-10-06T19:15:18Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sacramento Valley Water Storage and Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sacramento Valley Water Storage and Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to take actions to support non-Federal investments in water infrastructure improvements in the Sacramento Valley, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Sacramento Valley Water Storage and Restoration Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000578"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2017-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000612" joined="2017-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2017-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2017-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Power and Oceans" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Sacramento Valley Water Storage and Restoration Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to:

 complete the final feasibility study authorized under the Water Supply, Reliability, and Environmental Improvement Act for the Sites Reservoir in Colusa&#160;County, California, which shall evaluate the development of the project as a non-federal project whereby Interior may be a participant in the locally preferred project;&#160; work with the Department of Commerce, the Army Corps of Engineers, and the Environmental Protection Agency to coordinate the efforts of the relevant agencies and work with the state of California, the Sites Project Authority, and other stakeholders to complete and issue the final joint environmental impact statement and report on the project; submit such study and report to specified congressional committees; and take steps necessary to ensure that, in return for any federal investment in a non-federal Sites project, a proportionate share of the project's public benefits are federal benefits. The bill amends the Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act to: (1) authorize Interior to participate in construction of the project if Interior determines that the project is feasible; and (2) direct the Bureau, at the Authority's request, to enter into a partnership agreement for the Authority to provide full project management control for construction of the project or a separable element of the project.

The bill directs: (1) the Bureau to advance the project as a non-federal project under specified circumstances, and (2) Interior to execute a long-term agreement with the Authority for the coordination of operations of the Sites project and the Central Valley Project.

With respect to the Sites project, the Bureau shall: (1) be the lead federal agency for the purposes of all federal reviews, approvals, or decisions required under federal law to allow either the Bureau or the Authority to construct the project; and (2) take steps necessary to ensure that all such reviews, approvals, or decisions are completed on an expeditious basis by January 1, 2022.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
