<bill session="115" type="s" number="1609" updated="2017-09-22T15:15:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill making appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Alexander. With written report No. 115-132.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-20" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="178">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 178.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3219"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3266"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1576"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3354"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2018

Provides FY2018 appropriations for U.S. Army Corps of Engineers civil works projects, the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation, the Department of Energy (DOE), and independent agencies such as the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.

Provides appropriations for U.S. Army Corps of Engineers civil works projects, including for:

 Investigations, Construction, Mississippi River and Tributaries, Operation and Maintenance, the Regulatory Program, the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program, Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies, Expenses, and the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works. Provides appropriations to the Department of the Interior for the Central Utah Project and the Bureau of Reclamation.

Provides appropriations to DOE for Energy Programs, including:

 Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability, Nuclear Energy, Fossil Energy Research and Development, Naval Petroleum and Oil Shale Reserves, the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, the Energy Security and Infrastructure Modernization Fund, the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve, the Energy Information Administration, Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup, the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund, Science, the Advanced Research Projects Agency--Energy, the Office of Indian Energy Policy and Programs, the Tribal Energy Loan Guarantee Program, the Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Program, and the Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program. Provides appropriations to DOE for:

 Atomic Energy Defense Activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration, Environmental and Other Defense Activities, and the Power Marketing Administrations. Provides appropriations to several independent agencies, including the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.

Sets forth permissible and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-132</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
