<bill session="115" type="h" number="2717" updated="2017-07-13T13:18:02Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STAPLE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STAPLE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Trained in America Ph.D.s From Leaving the Economy Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Trained in America Ph.D.s From Leaving the Economy Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize certain aliens who have earned a Ph.D. degree from a United States institution of higher education in a field of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics to be admitted for permanent residence and to be exempted from the numerical limitations on H-1B nonimmigrants.</title>
    <title type="display">STAPLE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2017-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Stopping Trained in America Ph.D.s From Leaving the Economy Act of 2017 or the STAPLE Act 

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to exempt from: (1) direct numerical limitations aliens who have earned a Ph.D. degree in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics (STEM) from a U.S. institution of higher education and who have an offer of employment from a U.S. employer in a field related to such degree; and (2) H-1B visa (specialty occupation) numerical limitations aliens who have a U.S. STEM Ph.D. and with respect to whom the petitioning employer requires such an education.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
