<bill session="115" type="h" number="1727" updated="2017-10-03T07:16:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Limiting Inhumane Federal Trapping Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Limiting Inhumane Federal Trapping Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit use of body-gripping traps by personnel of the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture and on lands of such departments.</title>
    <title type="display">Limiting Inhumane Federal Trapping Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000371" joined="2017-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2017-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2017-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2017-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2017-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000390" joined="2017-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2017-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2017-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2017-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000480" joined="2017-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000170" joined="2017-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2017-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E391"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Crimes against animals and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Limiting Inhumane Federal Trapping Act

This bill prohibits any personnel of the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture (USDA), in performing their duties, from using, recommending, training in the use of, or planning for the use of, any body-gripping trap used to kill or capture an animal. This prohibition does not apply to training in the dismantling of body-gripping traps that have been illegally placed.

No person shall use or possess any body-gripping trap on property under the administrative jurisdiction of Interior or USDA, except in Indian country, regardless of whether the person is employed by, or is working under a contract with, Interior or USDA.

Such prohibitions shall not apply to the use of a body-gripping trap to:

 control documented, invasive species to achieve resource management objectives where alternative methods have failed; or protect a species that is listed as an endangered or threatened species or treated by the Forest Service as a sensitive species. Such exceptions shall not apply unless:

 such use of a body-gripping trap is in accordance with state and federal law; prior to using such a trap, all available and viable nonlethal methods for such control or protection have been attempted; and such attempts have been documented in writing, and the documentation is maintained at the headquarters of the department that employs the individual engaging in such attempt. The bill imposes criminal penalties for violating the prohibitions in this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
