<bill session="115" type="s" number="74" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Marine Oil Spill Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Marine Oil Spill Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the ability of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Coast Guard, and coastal States to sustain healthy ocean and coastal ecosystems by maintaining and sustaining their capabilities relating to oil spill preparedness, prevention, response, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Marine Oil Spill Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2261"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Marine Oil Spill Prevention Act

This bill address issues related to preventing and responding to oil spills.

This bill amends the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 to extend the moratorium on oil and gas leasing in certain areas in the Gulf of Mexico until June 30, 2027.

This bill sets forth provisions concerning Coast Guard responsibilities, including designating areas that are at heightened risk of oil spills and implementing measures to ameliorate that risk.

 This bill amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to establish a Gulf Coast Regional Citizens' Advisory Council to advise on facilities and tank vessels.

 This bill makes an owner of oil responsible for oil spill cleanup. Currently, owners of oil are only responsible if the oil is being transported in a single-hull vessel.

This bill amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to permit the Coast Guard or the Department of Commerce to request a National Transportation Safety Board investigation of any accident occurring in the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS).

Commerce must establish an inspection fee for OCS facilities for the cost of inspections of facilities and other duties.

This bill requires a comprehensive review of the capacity of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to respond to oil spills. NOAA must develop and maintain oil spill trajectory modeling capability.

The Coast Guard must evaluate and validate oil pollution containment and removal methods and technologies.

NOAA must carry out long-term marine environment monitoring and research program for the Gulf of Mexico.

The bill requires the Coast Guard to publish within 12 hours an Incident Action Plan in response to an oil spill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
