<bill session="115" type="h" number="98" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:31Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Amend the Code for Marriage Equality Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Amend the Code for Marriage Equality Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To replace references to "wives" and "husbands" in Federal law with references to "spouses", and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Amend the Code for Marriage Equality Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000465" joined="2017-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Amend the Code for Marriage Equality Act of 2017

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC), the Social Security Act (SSAct), and other federal laws (including provisions concerning workers' compensation, retirement benefits, disability and death benefits, insurance, inheritances, or immigration) to replace: (1) references to "wife" or "husband" with references to "spouse"; and (2) references to "husband and wife" or "husband or wife" with references to "married couple" or " married person."

For purposes of federal laws or regulations, "marriage" is defined as a legal union between two people as spouses. The bill eliminates a definition of "spouse" that refers only to a person of the opposite sex who is a husband or a wife.

Requirements concerning compensation to a surviving wife after the disability or death of a person employed at a military, air, or naval base outside the United States are revised to make surviving spouses eligible for such compensation.

Under the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, provisions concerning the amount of leave available to a husband and wife employed by the same employer are revised to apply to a married couple employed by the same employer.

Requirements under the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 that make disability and death benefits payable to the wife or widow of a miner are revised to make the benefits payable to the spouse or surviving spouse of a miner.

IRC provisions that require a divorced wife's gross income to include the income of any trust she is entitled to receive that would otherwise be includible in the gross income of her husband, or vice versa, are revised to apply to the gross income of individuals who are divorced from their spouse.

The bill revises title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the SSAct to consolidate separate provisions for a wife's insurance benefits and a husband's insurance benefits into a single standard for a spouse's insurance benefits.

Criminal penalties that currently apply to persons who threaten to kill, kidnap, or inflict bodily harm upon a former President's wife or widow are revised to apply to threats made to a former President's spouse or surviving spouse.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
