<bill session="115" type="s" number="1090" updated="2017-08-10T12:27:30Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water and Agriculture Tax Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water and Agriculture Tax Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to facilitate water leasing and water transfers to promote conservation and efficiency.</title>
    <title type="display">Water and Agriculture Tax Reform Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000880"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2017-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2017-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2017-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2017-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Water and Agriculture Tax Reform Act of 2017

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit tax-exempt mutual ditch or irrigation companies to earn income from dispositions of certain real property and stock interests without affecting their tax-exempt status, but requires that such income be used to pay the costs of operations, maintenance, and capital improvements of such a company.

The bill also establishes a rule regarding the organizational governance of mutual ditch or irrigation companies. Where state law provides that such a company may be organized in a manner that permits voting on a basis that is pro rata to share ownership on corporate governance matters, an organization's qualification as a mutual ditch or irrigation company must be determined without taking into account whether its member shareholders have one vote on corporate governance matters per share held in the corporation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
