<bill session="115" type="h" number="164" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:26Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing Access to Voluntary Screening for HIV/AIDS and STIs Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing Access to Voluntary Screening for HIV/AIDS and STIs Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for an evidence-based strategy for voluntary screening for HIV/AIDS and other common sexually transmitted infections, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Increasing Access to Voluntary Screening for HIV/AIDS and STIs Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2017-01-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, Ways and Means, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Increasing Access to Voluntary Screening for HIV/AIDS and STIs Act of 2017

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) and title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require Medicare and state Medicaid programs to provide routine HIV/AIDS and sexually transmitted infection (STI) screening services. State Medicaid programs must provide these services without cost sharing for the screened individual. The bill amends the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Internal Revenue Code to require group health plans and health insurers to provide coverage for routine HIV/AIDS and STI screening under no less favorable terms than other routine health screenings. The bill prohibits activities to avoid these requirements.

State Medicaid programs may receive enhanced federal matching funds for covering individuals with HIV/AIDS whose income and resources do not exceed the limits for disabled individuals.

The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) must track STI screening trends and other information regarding people with disabilities and women who have sex with women.

The CDC must work with others to: (1) make sex education materials accessible to the deaf and hearing loss community and to people with intellectual disabilities, (2) track access to women's health services for women with severe mobility impairments, (3) increase the number of people in public health careers who are deaf or living with hearing loss, (4) ensure that cervical cancer screening guidelines state that women who have sex with women should be subject to the same screening as women who have sex with men, and (5) improve information collection concerning STIs in transgender communities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
