<bill session="115" type="h" number="200" updated="2017-09-27T07:13:04Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Fishing Communities and Increasing Flexibility in Fisheries Management Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Fishing Communities and Increasing Flexibility in Fisheries Management Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to provide flexibility for fishery managers and stability for fishermen, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Fishing Communities and Increasing Flexibility in Fisheries Management Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Power and Oceans" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening Fishing Communities and Increasing Flexibility in Fisheries Management Act 

This bill revises and reauthorizes through FY2022 the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (MSA).

Revisions are made to: (1) requirements for fishery management plans for overfished fisheries; and (2) catch limit requirements, including by authorizing Regional Fishery Management Councils to consider changes in an ecosystem and the economic needs of the fishing communities when establishing the limits.

To distinguish between fish that are depleted due to fishing and those that are depleted for other reasons, the term "depleted" replaces the term "overfished" throughout the MSA.

Fishery impact statements must analyze the impacts of proposed actions in fishery management plans on the quality of the human environment.

 The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) must publish a plan for implementing the Cooperative Research and Management Program.

 The offshore jurisdiction of Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama is extended from three miles to nine miles for the recreational management of red snapper.

The Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission must conduct all fishery stock assessments used for management purposes by the Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council for the fisheries managed under the Council's Reef Fish Management Plan.

Any commercial catch share allocation in a fishery in the Gulf of Mexico may only be traded by sale or lease within the same commercial fishing sector.

NOAA must develop a plan to conduct stock assessments for all fish for which a fishery management plan is in effect under this bill.Additionally, NOAA must develop guidelines that will incorporate data from private entities into fishery management plans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
