<bill session="115" type="s" number="1012" updated="2017-08-25T04:57:22Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for drought preparedness measures in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2017-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water and Power" code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">New Mexico Drought Preparedness Act of 2017

 This bill directs the Bureau of Reclamation to carry out a water acquisition program in specified basins in New Mexico, under which the bureau shall: (1) make acquisitions of water by lease or purchase of water rights or contractual entitlements from willing lessors or sellers, consistent with the Rio Grande Compact and applicable state and federal law; and (2) take other actions to enhance stream flow to benefit fish and wildlife, water quality, and river ecosystem restoration and to enhance stewardship and conservation of working land, water, and watersheds.

The Bureau, in cooperation with the Middle Rio Grande Conservancy District, may provide funding and technical assistance for the installation of metering and measurement devices and the construction of check structures to: (1) ensure the conservation and efficient use of water by reducing actual consumptive use or by not increasing the use of water, and (2) improve the measurement and allocation of water.

The U.S. Army Corps of Engineers shall continue, for five years after enactment of this bill, the temporary deviation in the operation of Cochiti Lake and Jemez Canyon Dam that was initiated in 2009 and terminated in 2013, to evaluate the benefits of the deviation.

The bill authorizes financial assistance to be made available for eligible water projects to help western states and tribal governments address drought-related impacts to water supplies or any other immediate water-related crisis or conflict.

The Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 is amended to: (1) authorize the use of water management improvement grants to assist applicants in planning for or addressing the impacts of drought, and (2) authorize the Bureau to waive any cost-share requirements.

The Department of Agriculture may allocate certain financial assistance made available under the Food Security Act of 1985 to establish special conservation initiatives at the local, state, or regional level to assist producers in implementing eligible activities on agricultural land in the western states for: (1) mitigating the effects of drought; (2) improving water quality and quantity; (3) restoring, enhancing, and preserving fish and wildlife habitat; and (4) promoting innovative and collaborative conservation tools and approaches.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
