<bill session="115" type="h" number="337" updated="2017-05-03T23:53:41Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-06T18:59:18-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-02-06T18:59:18-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Black Hills National Cemetery Boundary Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Black Hills National Cemetery Boundary Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain Bureau of Land Management land from the Secretary of the Interior to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for inclusion in the Black Hills National Cemetery, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Black Hills National Cemetery Boundary Expansion Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000184"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06T17:14:03-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Lamborn moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06T17:14:46-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H985-987" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06T17:14:48-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 337.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06T17:23:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06T18:52:34-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H993-994" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="80" datetime="2017-02-06T18:59:18-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 407 - 0 (Roll no. 80).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H985-986" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06T18:59:19-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-06T14:01:58Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Black Hills National Cemetery Boundary Expansion Act

(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) complete environmental, cultural resource, and other due diligence activities on certain public land to confirm its suitability for inclusion in the Black Hills National Cemetery, South Dakota; and (2) notify the Department of the Interior of such activities.

After completion of such activities and upon receipt by Interior of written confirmation of suitability from the VA, the land shall: (1) be withdrawn from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining laws, the mineral leasing laws, and the geothermal leasing laws, for as long as it remains under VA administrative jurisdiction; (2) be deemed property; and (3) be transferred to the VA for use as national cemeteries. (Sec. 3) Interior shall publish a notice containing the legal descriptions of such transferred land.

 The VA shall reimburse Interior for reasonable transfer costs, including survey costs.

(Sec. 4) Upon a determination by the VA that all or a portion of such transferred land shall not be used for cemetery purposes, the VA shall: (1) notify Interior and transfer jurisdiction of the land back to Interior, and (2) be responsible for any decontamination costs necessary for restoration of the lands to the public lands.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
