<bill session="115" type="h" number="729" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tobacco Excise Tax and Parity Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tobacco Excise Tax and Parity Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reform and enforce taxation of tobacco products.</title>
    <title type="display">Tobacco Excise Tax and Parity Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000581"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-30T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Tobacco Excise Tax and Parity Act of 2017

 This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the taxation of tobacco products, to:

 increase or equalize excise taxes on small cigars, cigarettes, pipe tobacco, roll-your-own tobacco, large cigars, and smokeless tobacco; impose an excise tax on smokeless tobacco sold in discrete single-use units; tax other tobacco products at a level equivalent to the tax rate for cigarettes on an estimated per use basis; provide for annual inflation adjustments for excise tax rates on cigarettes and tobacco products; restrict the sale, lease, export, import, or delivery of tobacco production machines to persons lawfully engaged in: (1) the sale, lease, export, import, or delivery of such machines; (2) the manufacture or packaging of tobacco products or processed tobacco; or (3) the application of unique identification markings onto tobacco products or processed tobacco packages; specify marking and labeling requirements; require manufacturers, sellers, or importers of tobacco production machines to obtain permits; establish new criminal offenses relating to the licensing and distribution of tobacco products or processed tobacco; increase the civil penalty for tobacco-related infractions; and allow sharing of tax return information with government officials for the administration of laws relating to tobacco products and processed tobacco. The bill also: (1) requires the Department of the Treasury to coordinate with other government officials in addressing tobacco tax evasion and conducting other enforcement activities, (2) amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to impose a civil penalty for the importation of tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes by fraudulent means, and (3) provides for the enforcement of this bill in Indian tribal areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
