<bill session="115" type="h" number="1275" updated="2017-06-19T21:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">World's Greatest Healthcare Plan of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">World&#8217;s Greatest Healthcare Plan of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To eliminate the individual and employer health coverage mandates under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to expand beyond that Act the choices in obtaining and financing affordable health insurance coverage, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">World's Greatest Healthcare Plan of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000250"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="520"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">World's Greatest Healthcare Plan Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal the requirements for individuals to maintain minimum essential coverage and for large employers to offer affordable coverage to full time employees.

Health insurance is no longer required to cover preventive care at no cost or include the essential health benefits.

Individuals enrolling in health insurance who have not maintained continuous coverage over the previous 12 months are charged an extra 20% on premiums for each consecutive year without coverage, unless the individual is subject to similar state incentives to maintain coverage.

States may enroll uninsured residents in high deductible health plans. Individuals must be permitted to opt-out of this coverage.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must develop a risk adjustment mechanism for health insurance in the individual market.

For residents of a state to qualify for premium subsidies or the health insurance tax credit in this bill, the state must permit health insurance with an annual limit on benefits to be sold on its exchange.

The bill establishes an advanceable, refundable health insurance tax credit for taxpayers enrolled in coverage that does not cover abortion except in certain circumstances.

States may: (1) apply to HHS to use unclaimed health insurance tax credits for indigent health care; and (2) enroll Medicaid-eligible individuals in health insurance that qualifies for the tax credit instead of in Medicaid, at the individual's option.

The tax on excess health benefits (commonly called the Cadillac tax) is repealed.

The bill establishes Roth HSAs (health savings accounts) for paying certain medical expenses and health insurance premiums.

The tax deduction for medical expenses is eliminated.

This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) and title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, including to turn federal Medicaid payments into block grants.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
