<bill session="115" type="h" number="157" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:30Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combatting Terrorism in Tunisia Emergency Support Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combatting Terrorism in Tunisia Emergency Support Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize assistance for the Government of Tunisia, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Combatting Terrorism in Tunisia Emergency Support Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2017-01-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tunisia"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Combatting Terrorism in Tunisia Emergency Support Act of 2017

This bill declares that it is the policy of the United States to assist the government of Tunisia in eliminating terrorist organizations that operate in Tunisia and neighboring Libya and preventing fighters in Syria from returning to Tunisia.

This bill expresses the sense of the Congress that:

 significant reform that protects fundamental human rights is necessary to enable the Tunisian security services to combat terrorism and reinforce the rule of law; expeditious consideration of sales, leases, grants, or transfers of defense articles, services, and equipment is consistent with U.S. policy to assist in eliminating terrorist organizations that threaten Tunisia's national security; Tunisia's peaceful pursuit of democracy should be fully supported by the United States; organizations such as Ansar al-Sharia and the Islamic State have created terrorist sanctuaries in Libya and represent a significant threat to Tunisia's democratic government; and supporting Tunisia's orderly reform of its economic and social sectors should be a U.S. priority. The bill authorizes the Department of State to:

 provide assistance to strengthen and reform Tunisia's security sector; support Tunisia's efforts to combat terrorism; provide assistance to support Tunisia's democracy and civil society; provide assistance to support Tunisia's border security by enhancing its capabilities to interdict illicit weapons trafficking; reprogram certain funds to support Tunisia's economic reforms; and enter into a memorandum of understanding with Tunisia to increase military cooperation, including joint military exercises, personnel exchanges, and enhanced strategic dialogue. The President is authorized to provide defense articles, services, and training to Tunisia to counter terrorist threats.

The State Department shall submit a strategic plan within 90 days to carry out this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
