<bill session="115" type="h" number="1961" updated="2017-08-08T18:30:26Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Southern Utah Open OHV Areas Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Southern Utah Open OHV Areas Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conveyance of certain land to Washington County, Utah, to authorize the exchange of Federal land and non-Federal land in the State of Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Southern Utah Open OHV Areas Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="837"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Southern Utah Open OHV Areas Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to convey specified land owned and managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in Washington County, Utah, to the state of Utah in exchange for specified state lands.

Upon the conveyance of the nonfederal land to Interior, such land shall be used only: (1) as an open riding area for the use of off-highway vehicles; or (2) for any other public purpose consistent with uses allowed under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act.

Interior shall convey, without consideration, specified Open OHV Areas managed by the BLM to Washington County.

Interior shall convey to the county, without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the (Open OHV Areas) land managed by the BLM and identified as Hurricane Sand Dunes (NRA).

Such conveyed land shall be used only as: (1) an open riding area for the use of off-highway vehicles, or (2) for any other public purpose consistent with uses allowed under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
