<bill session="115" type="h" number="691" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CHOICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CHOICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Hope and Opportunity for Individuals and Communities through Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Hope and Opportunity for Individuals and Communities through Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand opportunity through greater choice in education, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">CHOICE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000592"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2017-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2017-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000621" joined="2017-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000566" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001189" joined="2017-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="235"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Creating Hope and Opportunity for Individuals and Communities through Education Act or the CHOICE Act

This bill amends the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act to include among the eligibility criteria for opportunity scholarships, a requirement that a student in Washington, DC is enrolled, or will be enrolled for the next school year, in a public or private elementary or secondary school. (Opportunity scholarships are provided to low-income DC students to enable them to attend a participating private school of their choice.)

The bill also amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to allow states that have established a program which allows the parents of disabled children to use public or private funds for assistance with the cost of their children attending a private school, to supplement those funds with their allocation of federal special education funds.

The bill authorizes grants to support the design and initial implementation of state programs that allow the parents of a disabled child to make a choice of the appropriate public or private school for their child.

The Department of Defense (DOD)must carry out a five-year pilot program to award scholarships to enable military dependent students who live on military installations to attend the public or private elementary or secondary schools their parents choose.DOD must select at least five military installations to participate in the program and choose those where military students would benefit from expanded education options.

The Department of Education must return to the Treasury specified amounts made available for salaries and expenses.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
