<bill session="115" type="s" number="280" updated="2017-08-10T13:24:02Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crags, Colorado Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crags, Colorado Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Crags, Colorado Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Crags, Colorado Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize, direct, expedite, and facilitate a land exchange in El Paso and Teller Counties, Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Crags, Colorado Land Exchange Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2017-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 115-45.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="58">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 58.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="618"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-09T13:49:48Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Crags, Colorado Land Exchange Act

(Sec. 4) This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA), if the Broadmoor Hotel, Inc., (BHI) offers to convey to the USDA 320 acres of specified nonfederal land in the Pike National Forest in Teller County, Colorado, and a permanent trail easement for the Barr Trail in El Paso County, Colorado, to accept the offer and convey to BHI 83 acres of specified federal land within the Forest, together with a nonexclusive perpetual access easement for BHI to and from such land on Forest Service Road 371.

The nonexclusive perpetual access easement granted to BHI shall allow: (1) BHI to fully maintain, at its own expense, and use Forest Service Road 371 from its junction with Forest Service Road 368 in accordance with historic BHI use and maintenance patterns; and (2) full and continued public and administrative access and use of FSR 371 in accordance with the existing Forest Service travel management plan, or as it may be revised by USDA.

(Sec. 5) The USDA shall determine the values of the lands to be exchanged through appraisals following specified requirements. The values shall be equal, or if they are not equal, equalized as prescribed by this bill.

The Barr Trail easement donation shall not be appraised for purposes of this bill.

(Sec. 6) The land acquired by the USDA under this bill shall become part of the Pike-San Isabel National Forest.

It is the intent of Congress that the land exchange directed by this bill be completed within one year of this bill's enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-45</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
