<bill session="115" type="s" number="1425" updated="2017-08-31T13:27:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coordinated Ocean Monitoring and Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coordinated Ocean Monitoring and Research Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Coordinated Ocean Monitoring and Research Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2017-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2017-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-08-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Geography"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Coordinated Ocean Monitoring and Research Act

 This bill revises and reauthorizes through FY2021 the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009.

The Integrated Ocean Observing System (IOOS) is a network of federal and regional entities that provide information about the nation's coasts and oceans, as well as the Great Lakes.

 The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) must: (1) serve as the lead federal agency for the implementation of the IOOS, and (2) establish an IOOS Program Office to oversee daily operations and coordination of the IOOS. The bill outlines the requirements for NOAA as the lead agency.

 The bill establishes a process for regional associations to certify their regional coastal observing systems.

 The Joint Subcommittee on Ocean Science and Technology of the National Science and Technology Council must: (1) conduct an Ocean Chemistry Coastal Community Vulnerability Assessment on ocean acidification within a year and every five years thereafter; and (2) develop a plan to deploy ocean acidification sensors prioritized by the threat to coastal economies and ecosystems, gaps in data on ocean acidification, and research needs.

 The National Science Foundation's research on ocean acidification must include research on: (1) impacts of multiple stressors on ecosystems exhibiting hypoxia (a dead zone that is depleted of oxygen), harmful algal blooms (rapid accumulation of algae), or sediment delivery; and (2) the effects of those impacts combined with changes in ocean chemistry.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
