<bill session="115" type="s" number="1639" updated="2017-09-11T03:06:47Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Opportunity Carbon Fee Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Opportunity Carbon Fee Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gas emission fees, reduce the rate of the corporate income tax, provide tax credits to workers, deliver additional benefits to retired and disabled Americans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Opportunity Carbon Fee Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="3420"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Opportunity Carbon Fee Act of 2017

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose fees on: (1) fossil fuel products producing carbon dioxide emissions, including coal, petroleum products, and natural gas; (2) fluorinated greenhouse gases; (3) emissions of any greenhouse gas from any greenhouse gas emissions source; and (4) associated emissions (attributable to venting, flaring, and leakage across the supply chain).

The bill directs the Department of the Treasury to:

 establish, implement, and report on a program to identify all major source categories of associated emissions and collect data on associated emissions from the coal, petroleum products, and natural gas supply chains; make specified adjustments to the new fees for importers and exporters of energy-intensive manufactured goods; make a specified payment each calendar year to certain Social Security beneficiaries, veterans, and disabled individuals; make cost mitigation grants to states to assist low-income and rural households and provide job training and worker transition assistance; and establish a website to make regular disclosures concerning revenue, tax savings, and benefits attributable to this bill. The bill also: (1) reduces the maximum income tax rate on corporations to 29% of taxable income over $75,000; and (2) allows a new carbon fee offset tax credit for the lesser of: 6.2% of earned income, or $550.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
