<bill session="115" type="hj" number="64" updated="2017-05-03T23:49:56Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States giving Congress power to regulate campaign contributions for Federal elections.</title>
    <title type="display">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States giving Congress power to regulate campaign contributions for Federal elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001180"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Constitutional Amendment

This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment giving Congress the power to prohibit, limit, or otherwise regulate donations to candidates for federal office or to purchase media advertisements intended to influence the outcome of any such election.

 States may prohibit, limit, or otherwise regulate donations to candidates for state office or donations for media advertisements intended to influence the outcome of an election for state office or any other direct vote in the state.

 The amendment prohibits a person who is not a U.S. citizen or who is a foreign government or its agent from: (1) donating to a candidate for public office in the United States, or (2) making donations intended to influence the outcome of an election for public office or of any other direct vote of the U.S. electorate.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
