<bill session="115" type="s" number="554" updated="2017-09-29T19:45:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for reconciliation pursuant to section 2002 of the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2017.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide for reconciliation pursuant to section 2002 of the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2017.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2017-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1436"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to terminate the Prevention and Public Health Fund.

The bill increases funding for community health centers.

The Department of Health and Human Services may not make payments under the transitional reinsurance program.

The bill makes appropriations for grants to states to address substance abuse or urgent mental health needs.

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, including to require individuals to pay back all excess advance payments of the premium assistance tax credit.

The premium assistance tax credit and reduced cost sharing are terminated at the end of 2019.

The small employer health insurance tax credit does not apply after 2019.

Individuals are no longer required to maintain minimum essential health care coverage.

Large employers are no longer required to provide health coverage to employees.

For one year, the bill restricts the availability of federal funding for payments to certain family planning providers (e.g., Planned Parenthood Federation of America).

This bill amends the Social Security Act, including to end the expansion of Medicaid under PPACA on December 31, 2019.

The tax on high-cost, employer-sponsored health coverage (popularly known as the "Cadillac tax") does not apply after 2019.

The bill revises provisions regarding health savings accounts, Archer medical savings accounts, health flexible spending arrangements, and health reimbursement arrangements, including to allow payments for over-the-counter medications.

The bill eliminates various taxes and fees imposed by PPACA, including the tax on medical devices, the annual fee on health insurers, the indoor tanning services tax, and the net investment income tax.

Funds are provided to the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
