<bill session="115" type="hc" number="14" updated="2017-05-03T23:46:54Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reclaiming Congress's Constitutional Mandate in Trade Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Establishing the Joint Ad Hoc Committee on Trade Responsibilities to develop a plan under which the functions and responsibilities of the Office of the United States Trade Representative shall be moved to the legislative branch in accordance with article I, section 8 of the Constitution of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Reclaiming Congress's Constitutional Mandate in Trade Resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Trade" code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reclaiming Congress's Constitutional Mandate in Trade Resolution

Establishes: (1) a Joint Ad Hoc Committee on Trade Responsibilities to develop a plan under which the functions and responsibilities of the Office of the United States Trade Representative (USTR) shall be moved to the legislative branch, and (2) a Congressional Advisory Board on Trade Responsibilities to advise the Joint Ad Hoc Committee in its development of the plan.

Requires the USTR and the other heads of executive branch offices to make available to the Joint Ad Hoc Committee and the Congressional Advisory Board such information and assistance as the committee and the board may reasonably require to carry out their activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
