<bill session="115" type="h" number="1529" updated="2017-06-19T21:30:25Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Debt Limit Control and Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Debt Limit Control and Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury from using extraordinary measures to prevent the Government from reaching the statutory debt limit, or using extraordinary measures once such limit has been reached, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Debt Limit Control and Accountability Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000213" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000580" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000573" joined="2017-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2017-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Debt Limit Control and Accountability Act of 2017

This bill prohibits the Department of the Treasury from using extraordinary measures either to prevent the United States from reaching the statutory debt limit or once the debt limit has been reached.

Under the bill, extraordinary measures are:

 suspending investments of the Thrift Savings Plan G Fund or the Exchange Stabilization Fund, suspending the issuance of new securities to the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund and Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund, redeeming early securities held by the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund and the Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund, suspending the issuance of new State and Local Government Series securities and savings bonds, replacing Treasury securities subject to the debt limit with debt issued by the Federal Financing Bank, or any other extraordinary actions taken by Treasury to avoid defaulting on the obligations of the United States. The bill also repeals statutory provisions that established procedures for presidential modification of the debt ceiling.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
