<bill session="115" type="h" number="210" updated="2017-10-05T07:12:49Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Energy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the development of energy on Indian lands by reducing Federal regulations that impede tribal development of Indian lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Native American Energy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2017-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-10-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 25 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Native American Energy Act

 This bill amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to permit certain entities to appraise Indian land or trust assets involved in a transaction requiring Department of Interior approval. (Currently, Interior sets appraisal requirements.) A tribe may waive the requirement for an appraisal.

Certain agencies within Interior must use a uniform system of reference numbers and tracking systems for oil and gas wells.

This bill amends the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to make environmental impact statements for major federal actions (excluding actions related to gaming) on Indian lands available only to certain entities.

The bill sets forth provisions for the judicial review of a cause of action related to energy development on Indian land.

This bill amends the Tribal Forest Protection Act of 2004 to direct Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to enter into agreements with Indian tribes to carry out demonstration projects that promote biomass energy production. Interior and USDA may carry out demonstration projects by which tribes may perform the functions of programs under that Act.

Activity pursuant to a tribal resource management plan approved by Interior is considered to be a sustainable management practice.

This bill amends the Long-Term Leasing Act to revise the types and duration of leases the Navajo Nation may enter without Interior's approval.

 Certain Interior rules regarding energy production do not apply on land held in trust for Indians or on restricted Indian land, except with the consent of the Indian beneficiaries.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
