<bill session="115" type="h" number="802" updated="2017-06-19T21:00:32Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aid to Allies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aid to Allies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit Senegal from receiving certain forms of development assistance for a two-year period and make available such assistance to Rwanda and Uganda, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Aid to Allies Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001187"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Rwanda"/>
    <term name="Senegal"/>
    <term name="Uganda"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="West Bank"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Aid to Allies Act

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that:

 in periods of constrained resources all budget items deserve scrutiny, especially foreign aid dollars; rather than assisting governments that undermine our allies, such dollars would be better spent in countries that support the shared interests of the American people; and the Board of the Millennium Challenge Corporation should not enter into any compact with Senegal until the board reports to Congress regarding Senegal's eligibility to meet specified democratic and economic criteria that consider the impact of Senegal's co-sponsorship of U.N. Security Council Resolution 2334 and other governance issues with respect to Senegal. Such resolution characterizes Israeli settlements in the West Bank and East Jerusalem as illegal and demands cessation of settlement activities.

The bill prohibits Senegal from receiving certain development assistance under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 for two years and makes such assistance available to Rwanda and Uganda.

The President's Malaria Initiative, the Feed the Future program, and the President's Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief are exempted from such prohibition.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
