<bill session="115" type="s" number="1116" updated="2017-10-11T22:00:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Community Economic Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Economic Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Native American Business Development, Trade Promotion, and Tourism Act of 2000, the Buy Indian Act, and the Native American Programs Act of 1974 to provide industry and economic development opportunities to Indian communities.</title>
    <title type="display">Indian Economic Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2017-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Indian Community Economic Enhancement Act of 2017

This bill amends the Native American Business Development, Trade Promotion, and Tourism Act of 2000 to establish duties for the Office of Native American Business Development (ONABD), including: (1) advising the Department of Commerce regarding the relationship between the United States and Indian tribes; and (2) serving as the point of contact for tribes, tribal organizations, and members of tribes regarding economic development and doing business in Indian lands.

The ONABD, the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs, and the Community Development Financial Institutions (CDFI) Fund must coordinate to support economic development in Native American communities.

CDFI Fund assistance benefiting Native American community development financial institutions does not require matching funds.

The Government Accountability Office must conduct a study that assesses: (1) current programs and services that assist Native American communities with business and economic development; (2) assistance provided to Native Americans pursuant to loan, bond, and tax incentive programs; and (3) alternative incentives for tribal governments to invest in a Native American community development investment fund or bank.

This bill amends the Buy Indian Act, including to require the Department of Health and Human Services to use Native American labor and purchase Native American industry products.

This bill amends the Native American Programs Act of 1974 to permit the Bureau of Indian Affairs to provide financial assistance to certain Native American community development financial institutions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
