<bill session="115" type="h" number="2134" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Endangered Species Management Self-Determination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Endangered Species Management Self-Determination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to permit Governors of States to regulate intrastate endangered species and intrastate threatened species, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Endangered Species Management Self-Determination Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000569"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2017-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000576" joined="2017-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000592" joined="2017-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2017-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001195" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2017-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="935"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Endangered Species Management Self-Determination Act

This bill amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (ESA) to require the Department of the Interior and the Department of Commerce to obtain the consent of each state for adding species to the list of threatened or endangered plants and animals when the species is present in the state.

Interior must submit to Congress a list of all endangered or threatened species. Congress must give its approval by a joint resolution before the list may take effect.

 Species are automatically taken off the list after five years, but Interior may petition for the species to be relisted. Interested persons may no longer petition for the addition or removal of a species from the list.

A state may regulate intrastate endangered or threatened species that are present within its boundaries. If a state elects to regulate those species, it is given exclusive authority to manage species and their habitats. State action with respect to intrastate species is not subject to judicial review.

The Bonneville, Southeastern, Southwestern, and Western Area Power Administrations must include in customer monthly billing statements information on the share of costs to the customer incurred as a result of compliance with the ESA, unless the costs are for intrastate species regulated by states.

Owners or lessees of property may apply to Interior for a determination of whether a proposed property use will violate the ESA. The use is deemed compliant if Interior fails to respond within 90 days. The owners and lessees may seek monetary compensation for unfavorable determinations.

The bill eliminates awards of attorney fees in citizen suits under the ESA.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
