<bill session="115" type="s" number="418" updated="2017-09-13T12:03:31Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of State and United States Agency for International Development Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of State and United States Agency for International Development Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require reporting on the implementation of Government Accountability Office recommendations by the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development.</title>
    <title type="display">Department of State and United States Agency for International Development Accountability Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of State and United States Agency for International Development Accountability Act of 2017

This bill requires: (1) the Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to submit: (1) a report listing all outstanding recommendations from the Government Accountability Office (GAO) that relate to the State Department or USAID that have not been fully implemented, and (2) a report on the implementation status of such recommendations.

The GAO shall report on any discrepancies between State Department-USAID list of outstanding recommendations and GAO's list.

The implementation status report shall include:

 for any recommendation the State Department or USAID has decided not to fully implement or to implement in a different manner than what was recommended, a detailed justification for the decision; for any recommendation the State Department or USAID has decided to adopt but which has not been fully implemented, a timeline for full implementation; and an explanation for any discrepancies included in the GAO report.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
