<bill session="115" type="h" number="3572" updated="2017-10-13T07:17:05Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making College More Affordable Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making College More Affordable Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To carry out an income-contingent repayment program for Federal Interest Free Education Loans for undergraduate students, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Making College More Affordable Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2017-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2017-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Making College More Affordable Act

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 by creating federal interest-free education loans for undergraduate students. The loans must have the same terms and conditions and benefits to borrowers as federal direct Stafford Loans. Interest on the interest-free loans may only accrue during periods when a borrower is not earning taxable income due to professional negligence, professional incompetence, or malicious action on the part of the borrower.

The Department of Education (ED) must carry out a repayment plan program for the interest-free loans under which loans payments are automatically withheld from the pre-tax income of the borrower.

ED must cancel any outstanding balance of principal or interest due on those interest-free loans made to a borrower who has made 300 monthly payments. The borrower must be taxed on the amount canceled. Those taxes must be applied to carry out the federal direct loan program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
