<bill session="115" type="s" number="51" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taking Action Against Drunk Drivers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taking Action Against Drunk Drivers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make habitual drunk drivers inadmissible and removable and to require the detention of any alien who is unlawfully present in the United States and has been charged with driving under the influence or driving while intoxicated.</title>
    <title type="display">Taking Action Against Drunk Drivers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2017-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2017-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2017-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2017-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2017-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2017-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2017-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2017-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2017-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000320" joined="2017-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2017-01-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Taking Action Against Drunk Drivers Act

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require the mandatory detention of an alien who: (1) was not lawfully admitted into the United States, held a revoked nonimmigrant visa, or violated his or her nonimmigrant status; and (2) has a pending federal or state charge of driving under the influence or driving while intoxicated, regardless of whether the offense is classified as a felony or a misdemeanor.

An alien convicted of three or more federal or state offenses for driving under the influence or driving while intoxicated, regardless of whether the offenses are classified as felonies or misdemeanors, is: (1) inadmissible, or (2) deportable if at least one of such offenses occurred after the enactment of this bill.

The definition of "aggravated felony" is expanded for purposes of such Act to include a third conviction under federal or state law for driving under the influence or driving while intoxicated, regardless of whether the offense is classified as a felony or a misdemeanor, for which the term of imprisonment is at least one year.

An alien who was convicted two or more times before the enactment of this bill for driving under the influence of alcohol or drugs may not be removed for the commission of an aggravated felony based upon such convictions until conviction of another such offense after the enactment of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
