<bill session="115" type="h" number="1425" updated="2017-06-19T21:15:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bring Small Businesses Back Tax Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bring Small Businesses Back Tax Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a lower rate of tax on a portion of pass-through business income, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Bring Small Businesses Back Tax Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001195" joined="2017-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Bring Small Businesses Back Tax Reform Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish new maximum individual tax rates for qualified business income that does not exceed $1 million (i.e., small business income). The maximum rates are: (1) 12% of such income not exceeding $150,000, and (2) 25% for income that exceeds $150,000 and is not more than $1 million.

The rates apply to up to $1 million of qualified business income that is: (1) gross earnings derived by an individual from any active trade or business carried on by the individual, excluding deductions attributable to the trade or business; or (2) the taxpayer's distributive or pro rata share of pass-through income from entities such as a partnership or S corporation. Qualified business income does not include capital gains, interest, dividends, or royalties.

For taxpayers that are not a corporation or a partnership with a corporation as a partner, the bill repeals the annual limitation on the election to expense certain depreciable business assets.

The bill also permits certain small businesses whose average gross receipts do not exceed $25 million (currently, $5 million) to use the cash accounting method without limitations and exempts such businesses from inventory rules.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
