<bill session="115" type="h" number="3379" updated="2017-09-11T02:55:43Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EARN IT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EARN IT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Advancement, Reducing Noncompliance, and Improving Trust Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Advancement, Reducing Noncompliance, and Improving Trust Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for an increase in the earned income tax credit for individuals with no qualifying children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">EARN IT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000464" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2017-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2017-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Enhancing Advancement, Reducing Noncompliance, and Improving Trust Act or the EARN IT Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the Earned Income Tax Credit (EITC) for individuals with no qualifying children and to establish additional requirements for claiming the EITC and the child tax credit.

The bill modifies the EITC for individuals with no qualifying children by:

 increasing the credit and phaseout percentages, increasing the earned income and phaseout amounts, reducing the minimum age to claim the credit, and modifying the formula for inflation adjustments. For a qualifying child to be taken into account for the EITC, a tax return must include a certification of the child's residency.

The bill prohibits the refundable portion of the child tax credit (commonly referred to as the additional child tax credit) from being claimed for a qualifying child unless the tax return includes a valid Social Security number for the child.

The bill increases from two to five years the disallowance period for taxpayers who improperly claim the EITC due to reckless or intentional disregard of rules and regulations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
