<bill session="115" type="h" number="296" updated="2017-10-12T07:15:50Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRO Sports Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRO Sports Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Properly Reducing Overexemptions for Sports Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Properly Reducing Overexemptions for Sports Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude major professional sports leagues from qualifying as tax-exempt organizations.</title>
    <title type="display">PRO Sports Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2017-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000460" joined="2017-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T13:45:43-04:00">
      <text>ASSUMING FIRST SPONSORSHIP - Mr. Gaetz asked unanimous consent that he may hereafter be considered as first sponsor of H.R. 296, a bill originally introduced by Representative Chaffetz, for the purpose of adding cosponsors and requesting reprintings pursuant to clause 7 of rule XII. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="3830"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Properly Reducing Overexemptions for Sports Act or the PRO Sports Act

 This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to remove professional football leagues from the list of tax-exempt organizations.

No organization or entity shall be treated as tax-exempt if it: (1) is a professional sports league, organization, or association, a substantial activity of which is to foster national or international professional sports competitions (including by managing league business affairs, officiating or providing referees, coordinating schedules, managing sponsorships or broadcast sales, operating loan programs for competition facilities, or overseeing player conduct); and (2) has annual gross receipts in excess of $10 million.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
