<bill session="115" type="h" number="2373" updated="2017-10-11T18:30:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act with respect to the accreditation of osteopathic residency training programs for purposes of graduate medical education payments under the Medicare program.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act with respect to the accreditation of osteopathic residency training programs for purposes of graduate medical education payments under the Medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000376"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2017-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to modify, with respect to graduate medical education (GME) payments under the Medicare program,&#160;provisions related to&#160;"approved medical residency training programs" by: (1) specifying that such programs include osteopathic community residency training programs; and (2) replacing the requirement for such programs to include certain postgraduate training in geriatric medicine with a requirement for approval by a certified accrediting body.

Under current law, a "foreign medical graduate" is generally a resident who was not a graduate of&#160;a school that meets the standards for accreditation by one of several specified accreditors. (Foreign medical graduates are subject to certain examination requirements for purposes of being counted as residents&#160;with respect to Medicare GME payments.) The bill alters this definition such that a "foreign medical graduate" is a resident who is not a graduate of an accredited school.

The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services must certify at least two accrediting bodies for the purpose of accrediting medical residency training programs in allopathic and osteopathic medicine.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
