<bill session="115" type="s" number="586" updated="2017-06-19T21:30:28Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corporate Tax Dodging Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corporate Tax Dodging Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the treatment of foreign corporations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Corporate Tax Dodging Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1451"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Corporate Tax Dodging Prevention Act 

 This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the taxation of the foreign-source income of domestic corporations, to:

 eliminate the deferral of tax on the foreign-source income of U.S. corporations for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017; include previously deferred foreign-source income of corporations as taxable income; deny the foreign tax credit to large integrated oil companies that are dual capacity taxpayers; limit the offset of the foreign tax credit to income that is subject to U.S. tax; treat foreign corporations managed and controlled in the United States as domestic corporations for U.S. tax purposes; limit the tax deduction of the interest expense of a U.S. corporation that is a member of a financial reporting group (i.e., a group that prepares consolidated financial statements according to generally accepted accounting principles or international financial reporting standards); and revise rules for the taxation of inverted corporations (i.e., U.S. corporations that acquire foreign companies to reincorporate in a foreign jurisdiction with income tax rates lower than the United States) to provide that a foreign corporation that acquires the properties of a U.S. corporation or partnership after May 8, 2014, shall be treated as an inverted corporation and thus subject to U.S. taxation if, after such acquisition it holds more than 50% of the stock of the new entity (expanded affiliated group).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
