<bill session="115" type="s" number="440" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:41Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a procedure for the conveyance of certain Federal property around the Dickinson Reservoir in the State of North Dakota.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to establish a procedure for the conveyance of certain Federal property around the Dickinson Reservoir in the State of North Dakota.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2017-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water and Power" code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill directs the Commissioner of Reclamation to: (1) provide to the holder of a permit for a cabin site located on federal property around the Dickinson Reservoir in North Dakota the first option to purchase the site for fair market value, provided that the permittee first pay to Dickinson Parks &amp; Recreation (the Department) any outstanding permit fees before exercising such option; and (2) convey to a permittee who exercises such option all U.S. interest in the site, easements for access to the site, a dock for the site, and the improvements on it. The fair market value of a property shall be determined by a local, third-party appraiser, valuing the property as unimproved residential property, excluding all improvements.

Beginning two years after enactment of this bill: (1) if a permittee has not exercised such option, the Commissioner shall transfer the site to the Department, without cost; and (2) the Commissioner shall transfer to the Department, without cost, land currently managed by the Department on which no cabin is located.

Each such conveyance and transfer shall be made subject to specified mineral rights and rights-of-way of third parties.

A permittee may not build any new permanent structure below an elevation of 2,430 feet. If a permittee builds such a structure, the permittee's site shall revert to the Department.

 Revenues from a sale of federal land pursuant to this bill shall be made available to the Commissioner for: (1) the costs of carrying out this bill, and (2) deferred maintenance activities relating to the operation of the dam in the Dickinson Reservoir.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
