<bill session="115" type="s" number="1169" updated="2017-09-11T03:00:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid Coverage for Addiction Recovery Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid Coverage for Addiction Recovery Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide States with an option to provide medical assistance to individuals between the ages of 22 and 64 for inpatient services to treat substance use disorders at certain facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Medicaid Coverage for Addiction Recovery Expansion Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2017-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2017-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2017-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3018" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2687"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medicaid Coverage for Addiction Recovery Expansion Act

This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to allow states to provide medical assistance to adults for residential addiction treatment facility services under the Medicaid program if such services are offered as part of a full continuum of evidence-based treatment services. "Residential addiction treatment facility services" are medically necessary inpatient services provided in an accredited, size-limited facility for the purpose of treating a substance use disorder within a specified time period.

The provision of medical assistance for such services to an individual shall not prohibit federal financial participation for medical assistance with respect to other services&#160;provided to the individual within the same time period.

Subject to specified conditions, a&#160;woman who is eligible for medical assistance on the basis of being pregnant may remain eligible for&#160;residential&#160;addiction treatment facility services&#160;for specified time periods without regard to eligibility limits that would otherwise apply as a result of her pregnancy ending.

In addition, the bill establishes a grant program for states to expand infrastructure and treatment capabilities of&#160;existing youth addiction treatment facilities that: (1)&#160;provide addiction treatment services to youths under Medicaid or the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP), and (2) are located in communities with high numbers of medically underserved populations of at-risk youths. At least 15% of grant funds awarded to a state must be used for making payments to rural facilities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
