<bill session="115" type="h" number="560" updated="2017-08-10T13:23:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-30T17:29:15-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-01-30T17:29:15-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area Improvement Act to provide access to certain vehicles serving residents of municipalities adjacent to the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area Improvement Act to provide access to certain vehicles serving residents of municipalities adjacent to the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2017-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-30T17:21:03-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McClintock moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-30T17:21:04-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H717-718" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-30T17:21:05-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 560.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-01-30T17:29:15-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H717-718" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-30T17:29:18-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 115-51.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="64">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 64.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-09T13:44:25Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House passed version is repeated here.)

(Sec. 1) This bill amends the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area Improvement Act with respect to the prohibition against the use of Highway 209, a federally owned road within the boundaries of the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area in Pennsylvania, by certain commercial vehicles except as they serve businesses located within or in the vicinity of the recreation area.

The local business use exception to the prohibition is revised to permit, until September 30, 2021, the use of commercial vehicles with four or fewer axles that are: (1) owned and operated by a business located in the recreation area or one or more adjacent municipalities, or (2) necessary to provide services to businesses or persons located in the recreation area or one or more such municipalities.

The adjacent municipalities referred to are Delaware Township, Dingman Township, Lehman Township, Matamoras Borough, Middle Smithfield Township, Milford Borough, Milford Township, Smithfield Township, and Westfall Township in Pennsylvania.

The Department of the Interior shall establish a fee and permit program for the use of Highway 209 by commercial vehicles, including an annual fee of up to $200 per vehicle. All fees received shall be set aside in a special account and be available for the administration and enforcement of the program, including registering vehicles, issuing permits and vehicle identification stickers, and personnel costs.

The following vehicles may use Highway 209 without a fee or permit requirement:

 local school buses; fire, ambulance, and other safety and emergency vehicles; and commercial vehicles along specified segments of the highway.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-51</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
