<bill session="115" type="s" number="458" updated="2017-09-22T19:00:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native Educator Support and Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native Educator Support and Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NEST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NEST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support the education of Indian children.</title>
    <title type="display">NEST Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2017-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2017-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2727"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Native Educator Support and Training Act or the NEST Act 

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish scholarships, loan forgiveness plans, and training programs for educators who commit to teaching in Native American or Bureau of Indian Education (BIE) schools.

This bill establishes three scholarship programs for students who are seeking degrees in education or school administration at institutions of higher education and commit to teaching in Native American or BIE schools:

 the Indian Student Educator Scholarship Program for students seeking degrees, the Indian Educator Scholarship Program for Indian students seeking degrees, and the Indian Educator Graduate Fellowship Program for Indian students seeking graduate degrees. Recipients of the scholarships must commit to working for a BIE school, a school serving Native Americans, or other specified schools and agencies for the greater of three years or the number of school years that the scholarship funded.

The bill establishes loan forgiveness programs for educators and Native Americans who have taught for at least five consecutive years at BIE schools or local educational agencies with high percentages of Native American students.

The bill extends the federal Perkins Loan Cancellation Program to educators teaching in BIE schools or in Native American language immersion programs.

The bill authorizes professional development grants for native-serving elementary and secondary schools. It also establishes the Native American Language Teacher Training Program to provide grants for institutions of higher education to develop training programs for Native American immersion and language teachers.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
