<bill session="115" type="s" number="1178" updated="2017-09-11T03:00:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Vulnerable Children and Families Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Vulnerable Children and Families Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to realign structures and reallocate resources in the Federal Government in keeping with the core belief that families are the best protection for children and the bedrock of any society to bolster United States diplomacy targeted at ensuring that every child can grow up in a permanent, safe, nurturing, and loving family, and to ensure that intercountry adoption to the United States becomes a viable and fully developed option for providing families for children in need, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Vulnerable Children and Families Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2017-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2532"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Vulnerable Children and Families Act of 2017

 This bill redesignates the Office of Children's Issues of the Department of State as the Office of Vulnerable Children and Family Security (VCFS).

The President shall appoint an Ambassador-at-Large to promote: (1) oversight of the VCFS; (2) the implementation in foreign countries of child welfare laws and policies in keeping with the goals of the United States Government Action Plan on Children in Adversity; and (3) addressing the gap in U.S. diplomacy, policy, and operations regarding permanent family care for children living without families.

The Ambassador-at-Large shall: (1) advise the State Department and the President about vulnerable children and family security in foreign countries; (2) represent the United States regarding international child welfare, family preservation and reunification, and provision of permanent, safe parental care; (3) develop related policies and programs; and (4) submit an annual report on implementation of such action plan.

 The bill provides the VCFS with lead responsibility for: (1) representing the U.S. government regarding intercountry adoptions, and (2) determining whether a country has met its obligations under the Hague Convention of Protection of Children and Cooperation in Respect of Inter-Country Adoption and is eligible to participate in intercountry adoptions in accordance with U.S. law.

 The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended to: (1) include in the annual country reports on human rights practices information on the conditions of children living in orphanages and group homes, and (2) repeal certain provisions providing assistance for orphans and other vulnerable children.

 The Special Advisor for Assistance to Orphans and Vulnerable Children shall work with the Ambassador-at-Large to ensure that U.S. assistance and development programs are focused on:

 child development through the integration of health, nutrition, and family support; facilitating government efforts to protect children from violence, exploitation, and neglect; building integrated child welfare and protection systems; and integrating such objectives with U.S. government agencies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
