<bill session="115" type="s" number="866" updated="2017-06-19T22:00:29Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prohibiting Detention of Youth Status Offenders Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prohibiting Detention of Youth Status Offenders Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to eliminate the use of valid court orders to secure lockup of status offenders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Prohibiting Detention of Youth Status Offenders Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2017-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2427-2428" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1885"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Prohibiting Detention of Youth Status Offenders Act of 2017

This bill amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to modify the deinstitutionalization of status offenders (DSO) core requirement with which a state must comply to receive funds under the Formula Grant Program. The DSO core requirement prohibits the secure detention or confinement of a juvenile who commits a status offense (i.e., an offense that would not be a crime if committed by an adult).

This bill eliminates an exception to the DSO core requirement that permits the secure detention or confinement of an out-of-state runaway youth.

It also eliminates, not later than one year after enactment, an exception to the DSO core requirement that permits the secure detention or confinement of a juvenile status offender who violates a valid court order. Until then, use of the valid court order exception to securely detain or confine a juvenile status offender must comply with additional requirements, such as issuance of a written court order, a three-day maximum length of detention, and a plan for release.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
