<bill session="115" type="h" number="2138" updated="2017-09-11T02:45:57Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sinai Service Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sinai Service Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that members of the Armed Forces performing services in the Sinai Peninsula of Egypt shall be entitled to tax benefits in the same manner as if such services were performed in a combat zone.</title>
    <title type="display">Sinai Service Recognition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000015" joined="2017-08-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="704"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Sinai Service Recognition Act

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to require a qualified hazardous duty area to be treated in the same manner as a combat zone for certain tax provisions.

A "qualified hazardous duty area" is the Sinai Peninsula of Egypt if a member of the Armed Forces performs services in such location that qualify for special pay for duty subject to hostile fire or imminent danger.

The requirement applies to specified tax provisions relating to:

 the special rule where a deceased spouse was in missing status; the exclusion from gross income of certain combat pay of members of the Armed Forces; income taxes of members of the Armed Forces on death; combat zone-related deaths of members of the Armed Forces; the definition of wages relating to combat pay for members of the Armed Forces; the taxation of phone service originating from a combat zone from members of the Armed Forces; joint tax returns where an individual is in missing status; and additional time for individuals serving in combat zones to file returns, pay taxes, and perform other specified acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
