<bill session="115" type="h" number="1574" updated="2017-06-19T21:30:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Dissenting Viewpoints and Voices Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Dissenting Viewpoints and Voices Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to clarify that the Federal Communications Commission may not take action against a broadcast licensee or any other person on the basis of viewpoint, to clarify that the President may not direct an agency to take such an action, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Dissenting Viewpoints and Voices Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Dissenting Viewpoints and Voices Act of 2017

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) from using the viewpoints that a person broadcasts or otherwise disseminates on issues of public importance as a basis for: (1) revoking the person's licenses or authorizations; (2) taking action against the person; or (3) placing conditions on the FCC's approval of the assignment or transfer of a station license or construction permit or the construction, extension, acquisition, operation, or discontinuation of a communications line.

The bill also prohibits the President from directing an agency to take actions against a person, or to condition agency approvals, based on a person's broadcasted or disseminated viewpoints.

Nothing in this bill affects the authority of the FCC or the President to take action against violations concerning the broadcast of: (1) obscene or indecent language, fraudulent schemes, or lottery information; or (2) content constituting incitement under the First Amendment.

The FCC may continue to enforce broadcast requirements that: (1) permit candidates to federal elective office to purchase reasonable broadcast time, (2) allow equal broadcast opportunities for all candidates for public office, and (3) require disclosures of paid broadcasts.

The President may continue to direct agencies to take actions to execute the President's legal duties.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
