<bill session="115" type="h" number="2758" updated="2017-09-21T16:00:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SOS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Survey Our Servicemembers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Survey Our Servicemembers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct annual surveys of veterans on experiences with medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SOS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1507"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Survey Our Servicemembers Act or the SOS Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to contract with an experienced non-government entity to conduct an annual survey, over a five-year period, to determine the experiences of veterans in obtaining hospital care and medical services at each VA medical facility.

Those surveys shall include questions relating to: the factors considered by the veteran in choosing whether to receive hospital care or medical services at a VA facility or at a non-VA facility, the quality of hospital care or medical services received at non-VA facilities, and the differences in cost to the veteran of receiving care or services at VA or at non-VA facilities. The VA shall make the survey results publicly available on its website.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
