<bill session="115" type="s" number="697" updated="2017-08-02T11:45:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tax Relief for Guard and Reserve Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tax Relief for Guard and Reserve Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to lower the mileage threshold for deduction in determining adjusted gross income of certain expenses of members of reserve components of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Tax Relief for Guard and Reserve Training Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2017-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2017-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2017-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1933-1934" label="Sponsor introductory remarks"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1934" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1687"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tax Relief for Guard and Reserve Training Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax deductions for expenses in connection with the performance of services as a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces, to: (1) reduce from 100 miles to 50 miles (without regard to whether such period includes an overnight stay) the distance from home requirement for the above-the-line deduction; and (2) exempt from the 2% floor on miscellaneous itemized deductions the deductions allowed that consist of expenses paid or incurred in connection with the performance of such services for any period (without regard to whether such period includes an overnight stay) during which the individual is more than 50 miles away from home in connection with the services.

(Above-the-line deductions are subtracted from gross income to arrive at adjusted gross income. Under current law, miscellaneous itemized deductions are only allowed if the aggregate of the deductions exceeds 2% of the taxpayer's adjusted gross income.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
