<bill session="115" type="h" number="3822" updated="2017-10-12T07:17:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CBO Show Your Work Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CBO Show Your Work Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Congressional Budget Office to make publicly available the fiscal and mathematical models, data, and other details of computations used in cost analysis and scoring.</title>
    <title type="display">CBO Show Your Work Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2017-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2017-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2017-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000563" joined="2017-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2017-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2017-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001195" joined="2017-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2017-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2017-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2017-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000819" joined="2017-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="1746"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">CBO Show Your Work Act 

This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to make available to Congress and the public each fiscal model, policy model, and data preparation routine that the CBO uses to estimate the costs and other fiscal, social, or economic effects of legislation.

For each estimate of the costs and other fiscal effects of legislation, the CBO must also disclose, in a manner sufficient to permit replication by individuals not employed by the CBO, the data, programs, models, assumptions, and other details of the computations used to prepare the estimate.

For data that is not required to be disclosed, the CBO must make available to Congress and the public:

 a complete list of all data variables for the data; descriptive statistics for all data variables for the data, to the extent that the descriptive statistics do not violate the rule against disclosure; a reference to the statute requiring that the data not be disclosed; and contact information for the individual or entity who has unrestricted access to the data.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
