<bill session="115" type="s" number="943" updated="2017-10-05T04:34:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct an accurate comprehensive student count for the purposes of calculating formula allocations for programs under the Johnson-O'Malley Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2017-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-10-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act

This bill requires the Department of the Interior to provide an updated and ongoing count of eligible Indian students for the Johnson-O'Malley Program (JOM Program) to ensure full participation of all qualified students. (The JOM Program awards contracts to support the cultural and academic needs of Native American students.)

Interior shall consult with Native American tribes and state and local education agencies that have not participated in the JOM Program to expand the number of eligible Native American students served.

Interior shall determine whether the JOM Program funding formula and eligibility requirements should be updated to ensure the maximum number of eligible Native American students.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
