<bill session="115" type="h" number="3195" updated="2017-09-14T07:15:37Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Honor Guardsmen and Reservists Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Honor Guardsmen and Reservists Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make available for purchase memorial headstones and markers for certain deceased members of the reserve components.</title>
    <title type="display">Honor Guardsmen and Reservists Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2017-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Honor Guardsmen and Reservists Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to make available for purchase a memorial headstone or marker for the marked or unmarked grave of: (1) an individual who performed inactive duty training or active duty for training for at least six years as a member of a National Guard or reserve component, but did not serve on active duty and is not otherwise ineligible for a memorial headstone or marker on account of the nature of the individual's separation from the Armed Forces or other cause; or (2) such an individual whose remains are unavailable.

Such a headstone or marker may be purchased under this subsection by: (1) the individual; (2) the surviving spouse, child, sibling, or parent of the individual; or (3) an individual other than the next of kin, as determined by the VA.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
