<bill session="115" type="h" number="3175" updated="2017-10-04T16:45:09Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Online Privacy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Online Privacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish privacy protections for customers of broadband Internet access service and other telecommunications services.</title>
    <title type="display">Online Privacy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2017-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2017-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2017-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2017-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2017-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2017-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2017-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="878"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Online Privacy Act 

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to promulgate customer privacy regulations that require telecommunications services, broadband Internet access services, and interconnected VoIP (internet phone) services&#160;to:

 notify a customer about the collection, use, and sharing of customer proprietary information that is individually identifiable customer proprietary network information, personally identifiable information, or the content of communications; obtain opt-in approval from a customer to use and share sensitive customer proprietary information about financial or health information, children, Social Security numbers, precise geolocation, content of communications, call detail information, web browsing or application usage history, or other customary proprietary information that the FCC determines to be sensitive; not refuse to serve a customer who does not consent to the use and sharing of customer proprietary information for commercial purposes under a "take-it-or-leave-it" offer; develop data security practices; and notify customers of security breaches. The FCC must also implement strong protection for de-identified customary proprietary information to prevent re-identifying such information.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
