<bill session="115" type="s" number="1144" updated="2017-10-03T04:30:39Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INVEST Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INVEST Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investment in New Ventures and Economic Success Today Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investment in New Ventures and Economic Success Today Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986  to encourage business creation by allowing faster recovery of start-up and organizational expenses, to simplify accounting methods for small businesses, to expand expensing and provide accelerated cost recovery to encourage investment in new plants and equipment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">INVEST Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2017-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2017-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3011-3012" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Investment in New Ventures and Economic Success Today Act of 2017 or the INVEST Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to modify various tax deductions, accounting methods, expensing rules, and cost recovery rules that apply to businesses.

The bill replaces several existing provisions relating to deductions for start-up and organizational business expenses with a consolidated deduction. The new provision applies to all business types, increases the dollar limitations for expenses that may be deducted, and reduces the amortization period for costs that exceed the expensing limit.

With respect to accounting methods, the bill modifies the requirements for using the cash accounting method, inventory accounting rules for small businesses, and accounting rules that apply to certain construction contracts.

The bill modifies the expensing and cost recovery rules to:

 increase the dollar limitation for the expensing of certain depreciable business assets, modify the rules that apply to the expensing of costs related to real property, make permanent the rule that allows businesses to elect to expense 50% of the cost of certain property and recover the remaining cost under the current depreciation rules, modify the depreciation rules for farm machinery and equipment, require the Department of the Treasury to update the schedule of class lives for depreciable property, modify the depreciation rules for luxury automobiles, modify the depreciation rules for computer or peripheral equipment used for personal purposes, and reduce the amortization period for intangible property acquired by a business.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
