<bill session="115" type="h" number="1520" updated="2017-06-19T21:30:29Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uniting Families Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uniting Families Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for the admission of certain sons and daughters of citizens of the United States, which citizens served on active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States abroad, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Uniting Families Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2017-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Uniting Families Act of 2017

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish a non-immigrant W-visa category for an alien who: (1) is 18 or older and is the genetic son or daughter of a U.S. citizen who served in the Armed Forces on active duty abroad, or (2) is the spouse or child of such alien and is accompanying, or following to join, such alien.

A visa shall not be issued until a petition has been filed in the United States by the applicant's citizen parent and approved by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). Such petition shall include:

 DNA evidence establishing that the alien is the petitioner's genetic child, a written agreement that the parent will provide financial support until the alien's status is adjusted to lawful permanent resident status, and information establishing that the petitioner is a U.S. citizen who served in the Armed Forces on active duty abroad. The bill provides that: (1) the period of authorized admission for a W-visa alien is five years, which may be extended for one additional two-year period; and (2) the total number of principal W-visa aliens who may be admitted during any fiscal is 5,000.

The bill prescribes the criteria that a W-visa alien must meet in order to adjust to lawful permanent resident status, including an understanding of the English language and U.S. history. (Such language and history requirements for naturalization purposes shall not apply to a person who has satisfied them in adjusting from W-visa status to lawful permanent resident status.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
