<bill session="115" type="s" number="403" updated="2017-07-20T16:56:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Savings Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Savings Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve access to health care through expanded health savings accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Health Savings Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1280"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1476"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="365"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="43"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1175"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Health Savings Act of 2017

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to health savings accounts (HSAs), to:

 rename high deductible health plans as HSA-qualified health plans; allow spouses who have both attained age 55 to make catch-up contributions to the same HSA; make Medicare Part A (hospital insurance benefits) beneficiaries eligible to participate in an HSA; allow individuals eligible for hospital care or medical services under a program of the Indian Health Service or a tribal organization to participate in an HSA; allow members of a health care sharing ministry to participate in an HSA; allow individuals who receive primary care services in exchange for a fixed periodic fee or payment, or who receive health care benefits from an onsite medical clinic of an employer, to participate in an HSA; include amounts paid for prescription and over-the-counter medicines or drugs as "qualified medical expenses" for which distributions from an HSA or other tax-preferred savings accounts may be used; increase the limits on HSA contributions to match the sum of the annual deductible and out-of-pocket expenses permitted under a high deductible health plan; and allow HSA distributions to be used to purchase health insurance coverage. The bill also: (1) amends the federal bankruptcy code to exempt HSAs from creditor claims in bankruptcy, and (2) amends the Social Security Act to reauthorize Medicaid health opportunity accounts.

The bill allows a medical care tax deduction for: (1) exercise equipment, physical fitness programs, and membership at a fitness facility; (2) nutritional and dietary supplements; and (3) periodic fees paid to a primary care physician and amounts paid for pre-paid primary care services.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
