<bill session="115" type="s" number="791" updated="2017-09-11T02:58:34Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Innovation Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Innovation Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to expand intellectual property education and training for small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Innovation Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2017-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2655"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Innovation Protection Act of 2017

This bill directs the Small Business Administration to develop partnership agreements that provide for:

 development of high-quality training for small businesses related to domestic and international protection of intellectual property, leveraging of training materials already developed for the education of inventors and small businesses, and participation of a nongovernmental organization. These agreements must also provide training:

 through electronic resources, including Internet-based webinars, and at physical locations, including a small business development center (SBDC); and the headquarters or a regional office of the United States Patent and Trade Office. The bill amends the Small Business Act to require services at an SBDC to include training in person or through a website relating to:

 domestic and international intellectual property protections, and how those protections should be considered in the business plans and growth strategies of small businesses.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
