<bill session="115" type="s" number="1064" updated="2017-10-06T05:51:49Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Lunch Shaming Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Lunch Shaming Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to prohibit the stigmatization of children who are unable to pay for meals.</title>
    <title type="display">Anti-Lunch Shaming Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2017-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2017-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2017-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2017-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2017-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2401"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Anti-Lunch Shaming Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to establish requirements for the treatment of a child who is a student at a school participating in the National School Lunch Program or the School Breakfast Program and is unable to pay for a meal at the school.

The bill applies to a child who either does not have funds to pay for a meal or has outstanding credit that was extended by a school food authority (SFA).

A SFA may not permit public identification or stigmatization of the child, such as by requiring a wristband or hand stamp. The child also may not be required to: (1) perform chores or activities that are not required of students generally, or (2) dispose of food after it has been served to the child.

Any communication related to outstanding credit must be directed to the child's parent or guardian. A child may be required to deliver a letter regarding outstanding credit that is addressed to a parent or guardian if the letter is not distributed to the child in a manner that stigmatizes the child.

The bill also expresses the sense of Congress regarding several issues regarding the administration of the school meal programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
