<bill session="115" type="s" number="742" updated="2017-09-11T02:57:59Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Broadband Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Broadband Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote competition, to preserve the ability of local governments to provide broadband capability and services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Community Broadband Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2017-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community Broadband Act of 2017

This bill bars state, local, or tribal&#160;governments from prohibiting or inhibiting such government entities or their affiliates&#160;from serving as "public providers" of telecommunications services or advanced telecommunications capabilities to any person or any public or private entity.

The bill prohibits such&#160;government and government-affiliated providers of public telecommunications services from favoring themselves over competing providers in the application of regulations, ordinances, public rights-of-way, or permitting requirements.

The bill expresses the sense of Congress that such&#160;governments or affiliates intending to provide public telecommunications services should consider public-private partnerships.

Public providers must provide public notice and opportunities for public input and private-sector bidding before providing telecommunications service to the public.

The bill provides an exemption from the prohibition on such governments favoring themselves in the application of regulations, and from the requirement to provide public notice and private bidding opportunities, during an emergency declared by the President, a governor, or an authorized elected local official.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
