<bill session="115" type="h" number="697" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:25Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-31T14:42:37-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-01-31T14:42:37-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Clearance Management and Administration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Clearance Management and Administration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Clearance Management and Administration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Clearance Management and Administration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to improve the management and administration of the security clearance processes throughout the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Clearance Management and Administration Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000193"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T14:35:11-05:00">
      <text>Mr. King (NY) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T14:35:20-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H776-778" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T14:35:22-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 697.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-01-31T14:42:37-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H776-777" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T14:42:38-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-31T19:42:37Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Department of Homeland Security Clearance Management and Administration Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require that the designation of the sensitivity level of national security positions be conducted in a consistent manner in all Department of Homeland Security (DHS) components and offices, consistent with federal guidelines. DHS must use uniform designation tools throughout DHS and provide training to appropriate staff.

The bill requires DHS: (1) by July 6, 2017, and every five years thereafter, to review all sensitivity level designations of national security positions at DHS; (2) if it determines that a change in the sensitivity level is warranted, to administratively adjust access and complete an appropriate level periodic reinvestigation; and (3) to report on such positions requiring access to classified information, no longer requiring access, or requiring a different level of access.

DHS's Inspector General must conduct regular audits of DHS compliance with regulations regarding such designations.

DHS must submit an annual report, through FY2022, on the denials, suspensions, revocations, and appeals of an individual's eligibility for access to classified information in DHS.

DHS must: (1) develop a plan to achieve greater uniformity regarding the adjudication of eligibility of an individual for access to classified information that is consistent with the Adjudicative Guidelines for Determining Access to Classified Information, and (2) ensure that all information received for such adjudication is consistent with such Guidelines and is protected against misappropriation. The plan shall consider the establishment of an internal appeals panel responsible for final national security clearance denial and revocation determinations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
