<bill session="115" type="s" number="316" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:40Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting States' Rights to Promote American Energy Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting States&#8217; Rights to Promote American Energy Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Mineral Leasing Act to recognize the authority of States to regulate oil and gas operations and promote American energy security, development, and job creation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting States' Rights to Promote American Energy Security Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2017-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting States' Rights to Promote American Energy Security Act

This bill amends the Mineral Leasing Act to prohibit the Department of the Interior from enforcing any federal regulation, guidance, or permit requirement regarding hydraulic fracturing (including any component of that process), relating to oil, gas, or geothermal production activities on or under any land in any state that has regulations, guidance, or permit requirements for that activity.

Interior must recognize and defer to state regulations, permitting, and guidance, for all activities regarding hydraulic fracturing relating to oil, gas, or geothermal production activities on federal land regardless of whether those rules are duplicative, more or less restrictive, have different requirements, or do not meet federal regulations, guidance, or permit requirements.

The bill defines "hydraulic fracturing" as the process by which fracturing fluids (including a fracturing fluid system) are pumped into an underground geologic formation to generate fractures or cracks, thereby increasing rock permeability near the wellbore and improving production of natural gas or oil.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
