<bill session="115" type="h" number="1388" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:05Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLEAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLEAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Legislating and Ethical Accountability Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Legislating and Ethical Accountability Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enact House Resolution 895, One Hundred Tenth Congress, (establishing the Office of Congressional Ethics) into permanent law.</title>
    <title type="display">CLEAN Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Clean Legislating and Ethical Accountability Now Act or the CLEAN Act

This bill enacts H.Res. 895, 110th Congress (establishing the Office of Congressional Ethics [OCE]) into permanent law, except that:

 the OCE shall be treated as a standing House committee for purposes of procuring the temporary or intermittent services of individual consultants or organizations to study or advise the OCE on matters within its jurisdiction or on its administration of affairs, references to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct shall be construed to be references to the House Committee on Ethics, the prohibition on members of the OCE board serving more than four consecutive Congresses shall not apply, individuals appointed for the remainder of a Congress may be reappointed for a second additional term of two Congresses, individuals who are subjects of a preliminary review or second-phase review by the board shall be informed of the right to be represented by counsel, and invoking that right should not be held negatively against them, the OCE may not take actions that would deny persons rights or protection provided under the Constitution; and the OCE shall have the same subpoena power as a House standing committee.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
