<bill session="115" type="h" number="1028" updated="2017-06-19T21:00:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commute Less Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commute Less Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 23 and 49, United States Code, with respect to congestion mitigation and metropolitan transportation planning, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Commute Less Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001165"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Commute Less Act of 2017

 (Sec. 2) This bill requires metropolitan planning organization (MPO) transportation plans to include, among other things, employer and transportation management organization outreach activities and strategies to help create and expand employer-based commuter programs.

An "employer-based commuter program" means a program implemented by employers to provide their employees with alternatives to driving to and from work in a vehicle occupied by a single individual.

The bill revises requirements regarding the interested parties that may comment on MPO transportation plans to include representatives of employers, employer-based commuter programs, and transportation management organizations.

The bill requires each MPO to establish an employer advisory council consisting of representatives of employers in the transportation management area. Each council shall develop and maintain a commuter trip reduction plan that identifies area goals for the reduction of vehicle miles traveled during peak commuting hours.

 MPO transportation improvement programs shall include, among other things, a list of projects identified in a commuter trip reduction plan that help achieve such reduction goals.

The Department of Transportation (DOT) is authorized to make a grant to a national nonprofit organization or other entity engaged in efforts relating to employer-based commuter programs to establish and operate an information clearinghouse for employer investment in transportation and employer-based commuter programs.

(Sec. 3) Recipients of federal assistance for the construction of federal-aid highway projects costing $75 million or more, or that will reduce traffic flow for more than 120 days, shall prepare congestion mitigation plans that include funding for projects to reduce vehicle miles traveled during peak commuting hours along impacted corridors.

 (Sec. 4) DOT shall:

 develop and implement a plan to expand and promote employer-based commuter programs; and report to Congress recommendations on how to better integrate such programs into disaster emergency planning, preparedness, and response activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
