<bill session="115" type="h" number="779" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:09Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Conflicts of Concern Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Conflicts of Concern Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To restrict United States nationals from traveling to countries in which foreign governments or anti-government forces allow foreign terrorist organizations to engage in armed conflict for purposes of participating in such armed conflict or from providing material support to entities that are engaged in such armed conflict, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">International Conflicts of Concern Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000804"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-31T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">International Conflicts of Concern Act

This bill directs the President to identify to Congress each country whose government is, and each country in which anti-government forces are, allowing one or more foreign terrorist organizations to engage in armed conflict occurring in that country.

The President shall designate a country as a "country of conflict concern" if: (1) its government or anti-government forces in the country are allowing one or more foreign terrorist organizations to engage in armed conflict in it, and (2) it is in the U.S. national security to restrict travel by any U.S. national to the country and restrict material support by U.S. nationals of entities engaged in armed conflict in it. Such a designation shall be terminated when the President certifies to Congress that either or both of these circumstances no longer apply.

The bill deems Syria to be a country of conflict concern.

The Presidentshall require a U.S. national to obtain a license to: (1) travel to a country of conflict concern, or (2) provide material support to entities engaged in armed conflict in such a country. Specified penalties shall apply to a person who violates such requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
