<bill session="115" type="s" number="215" updated="2017-08-10T13:24:00Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to issue an order continuing a stay of a hydroelectric license for the Mahoney Lake hydroelectric project in the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to authorize the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to issue an order continuing a stay of a hydroelectric license for the Mahoney Lake hydroelectric project in the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2017-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-24">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 115-77.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="96">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 96.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-24T12:33:12Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

(Sec.1)This bill requires the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), upon request, to issue a stay of the statutory deadline by which construction must commence on the Mahoney Lake Hydroelectric Project located in Ketchikan Gateway Borough, Alaska. (The City of Saxman, Alaska, was granted a construction license for the Mahoney Lake Hydroelectric Project on January 22, 1998.)

Additionally, upon request, FERC must reinstate the construction license and make it effective as of the date the stay is lifted.

FERC may reinstate the construction license if it is expired.

Subject to certain conditions, FERC may extend for up to six years the statutory deadline by which construction must commence on the project.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-77</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
