<bill session="115" type="s" number="1548" updated="2017-09-11T03:01:44Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oregon Wildlands Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oregon Wildlands Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain land administered by the Bureau of Land Management and the Forest Service in the State of Oregon as wilderness and national recreation areas and to make additional wild and scenic river designations in the State of Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Oregon Wildlands Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2017-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Oregon Wildlands Act

This bill designates specified Bureau of Land Management land in Oregon as the Rogue Canyon and Molalla National Recreation Areas in Oregon.

The Wild and Scenic Rivers Act is amended to add specified segments to the Rogue River as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.

Segment lengths and other technical corrections are made to segment designations for the Chetco River, Oregon.

The Squaw Creek is renamed as Whychus Creek.

The bill designates specified segments of: (1) Franklin and Wasson Creeks as wild rivers and components of the Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and (2) the Molalla River as a recreational river and components of such system.

Specified segments are added to the Elk River, and specified other river segments are designated as components of such system.

Approximately 56,100 acres of specified federal land are added to the Wild Rogue Wilderness, as well as approximately 600 acres of certain potential wilderness administered by the Department of the Interior.

Interior shall manage approximately 4,000 acres of Withdrawal Area to preserve the natural and primitive character of the land for recreational, scenic, and scientific use.

Approximately 30,540 acres of certain Forest Service and BLM land in Oregon are designated as the Devil's Staircase Wilderness and a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
