<bill session="115" type="h" number="2842" updated="2017-09-23T08:26:08Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-23T11:02:26-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-06-23T11:02:26-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conduct of demonstration projects to test the effectiveness of subsidized employment for TANF recipients.</title>
    <title type="display">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001107"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2017-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 115-185.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-20" calendar="Union" number="126">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 126.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21T16:47:39-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 396 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2842 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without instructions allowed. The resolution makes in order as original text for the purpose of amendment an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 115-22. The resolution makes in order only those further amendments printed in the Rules Committee report. Also, the resolution makes in order at any time on the legislative day of June 22, 2017, for the Speaker to entertain motion that the House suspend the rules relating to the bill H.R. 2353.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22T13:43:51-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 396 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T09:10:28-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 396.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5114-5125" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T09:10:33-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2842 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without instructions allowed. The resolution makes in order as original text for the purpose of amendment an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 115-22. The resolution makes in order only those further amendments printed in the Rules Committee report. Also, the resolution makes in order at any time on the legislative day of June 22, 2017, for the Speaker to entertain motion that the House suspend the rules relating to the bill H.R. 2353.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T09:11:01-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 396 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T09:11:02-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jeff Denham to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T09:11:13-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2842.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T09:40:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 396, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foxx amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T09:44:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 396, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bost amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T09:48:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 396, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bonamici amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T09:54:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 396, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Krishnamoorthi amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T09:57:05-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Krishnamoorthi amendment No. 4, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (NE) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T09:58:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 396, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Davidson amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T10:04:14-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Davidson amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Davis (IL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T10:04:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 396, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Khanna amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T10:08:47-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 396, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kilmer amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T10:43:22-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NE) moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T10:43:36-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T10:43:45-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2842 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T10:47:07-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5123-5125" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T10:48:02-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T10:54:34-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2842.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T10:55:10-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T10:55:19-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5117-5118" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="322" datetime="2017-06-23T11:02:26-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 377 - 34 (Roll no. 322).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23T11:02:28-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Human Resources" code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="396"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h148"/>
    <amendment number="h147"/>
    <amendment number="h146"/>
    <amendment number="h145"/>
    <amendment number="h144"/>
    <amendment number="h143"/>
    <amendment number="h142"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-06-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act

This bill amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require the Administration for Children &amp; Families (ACF) to make grants to states for demonstration projects that provide wage subsidies to enable low-income individuals to enter and retain employment.

States may use grant funds to subsidize an individual's wages for up to 12 months. The subsidy may be up to 50% of an individual's wages. Individuals are eligible for subsidized wages if they: (1) are recipients of TANF or similar state assistance or a noncustodial parent of a child receiving such assistance, (2) are unemployed when the subsidy begins, and (3) have an income below 200% of the poverty line.

States must ensure that participants in subsidized job programs do not displace current workers.

The ACF must reserve funding to carry out this bill from amounts in the Contingency Fund for State Welfare Programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-185</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
