<bill session="115" type="s" number="475" updated="2017-06-19T21:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CCM-CARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CCM&#8211;CARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Clinical Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Clinical Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase research, education, and treatment for cerebral cavernous malformations.</title>
    <title type="display">CCM-CARE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2017-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1255"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Clinical Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2017 or the CCM-CARE Act

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to strengthen and coordinate its efforts concerning cerebral cavernous malformation (CCM). (CCM is a condition in which blood vessels in the brain and spinal cord become enlarged, which can lead to seizures, paralysis, hearing or vision loss, or bleeding in the brain.) The NIH may award grants and enter into cooperative agreements for CCM research.

The NIH must: (1) award grants and contracts to plan and provide support for a network of CCM Clinical Research Centers; (2) identify and support additional centers to facilitate medical research to develop a cure for CCM and enhance medical care for CCM; and (3) convene a Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Research Consortium to develop programs for clinicians, scientists, and patients.

The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention may award grants and enter into cooperative agreements for the collection, analysis, and reporting of data on CCM.

The Department of Health and Human Services must award grants and enter into cooperative agreements for epidemiological activities related to CCM and must provide for a national CCM surveillance program.

The Food and Drug Administration must, in order to hasten clinical trials for CCM, coordinate with clinical centers, investigators, and advocates to support: (1) qualification of biomarkers, (2) qualification of patient reported outcome measures for quality of life, (3) investigational new drug applications, and (4) adaptive trial designs for rare disease research and expedited review of medications.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
