<bill session="115" type="h" number="2857" updated="2017-09-21T20:30:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-20T17:49:29-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-06-20T17:49:29-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Families in Substance Abuse Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Families in Substance Abuse Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Supporting Families in Substance Abuse Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Supporting Families in Substance Abuse Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support foster care maintenance payments for children with parents in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility for substance abuse.</title>
    <title type="display">Supporting Families in Substance Abuse Treatment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2017-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20T17:32:43-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Noem moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20T17:32:59-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4968-4970" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20T17:32:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2857.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-06-20T17:49:29-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4968-4969" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20T17:49:31-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Human Resources" code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-20T13:23:45Z" status="Passed House amended">Supporting Families in Substance Abuse Treatment Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to provide that the removal and foster care placement of a child shall meet the requirements for foster care maintenance payments on the child's behalf if the child has been placed with a parent residing in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility.

Placement with such a parent shall meet these requirements only if:

 the placement recommendation is specified in the child's case plan before the placement; the treatment facility offers, as part of substance abuse treatment, parenting skills training, parent education, and individual and family counseling; and this training and counseling are delivered under an organizational structure and treatment framework that involves understanding, recognizing, and responding to the effects of all types of trauma, and in accordance with recognized principles of a trauma-informed approach and trauma-specific interventions, to address the consequences of trauma and facilitate healing. The bill specifies the amount the state may receive for a child placed with a parent who is in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility for substance abuse.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
