<bill session="115" type="hj" number="100" updated="2017-08-14T19:30:18Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consolidated Authorization for Use of Military Force Resolution of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the use of United States Armed Forces against al Qaeda, the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL), and the Afghan Taliban.</title>
    <title type="display">Consolidated Authorization for Use of Military Force Resolution of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001150"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001050" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000051" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2017-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Consolidated Authorization for Use of Military Force Resolution of 2017

This joint resolution authorizes the President, for three years, to use all necessary and appropriate force to protect U.S. national security against Al Qaeda, the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL), the Afghan Taliban, and any associated organized and armed group that is a co-belligerent against the United States.

Congress declares that this authorization is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization under the War Powers Resolution and that nothing in this joint resolution supersedes any requirement of such resolution.

The President shall: (1) submit to Congress and publish in the Federal Register at least every 90 days a list of entities (including their locations) against which such authority has been exercised. If the President exercises such authority to deploy ground forces in a combat role, the President shall notify Congress at the earliest possible date after such deployment consistent with U.S. national security interests.

A joint resolution introduced on or after such notification that provides for modification or repeal of a deployment authority shall be considered to be in accordance with applicable procedures under the War Powers Resolution.

Specified prior authorizations for the use of military force are repealed.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
