<bill session="115" type="s" number="1696" updated="2017-09-16T04:33:07Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smart Energy and Water Efficiency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smart Energy and Water Efficiency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to provide for a smart energy and water efficiency management pilot program.</title>
    <title type="display">Smart Energy and Water Efficiency Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2479"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3275"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1460"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-08-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Smart Energy and Water Efficiency Act of 2017

This bill amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to require the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish and carry out a smart energy and water efficiency management pilot program to award grants to utilities, municipalities, water districts, Indian tribes or Alaska Native villages, and other water authorities for demonstrating advanced and innovative technology-based solutions that will:

 increase the energy efficiency of water, wastewater, and water reuse systems; improve those systems to help communities make significant progress in conserving water, saving energy, and reducing costs; support the implementation of innovative processes and the installation of advanced automated systems that provide real-time data on energy and water; and improve energy and water conservation, water quality, and predictive maintenance of energy and water systems, through the use of Internet-connected technologies. DOE must annually evaluate each grant project and make best practices identified in the evaluations available to the public.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
