<bill session="115" type="h" number="1184" updated="2017-06-19T21:15:29Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Telephone Connection Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Telephone Connection Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission to prescribe rules regulating inmate telephone and video service rates, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Family Telephone Connection Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000515"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2017-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Family Telephone Connection Protection Act of 2017

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission to adopt or continue in force regulations on the use of inmate telephone and video services that enable persons incarcerated in correctional institutions to originate calls at payphones, telephones, or video kiosks designated for the personal use of inmates.

The regulations must: (1) prescribe variable maximum per-minute compensation rates depending on factors such as carrier costs and the size of the correctional facility, (2) prohibit per-call or per-connection charges, (3) require providers of inmate telephone and video service to offer both collect calling and prepaid debit account services, (4) prohibit or limit the payment of commissions by such providers to administrators of correctional facilities based upon the revenue of the service, (5) require such administrators to allow more than one service provider at a facility so that inmates have a choice, and (6) prohibit or substantially limit any ancillary fees that are in addition to the per-minute rate and connection charge.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
