<bill session="115" type="s" number="758" updated="2017-09-11T02:58:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Janey Ensminger Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Janey Ensminger Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry's review and publication of illness and conditions relating to veterans stationed at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina, and their family members, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Janey Ensminger Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2017-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2017-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Janey Ensminger Act of 2017

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry, at least every three years, to:

 review the scientific literature relevant to the relationship between the employment or residence of individuals at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina, for at least 30 days during the period of August 1, 1953, to December 21, 1987, and specific illnesses or conditions incurred by those individuals and determine whether and to what extent the evidence shows that toxic substance exposure is a cause of an illness or condition; and publish and update a list of each illness and the categorization of evidence for which a determination of cause has been made. A veteran who served on active duty at Camp Lejeune for at least 30 days during such period is eligible for hospital care and medical services for any of the illnesses or conditions for which the evidentiary connection between toxic exposure and the illness or condition is categorized in such list as sufficient or modest. Such a veteran who has been furnished hospital care or medical services shall remain eligible for such care or services for such illness or condition even if the evidentiary connection is not categorized as sufficient or modest. A family member of such veteran who has been furnished hospital care or medical services shall remain eligible for hospital care or medical services for such illness or condition.

The Department of Veterans Affairs shall transfer for each of FY2017 and FY2018 specified finds to enhance the claims processing system, eligibility system, and web portal for the Camp Lejeune Family Member Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
