<bill session="115" type="h" number="1526" updated="2017-10-03T21:00:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to provide guidance and limitations regarding the integration of unmanned aircraft systems into United States airspace, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2017-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-13">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Digital Commerce and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Aviation" code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="631"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Drone Aircraft Privacy and Transparency Act of 2017

This bill amends the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to direct the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish procedures to ensure that the integration of unmanned aircraft (drone) systems into the national airspace system is done in compliance with privacy principles. Such procedures shall not apply to a drone system operated for news-gathering activities protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution.

DOT may not approve, issue, or award any certificate, license, or other grant of authority to operate a drone system in the national airspace system unless the pertinent application includes a data collection statement that provides reasonable assurance that the applicant will operate the drone in accordance with privacy principles. The same requirement shall apply to any drone system to be operated by a law enforcement agency, except that the application shall include a data minimization statement, instead of a data collection statement, that provides the same assurance.

The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) shall make any approved grant of authority, each such statement, and information about the drone's owner, operator, and technical capability available in a searchable format on the public FAA website.

A governmental entity may not use a drone system, or request information collected by another entity through a drone system, for protective activities or for law enforcement or intelligence purposes except pursuant to a warrant or as permitted under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978, except when: (1) a law enforcement entity reasonably believes there is an imminent danger of death or serious physical injury, or (2) the Department of Homeland Security determines that credible intelligence indicates there is a high risk of an imminent terrorist attack by a specific individual or organization.

It shall be unlawful to operate a drone system in a manner that is not in accordance with the terms of a data collection statement or that violates the rule implementing the procedures required by this bill. Any such violation shall be treated as an unfair or deceptive act or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act. This bill provides for enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission, by a civil action brought by a state, or by a private action.

The FAA shall revoke the certificate, license, or other grant of authority of a drone system operated in a violation of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
