<bill session="115" type="s" number="503" updated="2017-10-06T05:52:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Animal Welfare Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Animal Welfare Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to make publicly available certain regulatory records relating to the administration of the Animal Welfare Act and the Horse Protection Act, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the use of an alternative depreciation system for taxpayers violating rules under the Animal Welfare Act and the Horse Protection Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Animal Welfare Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1580" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1580-1581" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1368"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Animal Welfare Accountability and Transparency Act 

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to maintain and publicly disclose records relating to the administration of the Animal Welfare Act and the Horse Protection Act, including specified details regarding inspections, enforcement actions, regulations, registrations, and licenses under the two laws. Within 90 days of the enactment of this bill, USDA must make the records available to the public in an online searchable database in a machine-readable format on its website.

The bill also amends the Internal Revenue Code to require a taxpayer who has been convicted or assessed civil penalties for violating certain provisions of the Animal Welfare Act or the Horse Protection Act to use the alternative depreciation system that increases the number of years over which property is depreciated. The taxpayer must use the system for any property placed in service during the five-year period beginning with the year in which the period for seeking judicial review of a civil penalty has lapsed or in which there has been a final judgment entered with respect to the violation, whichever is earlier.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
