<bill session="115" type="h" number="238" updated="2017-08-17T17:56:18Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-12T17:41:21-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-01-12T17:41:21-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commodity End-User Relief Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commodity End-User Relief Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Commodity End-User Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, to better protect futures customers, to provide end-users with market certainty, to make basic reforms to ensure transparency and accountability at the Commission, to help farmers, ranchers, and end-users manage risks, to help keep consumer costs low, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Commodity End-User Relief Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001189" joined="2017-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2017-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2017-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10T18:02:35-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 40 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 78 and H.R. 238. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on both H.R. 78 and H.R. 238. The resolution provides for suspension authority at any time on the legislative day of January 13, 2017. The resolution also provides for legislative proceedings during the period of January 16, 2017 through January 20, 2017.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-11T13:40:11-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 40 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T12:39:15-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 40.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H404-428" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T12:39:20-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 78 and H.R. 238. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on both H.R. 78 and H.R. 238. The resolution provides for suspension authority at any time on the legislative day of January 13, 2017. The resolution also provides for legislative proceedings during the period of January 16, 2017 through January 20, 2017.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T12:39:33-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 40 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T12:39:35-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John J. Duncan, Jr. to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T12:40:19-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 238.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T13:25:31-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 40, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Aderholt Part B amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T13:31:40-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 40, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Austin Scott (GA) Part B amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T13:37:27-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 40, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conaway Part B amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T13:39:12-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 40, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conaway Part B amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T13:50:20-05:00">
      <text>POSTSPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Conaway amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Courtney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T13:50:48-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 40, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duffy Part B amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T13:57:38-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 40, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LaMalfa Part B amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T14:00:27-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 40, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lucas Part B amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T14:07:26-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 40, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hartzler Part B amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T14:14:02-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Conaway moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T14:14:17-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T14:14:33-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 238 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:14:01-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H450-451" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:14:13-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:14:28-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments which were debated earlier an on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:19:10-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 238.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:19:52-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:20:06-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H414-421" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:21:14-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Langevin moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H449" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:21:29-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to insert language prohibiting the Commission from considering the swaps regulatory requirements of a foreign jurisdiction if that jurisdiction has been found by the Commission, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, to have engaged in cyber-attacks targeting any election held in the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:28:03-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:35:06-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 190 - 235 (Roll no. 53).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="54" datetime="2017-01-12T17:41:21-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 182 (Roll no. 54).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12T17:41:22-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="40"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h38"/>
    <amendment number="h37"/>
    <amendment number="h36"/>
    <amendment number="h35"/>
    <amendment number="h34"/>
    <amendment number="h33"/>
    <amendment number="h32"/>
    <amendment number="h31"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-01-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Commodity End User Relief Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2021, and revises provisions related to, operations of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC).

In addition, the bill amends the Commodity Exchange Act to direct registered futures associations to require their futures commission merchant members to meet certain procedural and reporting requirements.

 The CFTC is authorized to require that certain property of the bankruptcy estate of a commodity broker who is a debtor in Chapter 7 bankruptcy (also known as "liquidation" bankruptcy) be included in customer property to the extent that such property is insufficient to satisfy the net equity claims of the broker's public customers.

 Before promulgating a regulation or issuing an order, the CFTC must publish an assessment of the costs and benefits of the action.

The heads of the CFTC's administrative units shall serve at the pleasure of the CFTC.

The bill establishes, within the CFTC, the Office of the Chief Economist.

The duration of an omnibus order of investigation (authorizing the CFTC to issue subpoenas to multiple persons in relation to a particular subject matter area) shall not be indefinite.

The bill exempts specified entities from certain&#160;clearing requirements applicable to swaps.

 With respect to swap dealer registration requirements, the bill: (1)&#160;prohibits the CFTC from modifying,&#160;except by affirmative rule or regulation,&#160;the threshold for de minimus (minor in quantity) swap dealing; (2) under certain circumstances, allows the use of specified financial models with respect to calculating capital requirements; and (3) modifies other provisions.

The bill exempts certain swap activities involving non-U.S. persons&#160;from U.S. swaps requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
