<bill session="115" type="h" number="2699" updated="2017-09-28T18:30:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to more effectively provide mental health resources for members of the Armed Forces at high risk of suicide, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of Defense to more effectively provide mental health resources for members of the Armed Forces at high risk of suicide, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2017-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD) to develop a methodology to:

 identify units of the Armed Forces that have a disproportionately high rate of suicide and suicide attempts; provide additional mental health resources for members of the Armed Forces deployed with such units; identify the circumstances of deployments associated with increased vulnerability to suicide, including the length and area of deployment and the nature and extent of contact with enemy forces; and provide additional preventative mental health care to units deployed under similar circumstances. DOD shall: (1) develop a methodology to assess the rate of suicide and suicide attempts of members of the Armed Forces of units that have been deployed in support of a contingency operation after September 11, 2001, and (2) provide outreach regarding the available mental health resources for veterans enrolled in the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) health care system who were deployed with such units.

Information obtained pursuant to this bill may be used by DOD and VA officers, employees, and contractors only for the purposes of carrying it out.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
