<bill session="115" type="s" number="1296" updated="2017-09-14T04:49:24Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRIVATE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting the Rights of IndiViduals Against Technological Exploitation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting the Rights of IndiViduals Against Technological Exploitation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Uniform Code of Military Justice to prohibit the wrongful broadcast or distribution of intimate visual images.</title>
    <title type="display">PRIVATE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2017-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2810"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2052"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1519"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting the Rights of IndiViduals Against Technological Exploitation Act or the PRIVATE Act

This bill amends the Uniform Code of Military Justice to prohibit a person from knowingly and wrongfully broadcasting or distributing an intimate visual image of a private area of another individual who is at least 18 years old, who is identifiable from the image or from information displayed in connection with the image, and who does not explicitly consent, if the person knows or reasonably should have known that:

 the image was made under circumstances in which the individual depicted retained a reasonable expectation of privacy regarding any broadcast or distribution of such image; and the broadcast or distribution of the intimate visual image is likely to cause harm, harassment, intimidation, emotional distress, or financial loss for the individual depicted or to harm substantially the depicted individual's health, safety, business, calling, career, financial condition, reputation, or personal relationships. The perpetrator of such offense is guilty of wrongful distribution of intimate visual images and shall by punished as a court-martial may direct.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
