<bill session="115" type="s" number="426" updated="2017-09-16T04:33:25Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase educational assistance provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs for education and training of physician assistants of the Department, to establish pay grades and require competitive pay for physician assistants of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2017-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3262"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out a five-year Grow Our Own Directive (or G.O.O.D.) pilot program to provide educational assistance to certain former members of the Armed Forces for education and training as VA physician assistants in exchange for recipients agreeing to be employed as physician assistants for the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) for a specified period at a VA medical facility located in a community designated as a medically underserved population in a state with a per capita population of veterans of more than 9%.

The VA shall: (1) provide at least 35 new scholarships under the pilot program each year, and (2) ensure that at least 25 new scholarships are awarded each year under its health professional and employee incentive scholarship programs for the education and training of physician assistants.

The VA must: (1) establish specified standards to improve its use of educational assistance programs to educate and hire physician assistants, and (2) increase for each of the next five years the scholarship amounts provided under such programs.

The bill establishes pay grades and competitive pay requirements for physician assistants. The VA must implement a national strategic plan for the retention and recruitment of VA physician assistants that includes competitive pay in comparison to the pay of physician assistants in the private sector.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
