<bill session="115" type="h" number="1936" updated="2017-09-14T07:15:55Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Do Your Job Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Do Your Job Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit congressional recesses until Congress adopts a concurrent resolution on the budget that results in a balanced Federal budget by the last fiscal year covered by such resolution, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Do Your Job Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000579"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2017-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2733"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Do Your Job Act 

This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to create points of order against resolutions providing for: (1) the adjournment of the House for more than three days during August until the House has approved all of the annual appropriation bills, or (2) the adjournment of either the House or the Senate for more than three days between October 1 and the end of the session of Congress until all of the annual appropriation bills have been presented to the President.

The bill also prohibits a congressional recess or adjournment longer than 24 hours during a calendar year until Congress agrees to a budget resolution that projects a balanced budget by the last fiscal year covered by the resolution.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
