<bill session="115" type="sr" number="119" updated="2017-06-19T21:45:25Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Oversight to Start Taxpayer Savings Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Oversight to Start Taxpayer Savings Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COST Savings Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COST Savings Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution requiring authorizing committees to hold annual hearings on Government Accountability Office investigative reports on the identification, consolidation, and elimination of duplicative Government programs.</title>
    <title type="display">COST Savings Resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2430" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Congressional Oversight to Start Taxpayer Savings Resolution or the COST Savings Resolution

 Requires each standing committee of the Senate (except the Committee on Appropriations) with jurisdiction, after the Government Accountability Office (GAO) reports annually to Congress on federal programs, agencies, offices, and initiatives with duplicative goals and activities, to conduct hearings on the report's recommendations for consolidation and elimination of the program, agency, office, or initiative.

Requires each standing committee of the Senate (except the Committee on Appropriations) with jurisdiction over any agency or program area on a High Risk List published by the GAO to conduct hearings on the vulnerabilities to fraud, waste, abuse, and mismanagement, or need for transformation, of the agency or program area.

Authorizes committees to hold joint hearings for any program, agency, office, initiative, or program area over which more than one standing committee has jurisdiction.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
