<bill session="115" type="h" number="1725" updated="2017-09-22T12:43:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-23T15:54:40-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-05-23T15:54:40-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quicker Veterans Benefits Delivery Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quicker Veterans Benefits Delivery Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the treatment of medical evidence provided by non-Department of Veterans Affairs medical professionals in support of claims for disability compensation under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit certain reports relating to medical evidence submitted in support of claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary.</title>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit certain reports relating to medical evidence submitted in support of claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000799"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2017-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000612" joined="2017-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2017-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2017-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2017-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2017-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2017-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 115-133.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-19" calendar="Union" number="82">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 82.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23T15:49:03-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Roe (TN) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23T15:49:04-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4475-4476" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23T15:49:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1725.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-05-23T15:54:40-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4475" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23T15:54:42-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23T15:54:45-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="706"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-23T14:11:06Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on May 19, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

(Sec. 1) This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), within 180 days of enactment of this bill, to submit a report on the progress of the VA's Acceptable Clinical Evidence initiative in reducing the necessity for in-person disability examinations.

 Such report shall include: (1) the number of claims eligible for the initiative, disaggregated by fiscal year; (2) the total number of claims eligible for the initiative that required a VA medical examiner to supplement the evidence with information obtained during a telephone interview with the claimant; (3) information on other VA initiatives to encourage the use of private medical evidence; (4) the anticipated impact on the time line and accuracy of processing claims if the VA were prohibited from requesting a private medical examination that is adequate for a claims decision; and (5) recommendations on how the VA can measure, track, and prevent the ordering of unnecessary medical examinations when a private examination has been administered.

 (Sec. 2) The VA shall submit by March 1 of FY2018-FY2024 an annual report that includes for each VA regional office: (1) the number of times a veteran who submitted private medical evidence in support of a claim for compensation or pension was scheduled for an examination by VA personnel because the private medical evidence was determined to be unacceptable, (2) the most common reasons for such determinations, and (3) the types of disabilities for which claims were most commonly denied when private medical evidence was submitted.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-133</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
