<bill session="115" type="h" number="1829" updated="2017-08-31T19:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Retiree Employment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Retiree Employment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To temporarily authorize recently retired members of the armed forces to be appointed to certain civil service positions, require the Secretary of Defense to issue certain notifications, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Military Retiree Employment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000604" joined="2017-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Retiree Employment Act

This bill permits, for a specified five-year period, retired members of the Armed Forces to be appointed to civil service positions in or under the Department of Defense (DOD) during the first 180 days after retirement without meeting current requirements regarding: (1) appointment authorization, (2) basic pay increase, or (3) existence of a state of national emergency.

The Office of Personnel Management shall establish an oversight plan to monitor such appointments.

DOD shall ensure that every DOD employee is informed, within one calendar day, of the publication of a vacancy within that employee's office that requires qualifications related to the employee's current duties.

DOD shall ensure for 10 years that each employee who is a veteran and who is newly hired or appointed to a DOD position shall be informed of the effect of certain DOD guidelines for reduction in force protection.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
