<bill session="115" type="s" number="191" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:38Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Freedom Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Freedom Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve patient choice by allowing States to adopt market-based alternatives to the Affordable Care Act that increase access to affordable health insurance and reduce costs while ensuring important consumer protections and improving patient care.</title>
    <title type="display">Patient Freedom Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2017-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2017-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2017-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2017-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S400-402" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-23T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Patient Freedom Act of 2017

This bill provides states with three options regarding title I (provisions on health insurance reform, exchanges, and subsidies) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA): (1) continue implementing PPACA, with a limit on total premium and cost sharing subsidies provided in the state; (2) waive the requirements of title I of PPACA, with specified exceptions; or (3) the second option plus implementation of a Roth health savings account (HSA) deposit system. Only residents of states continuing to implement PPACA are eligible for PPACA premium subsidies.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to set forth provisions regarding Roth HSAs, which have annual contribution limits and are not subject to taxes. Contributions to Roth HSAs are not tax deductible.

In states implementing a Roth HSA deposit system, residents who are enrolled in health insurance coverage that meets state standards receive monthly deposits in their Roth HSAs. States that administer deposits are entitled to payments from the Department of Health and Human Services for population health initiatives.

States with a Roth HSA deposit system must penalize residents who have a break in health coverage and may enroll residents in a default high deductible health plan that is continually available for enrollment.

Contributions may no longer be made to non-Roth HSAs.

HSAs and Roth HSAs may be used to pay monthly or prepaid amounts for physician services. These services are not considered to be health insurance.

This bill amends SSAct title XVIII (Medicare) to require participating hospitals to limit costs to individuals for uncovered emergency medical care.

Persons providing medical care must post prices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
