<bill session="115" type="s" number="1290" updated="2017-09-13T12:03:33Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Welfare Reform and Upward Mobility Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Welfare Reform and Upward Mobility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to help individuals receiving assistance under means-tested welfare programs obtain self-sufficiency, to provide information on total spending on means-tested welfare programs, to provide an overall spending limit on means-tested welfare programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Welfare Reform and Upward Mobility Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2017-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2832"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2996"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Welfare Reform and Upward Mobility Act

This bill requires the President to include in the annual budget proposal the total level of means-tested welfare spending by the federal, state, and local governments for the most recent fiscal year for which such data is available, and estimated levels for the current and 10 ensuing fiscal years.

For each of FY2019-FY2029 each state that receives means-tested welfare spending by the federal government shall report annually to the Congressional Budget Office on the total amount of such spending by the state for the fiscal year.

The Congressional Budget Act of 1974 is amended to define means-tested welfare spending as spending for any federal program designed specifically to give assistance or benefits exclusively to low-income Americans.

The refundable portion of certain tax credits shall also be means-tested welfare spending, as well as the refundable portion of the premium and out-of-pocket health care subsidies to be paid under the Patient Protection and Affordable Health Care Act.

The bill revises work eligibility requirements under the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program.

Part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act is amended to create the work preparation program for TANF families.

The bill eliminates separate participation rate requirements for two-parent families.

No federal funds shall be made available to carry out any means-tested housing program, but states may receive grants to fund their own housing programs.

The bill prohibits funding for abortions and for health benefits that cover abortion, including certain tax credits, except where the pregnancy results from rape or incest or in certain other health cases.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
