<bill session="115" type="s" number="303" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:39Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to discontinue a Federal program that authorizes State and local law enforcement officers to investigate, apprehend, and detain aliens in accordance with a written agreement with the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and to clarify that immigration enforcement is solely a function of the Federal Government.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to discontinue a Federal program that authorizes State and local law enforcement officers to investigate, apprehend, and detain aliens in accordance with a written agreement with the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and to clarify that immigration enforcement is solely a function of the Federal Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2017-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1236"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide that the authority to inquire about or verify immigration or citizenship status and to investigate, apprehend, arrest, or detain an individual for a violation of such Act is restricted to immigration officers and authorized employees of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and subject to limits set forth in other provisions of law.

DHS authority to enter into written agreements with a state or state subdivision to perform immigration-related investigations, apprehensions, or detentions of aliens in the United States is eliminated. The bill exempts from the restriction under this bill DOJ authority to enter into other state and local agreements: (1) in the event of an actual or imminent mass influx of aliens representing urgent circumstances; and (2) with respect to immigration-related detentions in non-federal facilities, including personnel and facilities construction. The bill also exempts from such restriction state and local enforcement authority to arrest and detain certain previously-deported illegal aliens who have been convicted of a felony.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
