<bill session="115" type="h" number="49" updated="2017-07-17T12:45:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Energy Independence and Job Creation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Energy Independence and Job Creation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish and implement a competitive oil and gas leasing program that will result in an environmentally sound program for the exploration, development, and production of the oil and gas resources of the Coastal Plain of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Energy Independence and Job Creation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy" code="HSSY20" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Power" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">American Energy Independence and Job Creation Act

This bill directs the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to implement a competitive leasing program for the exploration, development, and production of the oil and gas resources on the Coastal Plain, Arctic National Wildlife Refuge (ANWR), Alaska.

The bill amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act of 1980 to repeal the prohibition against leasing or other development leading to production of oil and gas from ANWR.

The bill requires BLM to conduct its first lease sale within 22 months. This bill also prescribes terms and conditions governing Coastal Plain lease sales, including the establishment of environmental protection standards and the prohibition of exporting oil produced under the lease.

The bill establishes the ANWR Alternative Energy Trust Fund, into which shall be deposited 50% of the amount of revenues from federal oil and gas leasing and operations authorized under this bill.The fund must be used to provide grants and incentives for certain energy programs, including grants for clean coal power and renewable energy initiatives, and incentives for hydroelectric production.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
