<bill session="115" type="h" number="839" updated="2017-08-04T22:15:27Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Service Spending Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Service Spending Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent the enrichment of certain Government officers and employees or their families through Federal funds or contracting, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Public Service Spending Integrity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000599"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2017-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-02">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-02">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Service Spending Integrity Act

This bill prohibits any federal funds from being obligated or expended for purposes of procuring goods or services at any business owned or controlled by a covered individual or any family member of such an individual. A "covered individual" is defined to include the President, the Vice President, the head of any executive department, and any individual occupying a position designated by the President as a cabinet-level position.

The bill also prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds from a Members' Representational Allowance or a Senators' Official Personnel and Office Expense Account for purposes of procuring goods or services at any business owned or controlled by the Member of Congress or any family member.

 No federal agency may enter into a contract with a business owned or controlled by a covered individual or family member. A business shall be deemed to be owned or controlled by a covered individual or family member, or by a Member of Congress or family member, if any such person: (1) is a member of the board of directors or similar governing body of the business, or (2) directly or indirectly owns or controls 51% or more of the voting shares of the business.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
