<bill session="115" type="h" number="2397" updated="2017-09-11T03:03:01Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Distribution and Promotion of Rights and Knowledge Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Distribution and Promotion of Rights and Knowledge Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DPRK Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 to authorize further actions to promote freedom of information and democracy in North Korea, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">DPRK Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2017-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2017-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" code="HSFA05" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1118"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Distribution and Promotion of Rights and Knowledge Act of 2017 or the DPRK Act of 2017

This bill amends the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 to authorize the President, through the Department of State, to: (1) distribute or provide grants to distribute information receiving devices, electronically readable devices, and other informational sources into North Korea; and (2) establish a grant program, which may involve public-private partnerships, to develop and/or distribute new products or methods to allow North Koreans easier access to outside information.

The Broadcasting Board of Governors may broadcast American, Korean, Chinese, and other popular music, television, movies, and popular cultural references as part of its programming.

The Board shall broadcast to North Korea in the Korean language information on rights, laws, and freedoms afforded through the North Korean Constitution, the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, the United Nations Commission of Inquiry on Human Rights in the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, and any other applicable treaties or international agreements to which North Korea is bound.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
