<bill session="115" type="h" number="284" updated="2017-09-13T07:15:35Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Medical Resident Training in Community Hospitals Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Medical Resident Training in Community Hospitals Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish rules for payment for graduate medical education (GME) costs for hospitals that establish a new medical residency training program after hosting resident rotators for short durations.</title>
    <title type="display">Advancing Medical Resident Training in Community Hospitals Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2017-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1291"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing Medical Resident Training in Community Hospitals Act of 2017

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to&#160;revise payment rules for graduate medical education (GME) costs with respect to a hospital that establishes a new medical residency training program.

With respect to a hospital that has not entered into a GME affiliation agreement, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) shall establish the hospital's full-time equivalent (FTE) resident amount only after determining that the hospital's medical residency training program trains more than 1.0 FTE resident in a cost reporting period. In the case of a hospital with an approved FTE resident amount based on the training of no more than 1.0 FTE resident in a cost reporting period before October 1, 1997, or 3.0 FTE residents in a cost reporting period after that date, CMS shall provide the hospital an opportunity to have its FTE resident amount reestablished when the hospital begins&#160;training FTE residents&#160;in excess of&#160;the&#160;applicable threshold.

Current law limits the number, subject to&#160;the application of&#160;certain adjustments,&#160;of FTE residents a hospital may have in allopathic and osteopathic medicine for purposes of Medicare payment. The bill specifies that CMS shall determine a hospital's&#160;limitation&#160;adjustment only after determining that the hospital's medical residency training program trains&#160;more than 1.0 FTE residents in a cost reporting period. In the case of a hospital with a limitation adjustment based on the training of no more than 1.0 FTE resident in a cost reporting period before October 1, 1997, or 3.0 FTE residents in a cost reporting period after that date, CMS shall provide the hospital an opportunity to have its&#160;adjustment re-determined&#160;when the hospital begins&#160;training FTE residents&#160;in excess of&#160;the&#160;applicable threshold.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
