<bill session="115" type="h" number="1641" updated="2017-09-11T03:02:56Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to clarify the responsibilities of Business Opportunity Specialists, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Small Business Act to clarify the responsibilities of Business Opportunity Specialists, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2017-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2810"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1773"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Small Business Act to declare that the exclusive duties of a Business Opportunity Specialist reporting to the senior official (or designee) appointed by the Small Business Administration (SBA) with certain SBA loan responsibilities, including the procurement program for small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans and the Historically Underutilized Business Zone (HUBZone) program, shall be to implement specified SBA loan programs, and complete other duties related to contracting programs.

Such duties shall include:

 performing specified functions with respect to small business concerns eligible to receive federal contracts and subcontracts; reviewing and monitoring compliance with mentor-protege agreements; representing the interests of the SBA and small business concerns in the award, modification, and administration of contracts and subcontracts awarded pursuant to the Act; and reporting fraud or abuse.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
