<bill session="115" type="h" number="1183" updated="2017-08-18T18:30:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildfire Prevention Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildfire Prevention Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to improve mitigation assistance.</title>
    <title type="display">Wildfire Prevention Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000599"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000171" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2017-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Wildfire Prevention Act of 2017

This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to provide hazard mitigation assistance in any area affected by a fire for which fire management assistance was provided under such Act, regardless of whether a major disaster is declared.

Recipients of hazard mitigation assistance may use such assistance to conduct the following activities to help reduce the risk of future damage, hardship, loss, or suffering in any area affected by a wildfire:

 reseeding ground cover with quick-growing or native species; mulching with straw or chipped wood; constructing straw, rock, or log dams in small tributaries to prevent flooding; placing logs and other erosion barriers to catch sediment on hill slopes; installing debris traps to modify road and trail drainage mechanisms; modifying or removing culverts to allow drainage to flow freely; adding drainage dips and constructing emergency spillways to keep roads and bridges from washing out during floods; planting grass to prevent the spread of noxious weeds; installing warning signs; establishing defensible space measures; and reducing hazardous fuels. The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) shall submit to specified congressional committees a report containing a summary of any projects carried out, and any funding provided to those projects, under this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
