<bill session="115" type="h" number="1834" updated="2017-09-06T07:13:37Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cancer Care Payment Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cancer Care Payment Reform Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a national Oncology Medical Home Demonstration Project under the Medicare program for the purpose of changing the Medicare payment for cancer care in order to enhance the quality of care and to improve cost efficiency, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cancer Care Payment Reform Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001159"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2017-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="463"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Cancer Care Payment Reform Act of 2017

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to establish the Oncology Medical Home Demonstration Project, through which the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) shall make special payments to participating oncology practices that coordinate patient care and meet other specified requirements.

During the first two years of the project, CMS shall pay a care coordination management fee to each such practice. After the third, fourth, and fifth years of the project, CMS shall pay a performance incentive payment to each participating practice that meets or exceeds performance standards developed by CMS.

CMS shall assess the performance of each participating oncology practice annually. Performance standards shall address: (1) specified measures related to patient care, resource utilization, survivorship, and end-of-life care; and (2) the patient experience of care, as reflected in surveys submitted by each practice. CMS shall also assess the extent to which a practice has used breakthrough or other best-in-class therapies.

To the extent practicable, CMS shall select practices of varying sizes and geographic areas for participation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
