<bill session="115" type="h" number="52" updated="2017-08-16T18:00:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jobs, On-the-Job 'Earn While You Learn' Training, and Apprenticeships for African-American Young Men Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jobs, On-the-Job Earn While You Learn Training, and Apprenticeships for African-American Young Men Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To rebuild the Nation's crumbling infrastructure, transportation systems, technology and computer networks, and energy distribution systems, by strongly and urgently requesting the immediate recruitment, employment, and on-the-job "earn as you learn" training of African-American young men ages 18 to 39, who are the hardest hit in terms of unemployment, with an unemployment rate of 41 percent nationally, and in some States and cities, especially inner cities, higher than 50 percent, which is a national crisis.</title>
    <title type="display">Jobs, On-the-Job 'Earn While You Learn' Training, and Apprenticeships for African-American Young Men Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2017-07-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2017-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000586" joined="2017-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000584" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000610" joined="2017-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2017-07-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2017-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2017-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Jobs, On-the-Job "Earn While You Learn" Training, and Apprenticeships for African-American Young Men Act

This bill requires the Department of Labor to request labor unions, general contractors, and businesses that will rebuild infrastructure, transportation systems, technology and computer networks, and energy distribution systems to actively recruit, hire, and provide on-the-job training to African American men ages 18 to 39 through existing jobs, apprenticeships, and "earn while you learn" programs. Labor must help coordinate such recruitment.

The jobs, training, and apprenticeships must be conducted in conjunction with Labor, labor unions and associations involved in infrastructure rebuilding, and the National Joint Apprenticeship and Training Committee.

Labor unions, contractors, and businesses involved with such infrastructure or systems must recruit by seeking assistance from the African American community, churches, the National Urban League, the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 100 Black Men of America, high school and college job placement offices, and media outlets.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
