<bill session="115" type="h" number="2602" updated="2017-06-27T12:15:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure our Skies Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure our Skies Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to include training for certain employees of air carriers to combat human trafficking, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Secure our Skies Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000468"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Aviation" code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Secure our Skies Act of 2017

This bill requires each air carrier providing passenger air transportation to provide flight attendants, pilots, and dispatchers who are employees or contractors of the carrier with training to combat human trafficking in the course of carrying out their duties. Such training shall cover: (1) common indicators of human trafficking, and (2) best practices for reporting suspected trafficking to law enforcement officers.

To assist in such training, the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Transportation shall provide information, including the Blue Campaign training module, for use by air carriers.

The Federal Aviation Administration shall report recommendations for improving the identification and reporting of human trafficking by air carrier personnel while protecting the civil liberties of passengers.

The bill grants immunity to an air carrier for reporting any suspicious transaction relevant to a possible violation of law or regulation relating to human trafficking.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
