<bill session="115" type="h" number="2700" updated="2017-09-27T19:30:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Development Investment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Development Investment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow employers a credit against income tax as an incentive to partner with educational institutions to improve workforce development and job training for students and a credit against income tax for certain expenses of job training programs.</title>
    <title type="display">Workforce Development Investment Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2017-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Workforce Development Investment Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow employers a business-related tax credit of $5,000 for each community college, other institution of higher education, or area career and technical education school engaged in a qualified partnership with the employer. The bill allows a maximum credit of $20,000 in any taxable year.

Within six months of the enactment of this bill, the Department of Education must define the term "qualified partnership." The term must include a partnership through which an employer: (1) collaborates with an educational institution to help develop curriculum in order to improve workforce development and job training for students; (2) helps provide instruction to students in the classroom; and (3) provides internships, apprenticeships, or other similar educational opportunities in the workplace for students.

This bill also allows employers a worker training tax credit equal to the lesser of: 50% of the job training program expenditures for a full-time employee participating in a qualified training program, or $5,000. A "qualified training program" is: (1) a qualified partnership, or (2) an apprenticeship program registered and certified with the Department of Labor under the National Apprenticeship Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
