<bill session="115" type="h" number="2458" updated="2017-08-10T12:27:27Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jamiel Shaw, II Memorial Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jamiel Shaw, II Memorial Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make payments by the Department of Homeland Security to a State contingent on a State providing the Federal Bureau of Investigation with certain statistics, to require Federal agencies, departments, and courts to provide such statistics to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and to require the Federal Bureau of Investigation to publish such statistics.</title>
    <title type="display">Jamiel Shaw, II Memorial Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000255"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Communications" code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Jamiel Shaw, II Memorial Act of 2017

 This bill prohibits the payment of funds to a state or its political subdivisions&#160;under any program or activity administered by the Department of Homeland Security&#160;unless such state: (1)&#160;compiles statistics on each person arrested, charged, convicted of a crime, or incarcerated by such state, including the immigration status and country of origin of such persons and the crimes for which such persons were arrested, charged,&#160;convicted, or incarcerated; (2) reports such statistics monthly to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); and (3) certifies, on a monthly basis, compliance with the requirements of this bill.&#160;Each federal agency must compile similar statistics and report on such statistics monthly to the FBI.

The FBI must annually publish all statistics reported under this bill as a separate data collection of&#160;its Uniform Crime Reports.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
