<bill session="115" type="h" number="2689" updated="2017-07-07T13:00:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Requirements, Expectations, and Standard Procedures for Executive Consultation with Tribes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Requirements, Expectations, and Standard Procedures for Executive Consultation with Tribes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RESPECT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RESPECT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prescribe procedures for effective consultation and coordination by Federal agencies with federally recognized Indian Tribes regarding Federal Government activities that impact Tribal lands and interests to ensure that meaningful Tribal input is an integral part of the Federal decision-making process.</title>
    <title type="display">RESPECT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000474" joined="2017-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Requirements, Expectations, and Standard Procedures for Executive Consultation with Tribes Act or the RESPECT Act

This bill requires federal agencies to have a process to ensure meaningful and timely input by Native American tribes before undertaking an activity that may have substantial direct impacts on the lands or interests of the tribes, on the relationship between the federal government and the tribes, or on the distribution of power and responsibilities between the government and the tribes. Agencies may temporarily waive these requirements in an emergency.

Federal agencies must: (1) recognize and respect tribal self-government and sovereignty, honor tribal rights, and strive to meet the responsibilities that arise from the unique legal relationship between the federal government and tribal governments; (2) grant tribal governments maximum discretion in the administration of federal statutes and regulations; (3) streamline the processes under which tribes apply for waivers of statutory and regulatory requirements; and (4) consider waiver applications with a view toward increasing opportunities for flexible policy approaches.

Tribes may seek judicial review of a determination of an agency under this bill if the tribe has exhausted all other administrative remedies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
