<bill session="115" type="s" number="650" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:42Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Support Small Business R &amp; D Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Support Small Business R &amp; D Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Support Small Business R &amp; D Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Support Small Business R &amp; D Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to expand tax credit education and training for small businesses that engage in research and development, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Support Small Business R &amp; D Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2017-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-08-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Risch without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-08-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="195">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 195.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1543"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-08-02T14:08:03Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Support Small Business R &amp; D Act of 2017

(Sec. 3) This bill requires the Small Business Administration (SBA) to develop partnership agreements to:

 provide for development of basic training relating to federal income tax credits benefitting small business concerns and startups, especially credits for research and experimentation, and informational materials relating to such credits, including Internal Revenue Service (IRS) guidance documents; provide these basic training and informational materials through electronic resources and at physical locations; and make the materials available to SBA business development programs and business development entities that partner with SBA programs, including universities, nonprofits, business incubators, and business accelerators. (Sec. 5) The bill amends the Small Business Act to require SBA development centers to provide, in conjunction with the IRS, informational materials, education, and basic training to small business concerns relating to federal income tax credits, including credits available to: (1) businesses generally; and (2) small business concerns and startups specifically, especially credits for research and experimentation. Such materials, education, and basic training may be delivered in person or through an Internet website.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
