<bill session="115" type="s" number="922" updated="2017-06-19T22:00:23Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Change Adapt America Fund Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Change Adapt America Fund Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Climate Change Advisory Commission to develop recommendations, frameworks, and guidelines for projects to respond to the impacts of climate change, to issue Federal obligations, the proceeds of which shall be used to fund projects that aid in adaptation to climate change, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Climate Change Adapt America Fund Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2494-2495" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2129"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Climate Change Adapt America Fund Act of 2017

This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to issue climate change obligations. The proceeds from the debt obligations must be deposited in the Adapt America Fund established by this bill within the Department of Commerce.

Commerce must carry out an investment program to fund projects for reducing economic, social, and environmental impact of the adverse effects of climate change.

The bill establishes the Climate Change Advisory Commission to: (1) establish recommendations, frameworks, and guidelines for the investment program; and (2) identify categories of the most cost-effective investments and projects that emphasize multiple benefits to commerce, human health, and ecosystems.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
