<bill session="115" type="h" number="1754" updated="2017-08-29T17:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to clarify the scope of the exception for common carriers.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to clarify the scope of the exception for common carriers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000567" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001201" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2017-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-28">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Digital Commerce and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to authorize the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to regulate activities of common carriers insofar as the activities are not regulated by the Federal Communications Commission under the Communications Act of 1934 or by the Surface Transportation Board or the Department of Transportation under interstate transportation laws.

Under current law, these common carriers are exempt from the FTC's authority based merely on their status as common carriers. The bill continues to prohibit the FTC from regulating common carriers insofar as they are subject to communications and transportation laws, but allows the FTC to regulate other activities of common carriers under its authority to investigate and prevent unfair methods of competition and unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
