<bill session="115" type="s" number="543" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:42Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Performance Accountability and Contractor Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Performance Accountability and Contractor Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to include in each contract into which the Secretary enters for necessary services authorities and mechanism for appropriate oversight, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Performance Accountability and Contractor Transparency Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2017-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2017-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2017-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2017-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Performance Accountability and Contractor Transparency Act of 2017

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to ensure that each VA contract for services includes:

 measurable metrics on the cost, schedule, and fulfillment of contract requirements; a plan of action and milestones for the provision of the service, including a description of the resources the provider will assign to provide the service; safeguards, including authority to levy financial penalties, to ensure that the service provided meets a minimum threshold of quality; and measurable metrics on the use of award or incentive fees. In each case of a contract that would result in the VA incurring an obligation exceeding $100 million, the VA must:

 ensure that the contract requires the service provider to document its work through VA information technology systems so that the VA can review and validate the quality of the service provided using the metrics set forth in the contract; use the appropriate VA project management accountability system to ensure that the contract provides an adequate return on investment; report on any failure of the service provider to meet contractual obligations, the effect of such failure, and the actions taken by the VA and by the contractor to address it; report the details of any modifications made to the contract and a justification for such modifications; and publish information about the contract and any modifications on its website.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
