<bill session="115" type="s" number="821" updated="2017-10-06T04:49:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote access for United States officials, journalists, and other citizens to Tibetan areas of the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2017-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1872"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Tibet"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reciprocal Access to Tibet Act of 2017

 This bill requires the Department of State to submit an annual, publicly-available report to Congress that includes: (1) a list of individuals holding specified senior Chinese leadership positions at the national and subnational levels; and (2) an assessment of the level of access Chinese authorities granted U.S. diplomats, journalists, and tourists to Tibetan areas in China. Such assessment shall include:

 a comparison with the level of access granted to other areas of China, a comparison between the levels of access granted to Tibetan and non-Tibetan areas in relevant provinces, a comparison of the level of access in the reporting year and the previous year, and a description of the measures that impede the freedom to travel in Tibetan areas. Listed persons shall be ineligible for a visa to enter or to be present in the United States if specified restrictions on foreign travelers entering Tibetan areas remain in effect, subject to a national interests waiver.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the State Department, when granting Chinese diplomats access to parts of the United States, should take into account the extent to which China grants U.S. diplomats access to parts of China, including the Tibetan areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
