<bill session="115" type="h" number="3284" updated="2017-09-27T04:47:58Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-14T12:06:32-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-09-14T12:06:32-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish a Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000627" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000625" joined="2017-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2017-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-01">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 115-284.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-09-01" calendar="Union" number="204">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 204.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:14:37-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Fitzpatrick moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:14:52-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7229-7232" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:14:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3284.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:23:17-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14T12:00:37-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7411-7412" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="529" datetime="2017-09-14T12:06:32-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 398 - 4 (Roll no. 529).</text>
      <reference ref="09/12/17 CR H7229-7230" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14T12:06:33-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-09-14T12:36:48Z" status="Passed House amended">Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act to direct the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to establish a Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series to address emerging terrorist threats and to enhance the ability of state and local jurisdictions to prevent, protect against, respond to, and recover from terrorist attacks.

The workshop series shall include:

 reviewing terrorism preparedness, response, and interdiction plans, policies, and procedures of the participating jurisdictions and identifying gaps in such plans, operational capabilities, response resources, and authorities; identifying federal, state, and local resources available to address such gaps; providing assistance to build or sustain the capabilities to close such gaps; examining the roles and responsibilities of participating agencies and respective communities in the event of a terrorist attack; improving situational awareness and information sharing among all participating agencies in the event of such an attack; and identifying and sharing best practices and lessons learned from each workshop series. FEMA shall select jurisdictions to host a workshop series from cities that: (1) have received or are receiving funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative, and (2) have requested to be considered. Individuals from state and local jurisdictions and emergency response providers in cities selected shall be eligible to participate in the series.

FEMA must report, each year for next six years, to all participating agencies and to Congress regarding key findings or themes, lessons learned, and best practices identified.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-284</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
