<bill session="115" type="h" number="2043" updated="2017-09-11T20:15:09Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Day in Court for Kids Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Day in Court for Kids Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide access to counsel for children and other vulnerable populations.</title>
    <title type="display">Fair Day in Court for Kids Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001038" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000580" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000170" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2017-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000474" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000062" joined="2017-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Day in Court for Kids Act of 2017

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) authorize the Department of Justice (DOJ) to appoint or provide counsel at government expense to aliens in removal proceedings.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall provide an alien in removal proceedings with all relevant documents in its possession, unless the alien has knowingly waived the right to such documents. In the absence of a waiver, a removal proceeding may not proceed until the alien has received and had time to review the documents.

DOJ may appoint or provide counsel to aliens in any INA proceeding.

DHS shall ensure that aliens have access to counsel inside all immigration detention and border facilities.

DOJ shall appoint counsel, at government expense if necessary, for an unaccompanied alien child or a particularly vulnerable individual. If DOJ has consolidated any such alien's case with that of any other alien and that other alien does not have counsel, the appointed counsel shall be appointed to represent the other alien as well.

DHS shall: (1) facilitate access to counsel for all aliens detained in facilities under the supervision of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP); and (2) establish procedures to ensure that legal orientation programs are available for all detained aliens, including aliens held in CBP facilities.

DOJ shall develop and administer a two-year pilot program at not fewer than two immigration courts to grant access to legal information to non-detained aliens with pending asylum claims.

DHS shall establish a pilot program to increase the court appearance rates of unaccompanied alien children and particularly vulnerable individuals by contracting with nongovernmental, community-based organizations to provide such aliens with case management services. The pilot program shall not be used to monitor individuals designated as unaccompanied alien children under the Homeland Security Act.

 If DOJ fails to appoint counsel for an unaccompanied alien child or vulnerable person: (1) no limitation pertaining to the filing of any motion to reopen the removal proceeding shall apply, and (2) the filing of such a motion shall stay the removal of the alien.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
