<bill session="115" type="h" number="1867" updated="2017-09-11T03:02:58Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide for equitable allotment of land to Alaska Native veterans.</title>
    <title type="display">Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="785"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1481"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-03T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Alaska Native Veterans Land Allotment Equity Act

 This bill amends the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to revise provisions regarding land allotments for Alaska Native Vietnam veterans. Eligibility is expanded to include all Alaska Native veterans who served between August 5, 1964, and May 7, 1975.

Allotments may be selected from vacant federal lands or lands that have been selected or conveyed to the state of Alaska or an Alaska Native corporation, if the state or corporation relinquishes or conveys the land to the United States for allotment. Land may not be selected from: (1) the right-of-way of the TransAlaska Pipeline; (2) the inner or outer corridor of that right-of-way; or (3) a unit of the National Park System, a National Preserve, or a National Monument.

 An heir of a deceased eligible veteran, regardless of the cause of death, may apply for and receive an allotment.

 Alaska Native Vietnam veterans who selected an allotment of land before enactment of this bill and who were not conveyed the allotment before the enactment of this bill may reselect land.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
