<bill session="115" type="h" number="1196" updated="2017-10-04T18:00:17Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Counterterrorism Screening and Assistance Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Counterterrorism Screening and Assistance Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a plan to combat international travel by terrorists and foreign fighters, accelerate the transfer of certain border security systems to foreign partner governments, establish minimum international border security standards, authorize the suspension of foreign assistance to countries not making significant efforts to comply with such minimum standards, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Counterterrorism Screening and Assistance Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Z000017"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2017-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2017-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2017-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2017-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-09-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Terrorism,  Nonproliferation, and Trade" code="HSFA18" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Counterterrorism and Intelligence" code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="942"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Counterterrorism Screening and Assistance Act of 2017

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the U.S. government must ensure that capacity-building assistance to combat terrorist travel is coordinated among departments and agencies as well as with foreign implementing partners, and (2) such assistance should be prioritized for the highest-risk countries for travel by terrorists and foreign fighters.

The Department of State shall submit to Congress biennially a foreign partner engagement plan that catalogues existing capacity-building initiatives abroad to combat travel by terrorists and foreign fighters and identifies areas for adjustment to align efforts with risk-based priorities.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the State Department shall accelerate the provision of appropriate versions of the following systems to foreign governments:

 U.S. Customs and Border Protection's global travel targeting and analysis systems; and the State Department's watchlisting, identification, and screening systems. DHS may provide, with specified exceptions, excess DHS nonlethal equipment and supplies (as well as related training) to a foreign government if that would:

 further U.S. homeland security interests; and enhance the recipient government's capacity to mitigate the threat of terrorism, infectious disease or natural disaster, protect lawful trade and travel, or enforce intellectual property rights. DHS shall:

 notify Congress before providing such systems, equipment, or supplies; and report to Congress annually through 2022 regarding foreign government efforts to combat terrorist and foreign fighter travel. The State Department may suspend non-humanitarian, non-trade-related foreign assistance to a foreign country identified in such a report as a country to which the minimum standards for serious and sustained efforts to combat terrorist and foreign fighter travel are applicable but whose government is not fully complying with such standards and is not making significant efforts to bring itself into compliance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
