<bill session="115" type="h" number="340" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation American Manufacturing Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation American Manufacturing Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against tax for qualified manufacturing facility construction costs and to allow a credit against tax for qualified manufacturing facility construction costs.</title>
    <title type="display">Next Generation American Manufacturing Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000248"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Next Generation American Manufacturing Act of 2017

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for the purchase (during a specified period of between 5 and 10 years based on the incentive needed with respect to each product) of new products certified as assembled in the United States and consisting of at least 60% of components assembled or otherwise arising in the United States.

The bill also establishes the 21st Century American Manufacturing Commission to conduct research to designate products eligible for such tax credit.

The bill allows certain start-up companies that are headquartered in the United States a tax credit for up to 25% of their costs for the construction of a manufacturing facility and for the purchase of specialized equipment for use at such facility. A "start-up company" is defined as any corporation or partnership that: (1) first has both gross receipts and qualified research expenses in a taxable year beginning after December 31, 2016; or (2) has both gross receipts and qualified research expenses in fewer than three taxable years beginning after December 31, 2016, and before January 1, 2022.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
