<bill session="115" type="h" number="3096" updated="2017-07-26T07:13:01Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drug-Free Indian Health Service Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drug-Free Indian Health Service Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To implement a mandatory random drug testing program for certain employees of the Indian Health Service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Drug-Free Indian Health Service Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000184"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Drug-Free Indian Health Service Act of 2017

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to implement mandatory random drug testing for Indian Health Service (IHS) employees who provide health care or administrative services to patients at IHS health care facilities. Officers of the Commissioned Corps of the Public Health Service are exempt from this drug testing. Each employee must be tested at least once per year for specified drugs.

HHS must notify employees of the implementation of this drug testing. Employees selected for drug testing must be notified of their selection on the same day as the testing.

Employees found to have engaged in illegal drug use, through testing, direct observation, evidence from a conviction, or voluntary admission, are prohibited from providing services to patients and referred to the HHS Employee Assistance Program (EAP). At the discretion of HHS, an employee may return to duty after obtaining counseling or rehabilitation through the EAP. HHS may initiate an adverse action, including removal, against an employee engaged in illegal drug use unless the employee voluntarily admits to illegal drug use, ceases such activity, and obtains counseling or rehabilitation through the EAP.

Employees who refuse to submit to drug testing are prohibited from providing services to patients and are subject to adverse action.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
