<bill session="115" type="h" number="2595" updated="2017-09-20T18:57:38Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide for an option under the Secure Mail Initiative under which a person to whom a document is sent under that initiative may elect to have the United States Postal Service use the Hold for Pickup service or the Signature Confirmation service in delivering the document, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2017-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2017-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000810" joined="2017-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="1208"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening the Department of Homeland Security Secure Mail Initiative Act

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to provide for an option under which a person to whom a document is sent under the Secure Mail Initiative may elect to have the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) use the Hold for Pickup service or the Signature Confirmation service in delivering the document.

DHS shall require payment of a fee for such services, which shall be deposited into the Immigration Examinations Fee Account and used to cover DHS and USPS costs of providing such services. The USPS: (1) may promulgate regulations that minimize such costs and do not require it to incur additional expenses that are not recoverable, and (2) shall notify DHS of any changes to such services.

If DHS determines that substantially similar services offered by a private carrier would provide better service and value than the USPS services, it may discontinue use of the USPS services and enter into a contract with the private carrier.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
