<bill session="115" type="s" number="441" updated="2017-06-19T21:15:26Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate the Organ Mountains and other public land as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks Conservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2017-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks Conservation Act

 This bill designates specified lands in New Mexico administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) of the Department of the Interior as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

 Such wilderness areas shall also be administered as components of the National Landscape Conservation System.

 The bill designates approximately 100 acres of specified BLM land in New Mexico as a potential wilderness area, upon which Interior shall permit only those uses already permitted. When specified conditions have been met, this area shall be incorporated into the Robledo Mountains Wilderness.

 The bill releases from further review for designation as wilderness the public land in Dona Ana County, New Mexico, administered by the BLM and not designated as wilderness.

 The bill withdraws the Potrillo Mountains Complex from the Potrillo Mountains Wilderness and closes a specified route from public access, making it available only for administrative and law enforcement uses, including border security.

 In implementing a management plan for the Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks National Monument in New Mexico, Interior shall include a watershed health assessment to identify opportunities for watershed restoration.

 Any land or interest that is within specified state trust land acquired by the United States shall become part of the monument.

 Interior shall convey to the state of New Mexico specified BLM land in exchange for specified parcels of state trust land within the monument.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
