<bill session="115" type="h" number="2809" updated="2017-09-25T16:15:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 51, United States Code, to provide for the authorization and supervision of nongovernmental space activities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001283" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2017-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2017-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2017-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2017-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2017-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-07T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017

This bill grants the Office of Space Commerce of the Department of Commerce the authority to issue certifications to U.S. nationals and nongovernmental entities for the operation of: (1) specified human-made objects manufactured or assembled in outer space, including on the Moon and other celestial bodies, with or without human occupants, that were launched from Earth; and (2) all items carried on such objects that are intended for use in outer space. To be eligible for certification, each entity's application must include a space debris mitigation plan for the space objects.

The office shall establish a Private Space Activity Advisory Committee to: (1) analyze the status and recent developments of nongovernmental space activities, and (2) advise on matters relating to U.S. private sector activities in outer space.

The bill authorizes the office to issue permits to persons for the operation of space-based remote sensing systems.

The office shall establish an Advisory Committee on Commercial Remote Sensing to advise on matters relating to the U.S. commercial space-based remote sensing industry.

The bill abolishes the Commercial Remote Sensing Regulatory Affairs Office of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
