<bill session="115" type="h" number="1681" updated="2017-10-03T07:16:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women Veterans and Families Health Services Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women Veterans and Families Health Services Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the reproductive assistance provided by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs to severely wounded, ill, or injured members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and their spouses or partners, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Women Veterans and Families Health Services Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000560"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2017-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2017-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001185" joined="2017-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000170" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2017-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="700"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Women Veterans and Families Health Services Act of 2017

 This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD) to furnish fertility treatment and counseling, including through the use of assisted reproductive technology, to a severely wounded, ill, or injured member of the Armed Forces who has an infertility condition incurred or aggravated while serving on active duty (covered member) or to the spouse, partner, or gestational surrogate of such member.

 DOD shall:

 establish procedures for gamete retrieval from a member of the Armed Forces in cases in which the fertility of such member is potentially jeopardized as a result of an injury or illness incurred or aggravated while serving on active duty; and give members of the Armed Forces on active duty the opportunity to cryopreserve and store their gametes prior to a combat zone deployment at no cost to the member. Fertility counseling and treatment are included within authorized Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) medical services.

 The VA shall furnish such treatment and services to a jointly applying covered veteran and his or her spouse, partner, or gestational surrogate.

The VA may pay the adoption expenses (for up to three adoptions) for a covered member who is enrolled in the VA health care system.

 The VA shall facilitate research conducted collaboratively by DOD and the Department of Health and Human Services to improve the VA's ability to meet the reproductive health care needs of veterans who have a service-connected genitourinary disability or a condition that was incurred or aggravated in the line of duty that affects the veterans' reproductive ability.

 The VA shall enhance the capabilities of the VA women veterans contact center to: (1) respond to assistance requests, and (2) refer such veterans to federal or community resources.

 The pilot program of group retreat reintegration and readjustment counseling for women veterans recently separated from service is enlarged and extended.

 The bill provides child care assistance to qualified veterans for: (1) mental health care services, and (2) readjustment counseling and related mental health services.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
