<bill session="115" type="hr" number="286" updated="2017-06-27T07:15:25Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Directing certain officials of the executive branch to provide information to the House of Representatives that will enable the House to meet its constitutional responsibility to conduct oversight of the executive branch by investigating potential conflicts of interests of President Donald J. Trump.</title>
    <title type="display">Directing certain officials of the executive branch to provide information to the House of Representatives that will enable the House to meet its constitutional responsibility to conduct oversight of the executive branch by investigating potential conflicts of interests of President Donald J. Trump.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001101"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2017-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Transportation and Infrastructure, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Presidential administrations"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Declares that the House of Representatives directs President Trump to: (1) transmit to the House of Representatives copies of any document, correspondence, or other communication in possession of the Executive Office of the President that refers or relates to his proposal to maintain an interest in his business holdings while turning over day-to-day operation of those interests to his sons Donald J. Trump, Jr., and Eric Trump; and (2) provide visitor logs for the White House and Mar-A-Lago to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. Requires such committee to hold ongoing votes on reporting the logs' contents to the full House.

Directs: (1) the Department of the Treasury to provide the House Committee on Ways and Means with the tax return information of Donald J. Trump for tax years 2007 through 2016 for review in closed executive session, and (2) such committee to hold a vote on reporting such information to the full House.

Directs the Office on Government Ethics to publish any waiver or exception granted to any federal officer or employee to the January 28, 2017, executive order entitled "Ethics Commitments by Executive Branch Appointees."

Directs the General Services Administration to provide the oversight committee with any legal analysis supporting its March 23, 2017, conclusion that Trump International Hotel in Washington, DC may maintain its lease with the federal government, despite an express prohibition on elected officials taking part in the lease.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
