<bill session="115" type="h" number="2674" updated="2017-09-19T11:30:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Young Americans Financial Literacy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Young Americans Financial Literacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program in the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection to fund the establishment of centers of excellence to support research, development and planning, implementation, and evaluation of effective programs in financial literacy education for young people and families ages 8 through 24 years old, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Young Americans Financial Literacy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001072"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E733"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Young Americans Financial Literacy Act

This bill requires the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau to award competitive grants to eligible&#160;institutions for the establishment of centers of excellence to support research, development, implementation, and evaluation of effective financial-literacy education programs for young people and families. An "eligible institution" is a partnership among two or more of the following:

 an institution of higher education; a local educational agency; a nonprofit agency, organization, or association; or a financial institution. Authorized grant-funded activities shall include:

 developing and implementing comprehensive, research-based, financial-literacy education programs for young people; designing instructional materials; developing and supporting the delivery of professional-development programs in financial-literacy education; improving access to, and dissemination of, financial-literacy information for young people and families; developing educational programs to reduce student-loan default rates; conducting ongoing research and evaluation of financial-literacy education programs; and measuring the effectiveness of authorized activities. The&#160;grant program&#160;shall terminate&#160;after FY2019.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
