<bill session="115" type="h" number="1397" updated="2017-09-11T03:02:55Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-11T18:54:12-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-11T18:54:12-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize, direct, facilitate, and expedite the transfer of administrative jurisdiction of certain Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To authorize, direct, facilitate, and expedite the transfer of administrative jurisdiction of certain Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001105"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-206, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-11" calendar="Union" number="143">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 143.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11T16:44:33-04:00">
      <text>Mr. LaHood moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11T16:44:42-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5404" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11T16:44:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1397.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11T16:51:40-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11T18:31:06-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5417" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="345" datetime="2017-07-11T18:54:12-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 406 - 0 (Roll no. 345).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5404" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11T18:54:13-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Highways and Transit" code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1460"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-11T15:19:33Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

(Sec. 1) This bill transfers administrative jurisdiction over:

 0.342 acres of federal land within the boundary of the George Washington Memorial Parkway from the Department of the Interior to the Department of Transportation (DOT), and 0.479 acres of federal land within the boundary of the Turner-Fairbank Highway Research Center of the Federal Highway Administration (FHA) adjacent to the parkway from DOT to Interior. Interior shall prohibit the storage, construction, or installation of any items that may interfere with access by the research center to certain restricted land within the parkway boundary for security and maintenance purposes.

The transfers of administrative jurisdiction under this bill shall not be subject to reimbursement or consideration.

The National Park Service and the FHA shall comply with the agreement they entered into on September 11, 2002, regarding the transfer of administrative jurisdiction, management, and maintenance of the land specified in it.

Subject to the terms of such agreement, Interior shall allow the research center to access specified acreage of: (1) the federal land transferred to Interior for purposes of transportation to and from the research center, and (2) such such land and the restricted land for maintenance of the visual appearance of such land.

The Research Center shall maintain the restricted land.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-206</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
