<bill session="115" type="s" number="1421" updated="2017-10-11T16:00:18Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patsy T. Mink Gender Equity in Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patsy T. Mink Gender Equity in Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support educational entities in fully implementing title IX and reducing and preventing sex discrimination in all areas of education.</title>
    <title type="display">Patsy T. Mink Gender Equity in Education Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2017-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="3828"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Patsy T. Mink Gender Equity in Education Act of 2017

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to establish an Office for Gender Equity to support state and local educational agencies, institutions of higher education, and elementary and secondary schools in fully implementing title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972, which prohibits discrimination on the basis of sex in federally funded education programs or activities. The office may provide grants and perform activities to reduce or prevent discrimination, bias, harassment, or violence based on actual or perceived sex, sexual orientation, gender, gender identity, pregnancy, childbirth, or related medical conditions or stereotypes in all areas of education.

The office must provide technical assistance and annual training to title IX coordinators and develop a handbook for conducting self-evaluations of title IX compliance. The training must address "compound discrimination" (defined as discrimination based on sex and other characteristics, including race, ethnicity, national origin, disability status, religion, or age).

The office may award grants to educational entities and partnerships to:

 train students, teachers, faculty, and personnel; increase campus resources, facilities, and course offerings; support title IX coordinators in performing outreach, advocacy, and education; identify patterns or systemic problems in title IX compliance; strengthen prevention education and awareness programs; conduct campus climate and victimization surveys; identify gender inequities; and improve data collection and reporting of gender equity indicators from academic assessments, civil rights data, campus data, employment data, attendance and absenteeism data, or title IX coordinator-to-student ratios. ED must coordinate with the Institute of Education Sciences and other federal offices and entities to investigate, identify, and disseminate best practices to: (1) reduce and prevent sex stereotyping, bias, and discrimination in curricula and educational materials; (2) address sex-based harassment and violence on campuses; (3) develop counseling and career guidance training; (4) mitigate implicit bias in teaching and discipline; and (5) address the needs of students who face compound discrimination.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
