<bill session="115" type="h" number="1459" updated="2017-10-05T07:16:18Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Stability Oversight Council Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Stability Oversight Council Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To place the Financial Stability Oversight Council and the Office of Financial Research under the regular appropriations process, to provide for certain quarterly reporting and public notice and comment requirements for the Office of Financial Research, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Financial Stability Oversight Council Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000614" joined="2017-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2017-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2017-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001193" joined="2017-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000606" joined="2017-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2017-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2017-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial Stability Oversight Council"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Financial Stability Oversight Council Reform Act 

This bill amends the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to make the budgets of the Financial Stability Oversight Council (FSOC) and the Office of Financial Research (OFR) subject to the annual appropriations process and to establish requirements for reports and a public notice and comment period.

 The budgets of the FSOC and the OFR are funded by assessments on financial institutions which are deposited into the Financial Research Fund and, under current law, are immediately available to be spent. This bill requires the funding from the Financial Research Fund to be made available by appropriations Acts.

 The OFR must submit quarterly reports to Congress regarding its:

 finances; workforce; and actions taken to achieve the goals, objectives, and performance measures of the office. The OFR must provide a public notice and comment period of at least 90 days before issuing any proposed report, rule, or regulation.

 The bill expands the duties of the OFR to include:

 publishing an annual work plan; consulting with other federal departments and agencies with relevant expertise prior to preparing any public report with respect to a specified entity, class of entities, or financial product or service; and developing and implementing a cybersecurity plan. The Government Accountability Office must annually audit the cybersecurity plan and its implementation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
