<bill session="115" type="h" number="2507" updated="2017-10-06T19:00:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Power Grid Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Power Grid Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a technology demonstration program related to the modernization of the electric grid.</title>
    <title type="display">21st Century Power Grid Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001168"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2017-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Power" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2479"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">21st Century Power Grid Act

This bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a financial assistance program to carry out eligible projects related to the modernization of the electric grid, including the application of technologies to improve observability, advanced controls, and prediction of system performance on the distribution system and related transmission system inter-dependencies.

To be eligible for financial assistance, a project shall: (1) be designed to improve the performance and efficiency of the future electric grid, while ensuring the continued provision of safe, secure, reliable, and affordable power, and provide new options for customer-owned resources; (2) demonstrate secure integration and management of energy resources and secure integration and interoperability of communications and information technologies; and (3) include the participation of a partnership consisting of two or more entities.

Each project shall include: (1) the development of a cybersecurity plan written in accordance with guidelines developed by DOE; and (2) a privacy impact assessment that evaluates the project against the five core concepts in DOE's Voluntary Code of Conduct (commonly known as the DataGuard Energy Data Privacy Program), or the most recent revisions to DOE's privacy program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
