<bill session="115" type="h" number="2883" updated="2017-09-11T03:05:58Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-19T17:25:18-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-19T17:25:18-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a more uniform, transparent, and modern process to authorize the construction, connection, operation, and maintenance of international border-crossing facilities for the import and export of oil and natural gas and the transmission of electricity.</title>
    <title type="display">Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2017-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 12 .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 31 - 20.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 115-225, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Committee on Natural Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-17" calendar="Union" number="160">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 160.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18T17:59:55-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 454 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2910, H.R. 2883 and H.R. 218. The resolution makes in order at anytime on the legislative day of July 20, 2017, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules, relating to the bill H.R. 2825. Also the rule provides that the Committee on Appropriations may at any time before 5 p.m. on Friday, July 21, 2017, file privileged reports to accompany measures making appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T15:33:09-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 454.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6010-6023" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T15:33:14-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2910, H.R. 2883 and H.R. 218. The resolution makes in order at anytime on the legislative day of July 20, 2017, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules, relating to the bill H.R. 2825. Also the rule provides that the Committee on Appropriations may at any time before 5 p.m. on Friday, July 21, 2017, file privileged reports to accompany measures making appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T15:34:25-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 454 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T15:34:26-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John J. Duncan, Jr. to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T15:34:36-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2883.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T16:15:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 454, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Engel amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T16:19:15-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Engel amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Engel demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T16:19:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 454, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tsongas amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T16:25:11-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tsongas amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Tsongas demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T16:26:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 454, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gene Green (TX) amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T16:29:48-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on the question of adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T17:05:06-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2883.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T17:05:34-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T17:05:45-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T17:07:05-04:00">
      <text>Mr. O'Halleran moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6021" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T17:07:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the O'Halleran motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to a requirement that all iron and steel products used in construction, connection, operation, and maintenance of the border-crossing facility be produced in the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T17:12:27-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T17:19:09-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 193 - 232 (Roll no. 397).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="398" datetime="2017-07-19T17:25:18-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 254 - 175 (Roll no. 398).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6017-6018" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19T17:25:20-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Power" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="454"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h209"/>
    <amendment number="h208"/>
    <amendment number="h207"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-06-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act

This bill prohibits any person from constructing, connecting, operating, or maintaining a border-crossing facility for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity across an international border of the United States without obtaining a certificate of crossing.

The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), with respect to oil or natural gas pipelines, or the Department of Energy (DOE), with respect to electric transmission facilities, must issue a certificate of crossing for the border-crossing facility within 120 days after final action is taken under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, unless it is not in the public interest.

DOE, as a condition of issuing a certificate, must require that the border-crossing facility be constructed, connected, operated, or maintained consistent with specified policies and standards.

The bill amends the Natural Gas Act to require FERC to approve within 30 days after receipt any application for the importation or exportation of natural gas to or from Canada or Mexico.

No presidential permit as required under specified executive orders shall be necessary for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of an oil or natural gas pipeline or electric transmission facility, including any border-crossing facility.

No certificate of crossing shall be required for a modification to an existing facility that is operating for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity prior to the enactment of this bill.

FERC and DOE must publish a final rule in the Federal Register within one year to carry out the requirements of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-225</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
