<bill session="115" type="h" number="905" updated="2017-09-27T07:15:43Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">You Own Devices Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 17, United States Code, to provide that the first sale doctrine applies to any computer program that enables a machine or other product to operate, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">You Own Devices Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2017-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000587" joined="2017-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2017-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">You Own Devices Act

This bill amends federal copyright law to allow the owner of a machine or other product operated in any part by a computer program to transfer an authorized copy of the computer program, or the right to obtain such copy, when the owner sells, leases, or otherwise transfers the machine or product to another person. The bill prohibits such right to transfer the computer program from being waived by any agreement.

Any right to receive modifications to such a computer program relating to security or error correction that applied to the owner of the machine or product shall apply to the person to whom the machine or product and the copy of the computer program are transferred.

Nothing in this bill should be construed to permit the owner to retain an unauthorized copy of the computer program after such a transfer.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
