<bill session="115" type="s" number="320" updated="2017-06-19T21:00:25Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NextGen Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NextGen Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal Aviation Administration to establish annual performance objectives and to hold the Chief NextGen Officer accountable for meeting such objectives.</title>
    <title type="display">NextGen Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S746-747" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S747" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">NextGen Accountability Act

This bill amends the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to direct the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to establish annual Next Generation Air Transportation System (NextGen) performance goals for each of the national airspace system performance metrics to meet identified performance metric baselines with respect to NextGen projects.

The bill amends the Vision 100--Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act to revise contents of an annual Department of Transportation report to Congress regarding an integrated work plan for the NextGen. The plan shall include, among other things, a description of the progress made in meeting NextGen performance goals relative to the performance metrics.

The bill revises requirements for the award of bonuses to the FAA Chief NextGen Officer. The FAA, for purposes of the award of such bonuses, shall also consider any progress made toward meeting the NextGen performance goals.

The bill revises certain performance goals set forth in the annual performance agreement between the FAA and the NextGen Officer to include quantifiable NextGen airspace efficiency, productivity, capacity, and safety performance objectives.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
