<bill session="115" type="h" number="621" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disposal of Excess Federal Lands Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disposal of Excess Federal Lands Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to sell certain Federal lands in Arizona, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nebraska, Nevada, New Mexico, Oregon, Utah, and Wyoming, previously identified as suitable for disposal, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Disposal of Excess Federal Lands Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Disposal of Excess Federal Lands Act of 2017

 This bill directs the Department of the Interior: (1) to offer for disposal by competitive sale for not less that fair market value certain federal lands in Arizona, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nebraska, Nevada, New Mexico, Oregon, Utah, and Wyoming, previously identified in the report submitted to Congress on May 27, 1997, pursuant to the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996, as suitable for disposal or exchange for the purpose of conducting restoration activities in the Everglades region of Florida; and (2) within four years after enactment of this bill, to submit a list of such lands that have not been sold and the reasons why.

All net proceeds from the sale of such lands shall be deposited into the Treasury for reduction of the public debt.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
