<bill session="115" type="sj" number="48" updated="2017-10-05T04:31:54Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States relating to parental rights.</title>
    <title type="display">A joint resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States relating to parental rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2017-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2017-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2017-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2017-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-08-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Constitutional Amendment

This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment stating that:

 the liberty of parents to direct the upbringing, education, and care of their children is a fundamental right; the parental right to direct education includes the right to choose, as an alternative to public education, private, religious, or home schools, and the right to make reasonable choices within public schools for one's child; neither the United States nor any state shall infringe upon these rights without demonstrating that its governmental interest as applied to the person is of the highest order and not otherwise served; the parental rights guaranteed by this amendment shall not be denied or abridged on account of disability; this amendment shall not be construed to apply to a parental action or decision that would end life; and no treaty may be adopted nor shall any source of international law be employed to supersede, modify, interpret, or apply to the rights guaranteed by this amendment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
