<bill session="115" type="s" number="135" updated="2017-07-20T16:56:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park Boundary Revision Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park Boundary Revision Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to redesignate Ocmulgee National Monument in the State of Georgia and revise its boundary, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park Boundary Revision Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="538"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park Boundary Revision Act

This bill redesignates the Ocmulgee National Monument in Georgia as the Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park. The boundary of the park is adjusted to include approximately 2,100 acres.

The Department of the Interior may acquire lands within park boundaries by donation or exchange only. No private property or non-federal public property shall be included within those boundaries without the owner's written consent.

 Interior shall conduct a special resource study of the Ocmulgee River corridor between the cities of Macon, Georgia, and Hawkinsville, Georgia, to determine:

 the national significance of the study area; the suitability and feasibility of adding lands in the study area to the National Park System; and the methods and means for the protection and interpretation of the study area by the National Park Service, other federal, state, local government entities, affiliated federally recognized Indian tribes, or private or nonprofit organizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
