<bill session="115" type="hc" number="25" updated="2017-09-06T07:15:26Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress on the admission of refugees and immigrants to the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of Congress on the admission of refugees and immigrants to the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2017-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2017-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of Congress that Executive Order 13769, entitled "Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States," is not a testament to the United States as a nation that is welcoming to all regardless of race, religion, or country of origin. Among the order's major provisions are restrictions on the entry of immigrants and nonimmigrants from seven countries (Iran, Iraq, Libya, Somalia, Sudan, Syria, and Yemen) and additional limitations on refugee admissions to the United States.

Declares that:

 the President must immediately allow for the continued entry of refugees that have already been granted admission to the United States by the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program; the United States should continue to resettle refugees that need protection, and lawful permanent residents should be granted entry into the United States, regardless of their country of origin; and the Visa Interview Waiver Program should not be suspended while the Department of State conducts a review of all nonimmigrant visa reciprocity agreements to ensure that there are no disruptions to communities, institutions of education, and interstate commerce.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
