<bill session="115" type="h" number="23" updated="2017-09-29T16:58:38Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-12T19:17:27-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-12T19:17:27-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gaining Responsibility on Water Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gaining Responsibility on Water Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Accelerated Revenue, Repayment, and Surface Water Storage Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Accelerated Revenue, Repayment, and Surface Water Storage Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Bureau of Reclamation Project Streamlining Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Water Rights Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Gaining Responsibility on Water Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Gaining Responsibility on Water Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Bureau of Reclamation Project Streamlining Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Water Rights Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Water Rights Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Water Supply Permitting Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide drought relief in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Gaining Responsibility on Water Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000129"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2017-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000612" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001048" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001165" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000181" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000820" joined="2017-01-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-11T21:22:29-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 431 Reported to House. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on both H.R. 2810 and H.R. 23. Both bills are considered under structured rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T14:53:57-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 431 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T16:34:05-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 431.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5503-5533" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5511-5524" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T16:34:10-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for one hour of debate on both H.R. 2810 and H.R. 23. Both bills are considered under structured rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T16:34:17-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 431 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T16:34:18-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Scott Perry to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T16:34:57-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T17:44:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LaMalfa amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T17:54:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Costa amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T18:01:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Costa amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T18:07:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Denham amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T18:11:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeSaulnier amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T18:20:21-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeSaulnier amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. DeSaulnier demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T18:21:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 431, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pearce amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T18:54:01-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T18:54:43-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T18:54:51-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T18:56:28-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Carbajal moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5531" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T18:56:53-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Carbajal motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to ensure that there is an adequate supply of water to fight wildfires, utilizing water from reservoirs or other surface waters.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T19:03:22-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T19:10:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 189 - 230 (Roll no. 351).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="352" datetime="2017-07-12T19:17:27-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 230 - 190 (Roll no. 352).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12T19:17:29-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Power and Oceans" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="431"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="875"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h159"/>
    <amendment number="h158"/>
    <amendment number="h157"/>
    <amendment number="h156"/>
    <amendment number="h155"/>
    <amendment number="h154"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Gaining Responsibility on Water Act of 2017

 This bill requires the Central Valley Project (CVP) and the State Water Project in California to be operated pursuant to the water quality standards and operational constraints described in the "Principles for Agreement on the Bay-Delta Standards Between the State of California and the Federal Government" dated December 15, 1994.

 The Department of the Interior shall cease any action to implement the San Joaquin River Restoration Settlement Act.

The Bureau of Reclamation shall complete specified feasibility studies for water storage projects in California.

Interior is directed, in the operation of the CVP, to adhere to California's water rights laws governing water rights priorities and to honor water rights senior to those held by the United States.

Interior, in the operation of the Trinity River Division of the CVP, shall not make releases from Lewiston Dam in excess of specified volumes for each water-year type.

Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall recognize: (1) congressional opposition to the violation of private property rights by the California State Water Resources Control Board in its proposal to require a minimum percentage of unimpaired flows in the main tributaries of the San Joaquin River; and (2) the need to provide reliable water supplies to municipal, industrial, and agricultural users across the state.

The Bureau of Reclamation is established as the lead agency for purposes of coordinating all reviews, permits, licenses, or other approvals or decisions required under federal law to construct qualifying water projects. Reclamation shall identify, as early as practicable upon receipt of an application for a qualifying project, any federal agency that may have jurisdiction over a review, permit, license, approval, or decision required for a qualifying project.

Interior must convert certain existing water service contracts between the United States and water users' associations to repayment contracts, upon the request of the contractor, to allow for the prepayment of such contracts.

The bill amends the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to authorize Interior to develop additional project benefits through the construction of new or supplementary works.

Neither Interior nor USDA may condition or withhold issuance or renewal of any land use permit based on federal limitations or encumbrances or otherwise infringe on state water rights.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
