<bill session="115" type="h" number="3238" updated="2017-10-07T07:15:57Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Assistance Equity Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Assistance Equity Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide assistance for common interest communities, condominiums, and housing cooperatives damaged by a major disaster, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Disaster Assistance Equity Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2017-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2017-08-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2017-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2017-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2017-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2017-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2017-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2017-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2017-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Disaster Assistance Equity Act of 2017

This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to modify the definition of "private nonprofit facility" to include any facilities (including roads, bridges, sewer systems, and other critical community infrastructure) owned or operated by a common interest community that provide essential services of a governmental nature.

The bill also defines additional terms under such Act, including "condominium" and "housing cooperative." "Common interest community" is defined as: (1) any nonprofit mandatory membership organization comprised of owners of real estate (other than a condominium or housing cooperative) described in a declaration or created pursuant to a covenant or other applicable law with respect to which a person, by virtue of the person's ownership of a unit, is obligated to pay for a share of real estate taxes, insurance premiums, maintenance or improvement of, or services or other expenses related to, common elements, other units, or any other real estate other than the unit described in the declaration; and (2) a condominium project that is comprised entirely of detached single family units or that is comprised of four or more multi-unit housing structures and that owns or operates facilities that provide essential services of a governmental nature.

The bill amends such Act to provide that for purposes of the provision of federal disaster assistance with respect to residential elements that are the legal responsibility of an association for a condominium or housing cooperative, the terms "individual" or "household" include the association.

The President must determine the maximum amount of assistance that any such association may receive under such Act for a single disaster.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
