<bill session="115" type="h" number="1543" updated="2017-06-19T21:30:22Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Support Small Business R &amp; D Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Support Small Business R &amp; D Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to expand tax credit education and training for small businesses that engage in research and development, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Support Small Business R &amp; D Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000376"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2017-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="650"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Support Small Business R &amp; D Act of 2017

This bill requires the Small Business Administration (SBA), in consultation with the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), to develop partnership agreements to:

 provide for development of basic training relating to federal income tax credits benefitting small business concerns and startups, especially credits for research and experimentation, and informational materials relating to such credits, including IRS guidance documents; provide these basic training and informational materials through electronic resources and at physical locations; and make the materials available to SBA business development programs and business development entities that partner with SBA programs, including universities, nonprofits, business incubators, and business accelerators. The bill amends the Small Business Act to require SBA development centers to provide, in conjunction with the IRS, informational materials, education, and basic training to small business concerns relating to federal income tax credits, including credits available to: (1) businesses generally; and (2) small business concerns and startups specifically, especially credits for research and experimentation.

Such materials, education, and basic training may be delivered in person or through an Internet website.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
