<bill session="115" type="s" number="859" updated="2017-07-27T06:06:18Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes Fishery Research Authorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes Fishery Research Authorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Director of the United States Geological Survey to conduct monitoring, assessment, science, and research, in support of the binational fisheries within the Great Lakes Basin, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Great Lakes Fishery Research Authorization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2017-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2017-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2017-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1580"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Great Lakes Fishery Research Authorization Act of 2017

This bill authorizes the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) to conduct critical monitoring, scientific assessments, and research in support of fisheries within the Great Lakes Basin between the United States and Canada.

In support of the fisheries within the Great Lakes Basin, the USGS Great Lakes Science Center shall: (1) execute a comprehensive, multi-lake, freshwater fisheries science program; (2) work cooperatively with regional, state, tribal, and local governments; and (3) consult with interested groups, including academia and Canadian agencies.

 To protect and improve the Great Lakes, the USGS Great Lakes Science Center may provide:

 deep-water ecosystem research, fish behavior and habitat reports, fish population assessments, invasive species research, use of biological equipment and laboratory capabilities necessary to support fishery management decisions, and studies that assess impacts on Great Lakes Fishery resources.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
