<bill session="115" type="h" number="854" updated="2017-06-19T21:00:29Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Retirement Security for American Workers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Retirement Security for American Workers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the qualification requirements with respect to certain multiple employer plans with pooled plan providers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Retirement Security for American Workers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001260"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2017-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000015" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000586" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000607" joined="2017-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Retirement Security for American Workers Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to modify the qualification requirements for certain multiple employer retirement plans.

A multiple employer plan that meets certain criteria may not be disqualified or otherwise lose its tax-favored status because one or more participating employers fail to take actions required with respect to the plan.

The bill applies to a multiple employer defined contribution plan or a plan that consists of Individual Retirement Accounts that either: (1) is sponsored by employers that both have a common interest other than having adopted the plan and control the plan, or (2) have a pooled plan provider.

The bill does not apply unless the terms of the plan require a noncompliant employer to, subject to the discretion of the Internal Revenue Service, (1) transfer assets of the plan attributable to the employees of the noncompliant employer to other specified retirement plans, and (2) be liable for plan liabilities attributable to employees of the noncompliant employer.

For the purposes of this bill, a defined contribution plan that is established or maintained for the purpose of providing benefits to the employees of two or more employers and that meets certain requirements (a pooled employer plan) is treated for the purposes of ERISA as a single plan that is a multiple employer plan.

The bill modifies reporting requirements under ERISA that apply to pooled employer and multiple employer plans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
