<bill session="115" type="h" number="3433" updated="2017-09-19T15:00:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Feeding America through Farm Flexibility Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Feeding America through Farm Flexibility Act of 2017'</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agricultural Act of 2014 to increase the number of base acres upon which agricultural producers are authorized to grow fruits and vegetables without a resulting reduction in payment acres on their farm when the resulting produce is used to help alleviate a food desert, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Feeding America through Farm Flexibility Act of 2017'</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000385"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2017-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Feeding America through Farm Flexibility Act of 2017

This bill amends the Agricultural Act of 2014 to increase the number of acres on which agricultural producers are authorized to grow fruits and vegetables without a resulting reduction in the payment acres used to calculate price loss coverage and agriculture risk coverage payments.

The increases are permitted if the crops on the additional acres are grown for sale or donation in a food desert, which is a census tract that: (1) has a poverty rate of at least 20%, and (2) provides difficult access to a retail outlet that provides a wide variety of fruits and vegetables.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
