<bill session="115" type="s" number="1118" updated="2017-09-29T04:34:17Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the North Korea Human Rights Act of 2004, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2017-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2017-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2397"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2017

This bill authorizes the President, through the Department of State, to: (1) provide grants to distribute information receiving devices, electronically readable devices, and other informational sources in North Korea; and (2) establish a grant program to develop and/or distribute new products or methods to allow North Koreans easier access to outside information.

The Broadcasting Board of Governors may broadcast American, Korean, Chinese, and other popular music, television, movies, and popular cultural references as part of its programming.

The Board shall broadcast to North Korea in the Korean language information on rights, laws, and freedoms afforded through the North Korean Constitution and through other applicable treaties or international agreements.

The President is authorized to provide grants for research on North Korea's denial of human rights.

The bill extends through 2022 the requirements for annual reports from: (1) the Special Envoy on North Korean human rights issues, (2) the U.S. Agency for International Development on U.S. humanitarian assistance activities both inside North Korea and for North Koreans outside of North Korea, and (3) the State Department and Department of Homeland Security on North Korean refugees and immigration.

The North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 is amended to authorize appropriations through FY2022 for: (1) programs that promote human rights, democracy, the rule of law, and the development of a market economy in North Korea; (2) actions to promote freedom of information in North Korea; and (3) humanitarian assistance to North Koreans who are outside of North Korea without the permission of the government.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
