<bill session="115" type="h" number="550" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:24Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Checkpoint Safety Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Checkpoint Safety Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require the deployment of law enforcement personnel at airport screening locations at very large airports, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Checkpoint Safety Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2017-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000625" joined="2017-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2017-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2017-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2017-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2017-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2017-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2017-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2017-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2017-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2017-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2017-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2017-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2017-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Protective Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Transportation Security" code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Checkpoint Safety Act of 2017

This bill revises minimum requirements for the deployment of armed law enforcement personnel at security screening locations at certain airports.

The Transportation Security Administration (TSA), formerly the Under Secretary of Transportation for Security of the Department of Transportation, shall order the deployment of at least one armed law enforcement officer within 300 feet of the security screening location and within the terminal during operating hours of each airport having annual enplanements of 8 million or more or international enplanements of 1 million or more. The TSA shall order the deployment of additional armed law enforcement officers at such airports if deemed necessary to ensure airport security.

The bill revises air transportation security program requirements to require that such programs ensure:

 law enforcement presence at each airport is adequate to ensure the safety of passengers, as under current law, and their property; close cooperation between all relevant parties in ensuring airport security; high training standards for all security and law enforcement personnel; prompt notification of, and law enforcement response to, any security incidents at airports, including detention of persons who attempt to evade transportation security screening; and multiple means for TSA Officers or members of the public to request prompt law enforcement assistance in the airport. The bill repeals TSA authority for allowing deputized state and local law enforcement officers to be stationed other than at airport security screening locations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
