<bill session="115" type="h" number="1202" updated="2017-09-13T21:00:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Red Hill Oversight and Environmental Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Red Hill Oversight and Environmental Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for environmental oversight and remediation activities at Red Hill Bulk Fuel Storage Facility.</title>
    <title type="display">Red Hill Oversight and Environmental Protection Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000571" joined="2017-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-17">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Readiness" code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="437"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Red Hill Oversight and Environmental Protection Act of 2017

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to ensure that: (1) its budget justification materials submitted to Congress include a description of how it will use funds to support any deliverables that the parties of the agreement between the Department of the Navy, the Defense Logistics Agency, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Region 9, and the State of Hawaii Department of Health, entered into on September 28, 2015, have identified as necessary to mitigate and prevent fuel leaks at the Red Hill Bulk Fuel Storage Facility on Oahu, Hawaii; and (2) each future-years defense program describes how DOD will use funds to support deliverables that the parties to such agreement identified as necessary to mitigate and prevent such leaks.

The EPA must ensure that its budget justification materials submitted to Congress include a description of how it will use funds to support such deliverables.

DOD may obligate or expend specified amounts to carry out an unspecified minor military construction project for the sustainment and maintenance of the facility. DOD shall submit to the congressional defense committees written notice of any decision to carry out such project, including a justification for, and the estimated cost of, such project. The authority to carry out such project shall terminate on September 30, 2030.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
