<bill session="115" type="h" number="212" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:26Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EFFECT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expediting Funding For Efficient Contracting Tribes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expediting Funding For Efficient Contracting Tribes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act to provide a process for expediting congressional review of an Indian tribe's funding agreement at the Indian tribe's request, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">EFFECT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expediting Funding For Efficient Contracting Tribes Act or the EFFECT Act

This bill amends the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act to permit an Indian tribe to submit a request for expedited review of the tribe's proposed annual funding agreement to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives. If the committees assent to the request, the Department of the Interior must waive part or all of the review period for the agreement and set or amend the effective date of the agreement, as specified by the committees.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
