<bill session="115" type="hr" number="278" updated="2017-09-13T16:00:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Members Operating to Be Innovative and Link Everyone Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MOBILE Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to permit absent Members to participate in committee hearings using video conferencing and related technologies and to establish a remote voting system under which absent Members may cast votes in the House on motions to suspend the rules.</title>
    <title type="display">MOBILE Resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001087" joined="2017-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2017-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Members Operating to Be Innovative and Link Everyone Resolution or the MOBILE Resolution

Amends Rule XI (Procedures of Committees and Unfinished Business) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require each committee to permit any member absent from the site of a hearing, and any other absent individual invited to participate in the hearing, to use video conferencing and related technologies in order to participate in it to the same extent as members of the committee and other individuals present at the site of the meeting.

Requires a committee to adopt a rule to count any member who participates remotely in a hearing as one of the number of members constituting a quorum at the hearing.

Amends Rule XV (Business in Order on Special Days) to require the Clerk, Chief Administrative Officer, and Sergeant at Arms to work together to develop and implement a secure remote voting system under which any member absent from the floor shall be permitted to cast a vote remotely on a motion to suspend the rules if the vote is taken by electronic device.

Requires the member to be treated as present for purposes of determining the existence of a quorum for considering the motion.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
