<bill session="115" type="h" number="2390" updated="2017-09-18T21:30:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLO Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLO Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen prohibitions regarding the Palestine Liberation Organization, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">PLO Accountability Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000435"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2017-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2017-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2017-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and North Africa.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Middle East and North Africa" code="HSFA13" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1060"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">PLO Accountability Act of 2017

This bill amends the Anti-Terrorism Act of 1987 to authorize the President to waive for up to six months the prohibition against establishment or maintenance of Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO) offices, headquarters, premises, or other facilities within U.S. jurisdiction if the President certifies to Congress that the Palestinians have entered into a final negotiated peace agreement with, and have ceased hostilities against, Israel or that:

 the Palestinians have not, on or after January 1, 2017, obtained state standing in the United Nations or any specialized agency thereof outside an agreement negotiated between Israel and the Palestinians; the Palestinians have officially ceased to be International Criminal Court (ICC) members and have withdrawn from the Rome Statute of the ICC; any ICC investigation against Israel initiated by, or on behalf of, the Palestinians has been withdrawn and terminated; the PLO and the Palestinian Authority (PA) no longer provide financial awards, payments, salaries, or benefits to Palestinians who have committed terrorist attacks, their families, or the families of those who died committing acts of terrorism; and the PLO and the PA have ceased to engage in a pattern of incitement against the United States or Israel.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
