<bill session="115" type="h" number="2296" updated="2017-10-12T21:45:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing CCUS Technology Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing CCUS Technology Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase accountability with respect to Department of Energy carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Advancing CCUS Technology Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000482" joined="2017-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-02">
      <text>Referred to House Science, Space, and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-02">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Power" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing CCUS Technology Act

This bill amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to direct the Department of Energy (DOE)to carry out research and developtechnologyto improve the conversion, use, and storage of carbon dioxide from fossil fuels. It also revises the program of research and commercial application for coal and power systems to require DOE, during each fiscal year after FY2017, to identify cost and performance goals for technologies allowing large-scale demonstration and the continued cost-competitive commercial use of coal.

DOEmust annually evaluateand make recommendations regarding any project it has entered into with a public or privateentityto developcarbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technologies.

DOE must report to Congress, within two years and every three years thereafter, regarding theprojectevaluations it has conductedand the progress it has made in advancing carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technologies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
