<bill session="115" type="h" number="1674" updated="2017-09-28T07:16:01Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Long Island Sound Restoration and Stewardship Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Long Island Sound Restoration and Stewardship Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend and reauthorize certain provisions relating to Long Island Sound restoration and stewardship.</title>
    <title type="display">Long Island Sound Restoration and Stewardship Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2017-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000293" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2017-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2017-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2017-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Power and Oceans" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="675"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Long Island Sound"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Long Island Sound Restoration and Stewardship Act

This bill reauthorizes the Management Conference of the Long Island Sound Study, the Long Island Sound Stewardship Act of 2006, the Long Island Sound Grants, and Long Island Sound Stewardship Grants through FY2023.

The bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to direct the Environmental Protection Agency's (EPA) Office of the Management Conference of the Long Island Sound Study to include in studies on strengthening the implementation of the Comprehensive Conservation and Management Plan for Long Island Sound: (1) environmental impacts on the sound watershed; and (2) planning initiatives that identify areas most suitable for various activities in order to reduce conflicts among uses, reduce adverse environmental impacts, facilitate compatible uses, or preserve critical ecosystem services.

The office must: (1) develop and implement strategies to increase education and awareness about the ecological health and water quality of the sound; and (2) monitor progress toward meeting the goals, actions, and schedules of the plan.

The limit on the federal share for certain grants for projects and studies to help implement the plan is revised by increasing the limit for grants other than citizen involvement and education grants.

A federal agency that owns or occupies real property, or carries out activities, within the sound watershed must: (1) participate in regional and subwatershed planning, protection, and restoration activities; and (2) ensure that the property and activities are consistent with the plan to the maximum extent practicable.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
