<bill session="115" type="s" number="110" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:37Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Coast Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Coast Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Digital Coast Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Digital Coast Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Digital Coast Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Digital Coast Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, to establish a constituent-driven program to provide a digital information platform capable of efficiently integrating coastal data with decision-support tools, training, and best practices and to support collection of priority coastal geospatial data to inform and improve local, State, regional, and Federal capacities to manage the coastal region, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Digital Coast Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2017-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2017-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-01-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-03-30">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune without amendment. With written report No. 115-14.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="25">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 25.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2017-05-25" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3225-3226" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3225-3226" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26T10:02:49-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26T11:06:03-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Geography"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T12:48:57Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate reported version is repeated here.)

Digital Coast Act

(Sec.4)This bill requires the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to establish a constituent-driven Digital Coast program. (This program currently exists under NOAA to provide data, tools, and training that communities use to manage their coastal resources.) The program must: (1) provide an online resource that integrates geospatial data, decision-support tools, training, and best practices to address coastal management issues and needs, and to enhance resilient communities, ecosystem values, and coastal economic growth and development; and (2) provide for the documentation, dissemination, and archiving of the data.

NOAA must focus on filling data needs and gaps for critical coastal management issues and support continued improvement in existing efforts to coordinate the acquisition and integration of key data sets needed for coastal management, and other purposes. NOAA may: (1) enter into financial agreements and collect fees to carry out the program; (2) enter into contracts with private sector entities as may be necessary to collect, process, and provide remote sensing and other geospatial data and products.

Additionally, NOAA may establish publicly available tools that track ocean and Great Lakes economy data for each coastal state.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-14</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
