<bill session="115" type="h" number="1493" updated="2017-07-20T17:26:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ADA Lawsuit Clarification Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ADA Lawsuit Clarification Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to impose notice and a compliance opportunity to be provided before commencement of a private civil action.</title>
    <title type="display">ADA Lawsuit Clarification Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000612"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">ADA Lawsuit Clarification Act of 2017

This bill amends the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to prohibit an aggrieved person from commencing a civil action for discrimination based on the failure to remove a structural barrier to entry into an existing public accommodation unless the owner or operator of such accommodation: (1) is provided a written notice specific enough to identify such barrier; and (2) has either failed, within 60 days after receipt of notice, to provide the aggrieved person with a written description outlining improvements that will be made to remove such barrier or failed, within 120 days after providing the description of improvements, to remove such barrier.

 An owner or operator may not be held civilly or criminally liable for failing to remove a structural barrier before the expiration of a 120-day that begins after the aggrieved person has been provided the description of improvements that will be made.

The Department of Justice must make technical assistance publications relating to compliance with this bill available in all languages commonly used by owners and operators.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
