<bill session="115" type="h" number="366" updated="2017-08-10T13:23:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-06">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">DHS SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">DHS Stop Asset and Vehicle Excess Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">DHS SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">DHS Stop Asset and Vehicle Excess Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Stop Asset and Vehicle Excess Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Stop Asset and Vehicle Excess Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DHS SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DHS SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DHS Stop Asset and Vehicle Excess Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DHS Stop Asset and Vehicle Excess Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS Stop Asset and Vehicle Excess Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS Stop Asset and Vehicle Excess Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Under Secretary for Management of the Department of Homeland Security to make certain improvements in managing the Department's vehicle fleet, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">DHS SAVE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2017-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T15:32:31-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Perry moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T15:32:39-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H788-789" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T15:32:41-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 366.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-01-31T15:39:26-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H788-789" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T15:39:28-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-04-24">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with amendments. With written report No. 115-32.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-04-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="41">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 41.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2017-05-02" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2683-2684" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2683-2684" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-05-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23T16:30:51-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McCaul asked unanimous consent to take from Speaker's Table and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4480" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="pingpong" datetime="2017-05-23T16:31:20-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4480" label="text as House agreed to Senate Amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-05-23T16:31:21-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2017-06-06" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="115-38" type="public" datetime="2017-06-06">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 115-38.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-07T03:59:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on April 24, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

DHS Stop Asset and Vehicle Excess Act or the DHS SAVE Act

 (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to make the Under Secretary for Management of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) responsible for overseeing and managing vehicle fleets throughout DHS, including:

 ensuring that DHS components are in compliance with federal law, executive branch guidance, and DHS policy regarding fleet management and use of vehicles from home to work; developing and distributing a standardized vehicle allocation methodology and fleet management plan; ensuring that components formally document fleet management decisions; and approving component fleet management plans, vehicle leases, and vehicle acquisitions. The bill lists responsibilities of component heads regarding vehicle fleets, including developing and annually submitting to the Under Secretary a vehicle allocation tool and fleet management plan.

The Under Secretary shall:

 collect, on a quarterly basis, information regarding component vehicle fleets; seek to achieve a capability to collect automated information regarding component vehicle fleets; track and monitor component information, and review each component's vehicle allocation tool and fleet management plan, to ensure that component vehicle fleets are the optimal size and are cost effective; provide guidance on how component heads may achieve optimal fleet size; and as part of the annual budget process, review and make determinations regarding annual component requests for vehicle fleet funding. Beginning with FY2019, the Under Secretary and component heads may not approve a vehicle lease, acquisition, or replacement request, no DHS official with vehicle fleet management responsibilities may receive annual performance compensation in pay, and no senior executive service official of DHS whose office has a vehicle fleet may receive access to a car service, if such officials did not comply with vehicle allocation tool and fleet management plan requirements in the prior fiscal year.

The Under Secretary may determine the feasibility of operating a vehicle motor pool to permit components to share vehicles to reduce the number of excess DHS vehicles.

(Sec. 3) The Inspector General of DHS shall: (1) conduct a review of implementation of vehicle allocation tool and fleet management plan requirements for FY2019, which shall include analysis of the effectiveness of such requirements with respect to cost avoidance, savings realized, and component operations; and (2) upon request, provide to specified congressional committees information regarding such review.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-32</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
