<bill session="115" type="h" number="2399" updated="2017-09-11T03:03:01Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LEAP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LEAP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leveraging and Energizing America's Apprenticeship Programs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leveraging and Energizing America&#8217;s Apprenticeship Programs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow employers a credit against income tax for employees who participate in qualified apprenticeship programs.</title>
    <title type="display">LEAP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000619"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2017-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2017-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2017-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001193" joined="2017-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-08">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="393"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3628"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3061"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government Publishing Office (GPO)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Leveraging and Energizing America's Apprenticeship Programs Act or the LEAP Act

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow employers a business-related tax credit of $1,500 for hiring&#160;an apprenticeship employee who has not attained age 25&#160;at the close of the taxable year or $1,000 for an apprenticeship employee who has attained age 25. The bill allows such credit for no more than&#160;two taxable years with respect to any apprenticeship employee. An "apprenticeship employee" is an employee who is employed in an officially-recognized apprenticeable occupation pursuant to an apprentice agreement registered with the Office of Apprenticeship of the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor or a state apprenticeship agency.

 The Office of Management and Budget must coordinate with federal departments and independent agencies to: (1) determine which government publications could be available on government websites and no longer printed, (2) devise a strategy to reduce overall government printing costs over the 10-year period beginning with FY2016, (3) establish government-wide guidelines on employee printing, and (4) issue guidelines for publicly disclosing information about the publication of government documents.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
