<bill session="115" type="sr" number="180" updated="2017-07-20T17:26:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution condemning the violence against peaceful protesters outside the Turkish Ambassador's residence on May 16, 2017, and calling for the perpetrators to be brought to justice and measures to be taken to prevent similar incidents in the future.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution condemning the violence against peaceful protesters outside the Turkish Ambassador's residence on May 16, 2017, and calling for the perpetrators to be brought to justice and measures to be taken to prevent similar incidents in the future.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3223" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="identical" number="354"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the rights to peacefully assemble and freely express one's views are essential to American democracy; and (2) the United States should take steps to strengthen free press and civil society freedoms in countries such as Turkey.

Calls for: (1) any Turkish security official who directed or participated in efforts by Turkish security forces to suppress peaceful protests outside of the Turkish Ambassador's residence in Washington, DC on May 16, 2017, to be charged and prosecuted under U.S. law; (2) the Secret Service and the Diplomatic Security Service of the Department of State to review such incident and confirm with the Turkish National Police the standards expected by visiting security details; (3) the State Department to request the waiver of immunity of any Turkish security detail official who engaged in assault in the United States prior to such individual's release from custody; and (4) the State Department to review its security procedures to mitigate the likelihood of such an incident in the future.

Declares that U.S. respect for free speech requires U.S. officials to speak out against such incidents.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
