<bill session="115" type="h" number="1125" updated="2017-08-07T20:15:26Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VISA Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VISA Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Visa Investigation and Social Media Activity Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Visa Investigation and Social Media Activity Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for new procedures pertaining to the processing of petitions and applications for immigrant or nonimmigrant visas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">VISA Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001299"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Counterterrorism and Intelligence" code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Visa Investigation and Social Media Activity Act of 2017 or the VISA Act of 2017

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to prohibit a petition or application filed with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) or with a consular officer for the issuance of a visa or the admission of an alien from being approved unless a background check to determine whether the alien is a national security threat or is otherwise ineligible for such visa or admission is completed for: (1) the petitioner or applicant, and (2) each beneficiary or derivative of the petition or application.

Such background check shall include a review of the alien's publicly available interactions on, and posting of material to, the Internet (including social media services).

An applicant must provide an English translation of his or her documentation.

No petition or application for any immigration benefit, except for work authorization, may be approved for an alien who is at least 11 years old unless DHS conducts an in-person interview with such alien.

DHS shall begin implementation of an analytics software plan to detect fraud in immigration benefits applications and petitions and to ensure that an applicant or petitioner does not pose a national security threat.

The bill requires the deployment of DHS employees to all visa-issuing embassies and consulates.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
