<bill session="115" type="s" number="1181" updated="2017-09-22T19:45:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Good Samaritan Search and Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Good Samaritan Search and Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior and Secretary of Agriculture to expedite access to certain Federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of each Secretary for good Samaritan search-and-recovery missions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Good Samaritan Search and Recovery Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2017-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3668"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Good Samaritan Search and Recovery Act 

 This bill directs the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to implement a process to provide eligible organizations and individuals expedited access to federal land to conduct good Samaritan search-and-recovery missions, which are searches for one or more missing individuals believed to be deceased at the time that the search is initiated.

The bill sets forth procedures for the approval or denial of requests made by eligible organizations or individuals to carry out a good Samaritan search-and-recovery mission.

Interior and USDA shall develop search-and-recovery focused partnerships with search-and-recovery organizations to coordinate good Samaritan search-and-recovery missions, and expedite and accelerate mission efforts for missing individuals.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
