<bill session="115" type="h" number="2722" updated="2017-09-06T07:13:42Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SWINE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Swine Waste Infrastructure and Natural Environment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Swine Waste Infrastructure and Natural Environment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage the development, certification, and adoption of environmentally sustainable swine waste disposal technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SWINE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000523"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Trade" code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Swine Waste Infrastructure and Natural Environment Act or the SWINE Act 

This bill establishes a program to certify environmentally sustainable swine waste disposal technologies and authorizes related tax credits and grants.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) must certify technologies that:

 eliminate animal discharge into surface waters and groundwater through direct discharge, seepage, or runoff; substantially eliminate atmospheric emissions of ammonia from swine waste; substantially eliminate the emission of odor from swine waste that is detectable beyond the boundaries of the parcel or tract of land on which the swine farm is located; substantially eliminate the release of disease-transmitting vectors and airborne pathogens from swine waste; substantially eliminate nutrient and heavy metal contamination of soil and groundwater from swine waste; and are cost-effective. States may not issue permits, pursuant to any federal law, to a swine farm that is a concentrated animal feeding operation unless the farm disposes of swine waste using a certified technology.

The bill amends several agricultural laws to:

 require USDA to make competitive grants for activities to identify, evaluate, and demonstrate environmentally superior swine waste management technologies; permit the Pork Promotion Board to use its funding for activities related to the grants; and make the installation and maintenance of a certified technology on a swine farm eligible for the Environmental Quality Incentives Program. The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow tax credits for: (1) the installation of a certified swine waste disposal technology, and (2) the disposal of swine waste using certified technology.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
