<bill session="115" type="s" number="651" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:42Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Contractor Accountability and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Contractor Accountability and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the posting online of certain government contracts.</title>
    <title type="display">Contractor Accountability and Transparency Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2017-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Contractor Accountability and Transparency Act of 2017

This bill amends the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 to require the posting online of any contract, subcontract, purchase order, task order, or delivery order for the procurement of property or services with a value greater than the simplified acquisition threshold (covered contract).

The website established pursuant to such Act, containing information on each federal award of federal financial assistance and expenditures, shall include a machine readable, searchable copy of each covered contract entered into by a federal agency after the date of this bill's enactment.

A contractor may request to redact any national security sensitive or classified information or trade secrets or other proprietary information from such a contract. The federal contracting official shall determine the extent to which redaction is appropriate in accordance with Office of Management and Budget guidance. Any information required to be made available to the public under the Freedom of Information Act may not be redacted.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
