<bill session="115" type="h" number="1365" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:04Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-24T11:12:05-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-24T11:12:05-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require certain acquisition innovation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2017-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 115-48.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-20" calendar="Union" number="28">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 28.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22T12:51:11-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Donovan moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22T12:51:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2307-2308" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22T12:51:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1365.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22T12:58:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Donovan objected to the Yea - Nay vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-24T11:03:47-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2392" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="193" datetime="2017-03-24T11:12:05-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 424 - 0 (Roll no. 193).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2307" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-03-24T11:12:06-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-24T12:27:40Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on March 20, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) Under Secretary for Management to:

 designate an individual within DHS to manage DHS acquisition innovation efforts, test emerging acquisition best practicess, develop and distribute best practices and lessons learned regarding acquisition innovations, establish metrics to measure the effectiveness of acquisition innovation efforts, and determine impacts of acquisition innovation efforts on the private sector by obtaining feedback from it and incorporating such feedback into future acquisition innovation efforts. The bill requires DHS, by 90 days after it submits the annual budget justification for DHS for each of FY2018-FY2022, to provide information to specified congressional committees on:

 emerging acquisition best practices that were tested within DHS, efforts to distribute best practices and lessons learned within DHS, utilization of best practices by DHS components, performance as measured by the metrics established under this bill, outcomes of efforts to distribute best practices and lessons learned within DHS, impacts of the utilization of innovative acquisition mechanisms by DHS on the private sector, the criteria used to identify specific acquisition programs or activities to be included in acquisition innovation efforts and the outcomes of such programs or activities, and recommendations to enhance acquisition innovation in DHS.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-48</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
