<bill session="115" type="h" number="2824" updated="2017-10-11T04:29:24Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-26T16:05:36-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-09-26T16:05:36-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing Opportunity through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing Opportunity through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Increasing Opportunity and Success for Children and Parents through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Increasing Opportunity and Success for Children and Parents through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Increasing Opportunity and Success for Children and Parents through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Control Unlawful Fugitive Felons Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Control Unlawful Fugitive Felons Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Increasing Opportunity and Success for Children and Parents through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title V of the Social Security Act to extend the Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting Program.</title>
    <title type="display">Increasing Opportunity and Success for Children and Parents through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001172"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000184" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2017-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000462" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2017-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-09-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 15.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-21">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 115-315, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-09-21" calendar="Union" number="225">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 225.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Ways and Means, H. Rept. 115-315, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25T18:43:27-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 533 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2824 and H.R. 2792. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. The resolution provides a structured rule for H.R. 2824, and closed rule for H.R. 2792. It provides for 1 hour of general debate for both bills.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T13:46:48-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 533.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7506-7514" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T13:46:53-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2824 and H.R. 2792. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. The resolution provides a structured rule for H.R. 2824, and closed rule for H.R. 2792. It provides for 1 hour of general debate for both bills.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T13:47:22-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 533 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T13:47:23-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Martha Roby to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T13:48:07-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2824.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T14:27:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 533, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (NE) amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T14:32:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 533, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pascrell amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T14:40:04-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pascrell amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Pascrell demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T14:40:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 533, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DelBene amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T14:44:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 533, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Murphy (FL) amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T14:50:24-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NE) moved that the Committee now rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T14:50:44-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T14:50:56-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2824 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T15:14:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7514-7517" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T15:15:20-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T15:15:49-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of an amendment which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T15:42:15-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2824.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T15:42:52-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T15:43:17-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T15:43:56-04:00">
      <text>Ms. DelBene moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7515" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T15:44:14-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DelBene motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with the following amendment to strike the two additional requirements in the underlying bill to allow for a clean reauthorization of the Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting program (MIECHV).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T15:50:11-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T15:59:39-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 191 - 232 (Roll no. 536).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="537" datetime="2017-09-26T16:05:36-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 214 - 209 (Roll no. 537).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7510-7511" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26T16:05:38-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Human Resources" code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="procedurally-related" number="533"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2792"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1829"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h450"/>
    <amendment number="h449"/>
    <amendment number="h448"/>
    <amendment number="h447"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-06-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Increasing Opportunity through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act

This bill amends title V (Maternal and Child Health Services) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to reauthorize&#160;through FY2022, and otherwise revise,&#160;the Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting Program.

 Under current law,&#160;grantees were required,&#160;after&#160;three years&#160;of program implementation, to demonstrate improvement in specified benchmark areas. The bill requires&#160;grantees&#160;to continue, in subsequent years,&#160;to track and demonstrate improvement in applicable benchmark areas. A&#160;grantee that fails to do so&#160;must develop and implement a corrective action plan, subject to approval by&#160;the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). HHS&#160;shall terminate a&#160;program grant made to&#160;a grantee&#160;that implements such a plan but continues to fail to demonstrate improvement.

As a condition&#160;for receiving grant funds under the program, a state must conduct a statewide needs assessment by&#160;October 1, 2019, and at least once every five years thereafter.

A grantee may use&#160;program grant funds&#160;to support&#160;a "pay-for-outcomes initiative"&#160;(a performance-based grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, awarded by a public entity, in which a commitment is made to pay for improved outcomes that result in social&#160;benefit and&#160;public-sector cost savings).

Grantees must provide matching funds under the program beginning in FY2020.

HHS must designate data-exchange standards applicable to the program.

The bill also amends title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) under the SSAct to&#160;prohibit&#160;the payment of SSI&#160;benefits to an individual who is subject to an arrest warrant for: (1)&#160;committing, or attempting to commit, a felony; or (2) violating a condition of parole or probation.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-315</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-315</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
