<bill session="115" type="h" number="1000" updated="2017-05-18T07:16:03Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Humphrey-Hawkins 21st Century Full Employment and Training Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jobs for All Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the National Full Employment Trust Fund to create employment opportunities for the unemployed.</title>
    <title type="display">Jobs for All Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2017-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000127" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000248" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2017-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2017-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-09">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-09">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Humphrey-Hawkins 21st Century Full Employment and Training Act of 2017 or the Jobs for All Act

 This bill directs the Department of Labor to establish a Full Employment National Trust Fund with two separate accounts for: (1) Employment Opportunity Grants to states, Indian tribes, local governments, publicly-funded elementary and secondary educational institutions, educational institutions in the Federal Work-Study Program, and tax-exempt non-profit organizations for job-creating activities in communities whose economy is not at a level of full employment; and (2) Workforce Investment programs.

Labor is required, through studies it conducts or through independent studies, to:

 review the effectiveness of job training and job creation programs under this bill, disseminate information concerning best practices for achieving the bill's goals, and acquire a better understanding of such programs' true cost. Arbitration procedures are established for resolution of disputes for grant recipients. Labor is required to post a whistleblower hotline on its website for the public to report noncompliance with the bill's requirements.

 Labor must convene an annual national employment conference to discuss this bill's role in addressing all aspects of unemployment problems, the sharing of best practices in addressing them, and the discussion of problems in the administration of this bill.

The Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act is amended to revise member composition requirements for state and local workforce development boards to include at least 25% of the chief executive officers of minority-serving, community-based organizations.

The Internal Revenue Code is amended to impose a tax on the transfer of ownership in certain covered securities transactions, payable by trading facilities or brokers that deal in such transactions. A penalty is imposed against persons who fail to include such transactions on any tax return or statement.

Labor shall suspend new hiring of unemployed persons and freeze the hourly wages paid for jobs funded under this bill whenever it is determined that:

 the unemployment rate is less than 4%, and the consumer price index (inflation) is greater than 3%.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
