<bill session="115" type="h" number="2231" updated="2017-07-29T15:15:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a joint commission on North Korea, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To establish a joint commission on North Korea, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000617"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2017-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2017-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2017-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2017-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-28">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" code="HSFA05" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill authorizes the Department of State to seek to establish a joint commission with countries in the Indo-Asia Pacific region to:

 support professional dialogues to coordinate the detection of North Korean violations of United Nations Security Council resolutions, develop responses, and enhance monitoring of nuclear weapons proliferation capabilities; coordinate sub-cabinet level political discussions on contingency responses to such violations; facilitate technical discussions among the Departments of State, Defense (DOD), Energy, and the Treasury, the Intelligence Community, and their counterparts in countries in the region on technical aspects of North Korea's nuclear program and accompanying U.S. sanctions; coordinate information sharing among the intelligence services of the participating countries to identify immediate threats; and create guidelines for coordinating multilateral direct action against shared threats. The bill declares that it is U.S. policy: (1) to continue to maintain robust and multifaceted diplomatic engagement in the region, to include promoting U.S. values and economic interests and a strong military posture; and (2) that diplomacy, development, and defense should be used to enhance U.S. national security, promote U.S. interests, reassure U.S. allies, deter aggression, and respond swiftly to crises.

DOD may conduct routine and enhanced ports of call with key allies in the region.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
