<bill session="115" type="h" number="1638" updated="2017-06-19T21:30:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iranian Leadership Asset Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iranian Leadership Asset Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees on the estimated total assets under direct or indirect control by certain senior Iranian leaders and other figures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Iranian Leadership Asset Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000611"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and North Africa.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Middle East and North Africa" code="HSFA13" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Iranian Leadership Asset Transparency Act

This bill requires the Department of the Treasury, in furtherance of efforts to prevent the financing of terrorism, money laundering, or related illicit finance and to make financial institutions' required compliance with remaining sanctions more easily understood, to submit within 270 days and annually thereafter for the next two years a report regarding:

 the funds or assets held in U.S. and foreign financial institutions that are directly or indirectly controlled by specified Iranian officials; any equity stake such official has in an entity on Treasury's list of Specially Designated Nationals or in any other sanctioned entity; how such funds, assets, or equity interests were acquired and used; new methods used to evade anti-money laundering and related laws, including recommendations to improve techniques to combat illicit uses of the U.S. financial system by each such official. recommendations for revising U.S. economic sanctions against Iran to prevent Iranian officials from using funds or assets to develop and procure ballistic missile technology; how Treasury assesses the effectiveness of U.S. economic sanctions against Iran; and recommendations for improving Treasury's ability to develop and enforce additional economic sanctions against Iran if so ordered by the President. The unclassified portion of the report shall be made available to the public and posted on Treasury's website in downloadable English, Farsi, Arabic, and Azeri versions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
