<bill session="115" type="s" number="592" updated="2017-07-20T16:56:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to support meeting the increasing needs of the United States for a cybersecurity and information assurance workforce by reinvigorating and modifying the Information Assurance Scholarship Program of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2017-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1745" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1609"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program Act of 2017

This bill designates the existing Department of Defense (DOD) information assurance scholarship and grant program as the Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program to provide financial assistance (with consideration given to whether the recipient is, or the pursuit of the degree is at, a Center of Academic Excellence in Information Assurance Education designated by the National Security Agency) to: (1) persons pursuing information assurance degrees or certifications at institutions of higher education in exchange for an agreement to serve on active duty in the armed forces or as a DOD employee for a designated period; and (2) institutions of higher education to support development of faculty, curriculum, laboratories, and research for information assurance disciplines.

Not less than 5% of the amounts available for scholarship financial assistance must be available for the pursuit of associate degrees.

DOD must submit a plan for reinvigorating the program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
