<bill session="115" type="s" number="1267" updated="2017-09-22T12:43:17Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Mineral Revenue Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Mineral Revenue Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Mineral Leasing Act to require the Secretary of the Interior to convey to a State all right, title, and interest in and to a percentage of the amount of royalties and other amounts required to be paid to the State under that Act with respect to public land and deposits in the State, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">State Mineral Revenue Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2017-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2661"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">State Mineral Revenue Protection Act

This bill amends the Mineral Leasing Act to provide a mechanism for states to receive their entitled percentage of sales, bonuses, royalties, and rentals for all public land or deposits located in the state.

The bill eliminates the 2% fee that the federal government currently deducts from a state's entitled share to cover administrative or other costs.

On request of a state, the Department of the Interior must convey to the state their entitled percentage of all right, title, and interest for all public land or deposits located in the state.Interior must provide prompt notice of any such conveyance and the duty of the leaseholder to make direct payments to the state.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
