<bill session="115" type="sr" number="85" updated="2017-05-16T18:52:04Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution calling on the Government of Iran to fulfill repeated promises of assistance in the case of Robert Levinson, the longest held United States civilian in our Nation's history.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution calling on the Government of Iran to fulfill repeated promises of assistance in the case of Robert Levinson, the longest held United States civilian in our Nation's history.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1749-1750" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="185"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Recognizes that March 9, 2017, marks 10 years since the disappearance of Robert Levinson from Kish Island, Iran, and that Levinson is the longest held U.S. civilian in U.S. history. Notes that repeated pledges by Iranian officials to provide their government's assistance have not led to any meaningful progress in locating or returning him.

 Urges the government of Iran to take meaningful steps towards fulfilling its promises to assist in locating and returning Levinson, including immediately providing all information from all entities of such government regarding his disappearance.

 Urges the President and U.S. allies to continue to press the Iranian government to locate and return Levinson, notwithstanding disagreements with Iran on a broad array of issues. Notes that further delay in locating and returning Levinson remains a significant obstacle to improving U.S.-Iran relations.

 Expresses sympathy to Levinson's family and expresses hope that their ordeal can be brought to an end in the near future.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
