<bill session="115" type="h" number="2214" updated="2017-09-28T16:30:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Government Shutdown Accountability and Economic Report Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Government Shutdown Accountability and Economic Report Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the payment of salary to Members of Congress in the event of a Government shutdown, to direct the Congressional Budget Office to submit daily reports during the period in which a Government shutdown is in effect on the effects of the shutdown on the economy and the costs of the shutdown to taxpayers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Government Shutdown Accountability and Economic Report Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2017-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2017-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1789"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1794"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Government Shutdown Accountability and Economic Report Act of 2017

 This bill prohibits Members of Congress from being paid salaries during a pay period in which a government shutdown is in effect after the regularly scheduled general election for federal office held in November 2018.

For the purpose of this bill, a government shutdown is considered to be in effect if there is a lapse in appropriations for any federal agency or department as a result of a failure to enact a regular appropriations bill or continuing resolution.

If a government shutdown occurs during the 115th Congress, congressional salaries must be withheld during the shutdown and released to Members of Congress at the end of the Congress, subject to an exception for any day during the 115th Congress which occurs after the date of the regularly scheduled general election for federal office held in November 2018.

During a government shutdown, the Congressional Budget Office must submit specified reports to Congress regarding the costs and economic effects of the shutdown.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
