<bill session="115" type="h" number="2591" updated="2017-10-04T07:16:05Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing the Pittman-Robertson Fund for Tomorrow's Needs Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing the Pittman-Robertson Fund for Tomorrow&#8217;s Needs Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act to modernize the funding of wildlife conservation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Modernizing the Pittman-Robertson Fund for Tomorrow's Needs Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2017-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000560" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001072" joined="2017-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000585" joined="2017-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2017-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000593" joined="2017-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2017-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2017-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000806" joined="2017-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1613"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Modernizing the Pittman-Robertson Fund for Tomorrow's Needs Act of 2017

This bill amends the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act to make it one of the purposes of the Act to provide financial and technical assistance to the states for the promotion of hunting and recreational shooting.

The bill also prescribes a formula for the allocation of funds apportioned to a state that may be used for any activity or project to recruit or retain hunters and recreational shooters.

In addition to other uses authorized under this bill, amounts apportioned to the states from any taxes on pistols, revolvers, bows, and arrows may be used for hunter recruitment and recreational shooter recruitment.

The funds apportioned to a state for wildlife restoration management may be used for related public relations.

If a state has not used all of the tax revenues apportioned to it for firearm and bow hunter education and safety program grants, it may use its remaining apportioned funds for the enhancement of hunter recruitment and recreational shooter recruitment.

Up to $5 million of the revenues covered into the wildlife restoration fund in the Treasury from any tax imposed for a fiscal year on the sale of certain bows, arrows, and archery equipment shall be available to the Department of the Interior exclusively for making hunter recruitment and recreational shooter recruitment grants that promote a national hunting and shooting sport recruitment program, including related communication and outreach activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
