<bill session="115" type="s" number="996" updated="2017-09-23T04:31:33Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Higher Education Affordability Necessary to Compete Economically Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Higher Education Affordability Necessary to Compete Economically Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Middle Class CHANCE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Middle Class CHANCE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve college affordability.</title>
    <title type="display">Middle Class CHANCE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2260"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Creating Higher Education Affordability Necessary to Compete Economically Act or the Middle Class CHANCE Act This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify provisions related to the Federal Pell Grant program.

Specifically, it increases the maximum Federal Pell Grant award for academic year 2018-2019 and adjusts it in subsequent award years to account for changes in the Consumer Price Index.

The bill also increases from one to two the number of Pell Grants an eligible student may receive in a single award year (i.e., it restores year-round Pell Grants). A student's total amount of Pell Grants must not exceed 150% of the maximum Pell Grant for that award year. Also, any period during which a student receives an additional Pell Grant counts toward that student's lifetime Pell Grant eligibility period.

Finally, the bill increases from 12 to 15 semesters a student's lifetime Pell Grant eligibility period.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
