<bill session="115" type="s" number="1583" updated="2017-09-22T12:43:17Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legislative Performance Review Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legislative Performance Review Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the period of authorization of new budget authority provided in appropriation Acts, to require analysis, appraisal, and evaluation of existing programs for which continued new budget authority is proposed to be authorized by committees of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Legislative Performance Review Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2017-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001202" joined="2017-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Legislative Performance Review Act of 2017

This bill limits the duration of authorizations of appropriations, requires programs with expired authorizations to be terminated, and establishes reporting requirements.

The bill prohibits Congress from considering legislation that: (1) authorizes appropriations for more than four years, or (2) authorizes the enactment of an unlimited amount of appropriations for any purpose.

If Congress determines that an authorization for more than four years is necessary to accomplish the purposes of an authorization, it may waive the time limit by considering a waiver resolution using expedited legislative procedures.

Congressional committees that report legislation authorizing appropriations must include in committee reports: (1) an analysis, appraisal, and evaluation of existing programs for which appropriations are authorized; and (2) specified details regarding the purpose and need for new programs for which appropriations are authorized.

Federal agencies must implement a two-year plan to terminate programs with expired authorizations.

The bill establishes new points of order against legislation that provides appropriations that are either unauthorized or are pursuant to authorizations that violate the time limits and other requirements established by this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
