<bill session="115" type="s" number="392" updated="2017-08-10T13:24:04Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">400 Years of African-American History Commission Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">400 Years of African-American History Commission Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">400 Years of African-American History Commission Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">400 Years of African-American History Commission Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the 400 Years of African-American History Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">400 Years of African-American History Commission Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2017-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1219" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 115-63.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="81">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 81.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1242"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1460"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-16T12:29:29Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

400 Years of African-American History Commission Act

(Sec. 3) This bill establishes the 400 Years of African-American History Commission to develop and carry out activities throughout the United States to commemorate the 400th anniversary of the arrival of Africans in the English colonies at Point Comfort, Virginia, in 1619.

The commission must:

 plan programs to acknowledge the impact that slavery and laws that enforced racial discrimination had on the United States; encourage civic, patriotic, historical, educational, artistic, religious, and economic organizations to organize and participate in anniversary activities; assist states, localities, and nonprofit organizations to further the commemoration; and coordinate for the public scholarly research on the arrival of Africans in the United States and their contributions to this country. (Sec. 5) The commission may provide: (1) grants to communities and nonprofit organizations for the development of programs; (2) grants to research and scholarly organizations to research, publish, or distribute information relating to the arrival of Africans in the United States; and (3) technical assistance to states, localities, and nonprofit organizations to further the commemoration.

(Sec. 7) The commission must prepare a strategic plan and submit a final report to Congress that contains a summary of its activities, an accounting of its received and expended funds, and its recommendations.

(Sec. 9) The commission shall terminate on July 1, 2020.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-63</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
