<bill session="115" type="s" number="671" updated="2017-07-27T04:51:41Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agriculture Students EARN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agriculture Students EARN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agriculture Students Encourage, Acknowledge, Reward, Nurture Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agriculture Students Encourage, Acknowledge, Reward, Nurture Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from gross income certain amounts realized on the disposition of property raised or produced by a student farmer, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Agriculture Students Encourage, Acknowledge, Reward, Nurture Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2017-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2017-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1626"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Agriculture Students EARN Act or the Agriculture Students Encourage, Acknowledge, Reward, Nurture Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from the gross income of a student farmer up to $5,000 of the gain from the sale or exchange of personal property (including livestock, crops, and agricultural mechanics or shop products) produced or raised by the student farmer.

A student farmer is an individual who is under 19 years of age and is enrolled in: (1) a program established by the National FFA Organization; (2) a 4-H Club or other program established by 4-H; or (3) a student agriculture program that is under the direction or guidance of an agricultural educator, advisor, or club leader.

To qualify for the exclusion, the production and sale or exchange of the property must be supervised by one of the specified agriculture programs. The sale or exchange must also occur during qualified public entertainment or convention and trade show activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
