<bill session="115" type="s" number="268" updated="2017-06-19T21:00:34Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investing in Student Success Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investing in Student Success Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide the legal framework necessary for the growth of innovative private financing options for students to fund postsecondary education, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Investing in Student Success Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2017-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-01T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Investing in Student Success Act of 2017

This bill authorizes an individual (i.e., a student) and another person (i.e., an investor) to enter an income-share agreement (ISA) in which the student agrees to pay a percentage of future income, for a specified period of time, in exchange for funds to pay for postsecondary education, workforce development, or other purposes.

An ISA that complies with specified terms and conditions and meets certain disclosure requirements is a valid, binding, and enforceable contract and is not subject to state laws that limit interest rates or regulate assignments of future income.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to include an ISA as a qualified education loan (a qualified education loan is not dischargeable in bankruptcy), but it prohibits a tax deduction for interest paid on an ISA (interest paid on a qualified education loan is tax deductible).

Payments to a student under an ISA are not includible as: (1) gross income for tax purposes, or (2) income or assets for federal financial aid eligibility purposes under the Higher Education Act of 1965.

The bill amends the Investment Company Act of 1940 to exclude as an investment company any person whose business substantially consists of making ISAs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
