<bill session="115" type="h" number="71" updated="2017-06-19T20:15:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-04T12:47:30-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-01-04T12:47:30-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide taxpayers with an annual report disclosing the cost and performance of Government programs and areas of duplication among them, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000798"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000374" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000460" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001071" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001058" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000174" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000584" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000462" joined="2017-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000475" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000063" joined="2017-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2017-01-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04T12:38:04-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04T12:38:26-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H63-65" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04T12:38:29-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 71.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-01-04T12:47:30-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H63-64" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04T12:47:31-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="317"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-04T14:37:54Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act

(Sec. 2) This bill requires that the website of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) include a program inventory that identifies each program of the federal government for which there is more than $1 million in annual budget authority. Such inventory shall include: (1) any activity that is commonly referred to as a program by a federal agency, and (2) any activity that is referenced in law as a program after June 30, 2019.

For programs identified in such inventory for which there is more than $1 million and not more than $10 million in annual budget authority (smaller programs), the inventory must include:

 an identification of the program activities that are aggregated, disaggregated, or consolidated as part of identifying programs; for each such program activity, the amount of funding for the current fiscal year and the previous two fiscal years; an identification of the statutes that authorize the program and any major regulations specific to the program; a description of the individuals served by a program and beneficiaries who received financial assistance under a program for the most recent fiscal year; and links to any evaluation, assessment, or program performance reviews by the agency, an Inspector General, or the Government Accountability Office released during the preceding five years. For programs identified in such inventory for which there is more than $10 million in annual budget authority (larger programs), the inventory must include:

 an identification of the program activities that are aggregated, disaggregated, or consolidated as part of identifying programs; for each program activity, the amount of funding for the current fiscal year and the previous two fiscal years; an estimate of the amount of funding for the program; an identification of the statutes that authorize the program and any major regulations specific to the program; a description and estimate of the number of individuals served by a program and beneficiaries who received financial assistance under a program for the most recent fiscal year; a description of the federal employees who administer the program and other individuals whose salary is paid in full or in part by the federal government through a grant, contract, cooperative agreement, or another form of financial award or assistance; links to any evaluation, assessment, or program performance reviews by the agency, an Inspector General, or the Government Accountability Office released during the preceding five years; and financial and other information for each program activity required to be reported under the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006. The OMB shall: (1) archive and preserve the information included in the program inventory; and (2) not later than February 1 of each fiscal year, publish on a public website the total amount of undisbursed grant funding remaining in grant accounts for which the period of availability to the grantee has expired.

(Sec. 3) The bill requires the OMB, not later than June 30, 2018, to: (1) prescribe guidance to implement this Act, and (2) issue guidance to assist agencies in identifying how the program activities used in budget or appropriations accounts correspond with programs identified in the program inventory required by this Act. The OMB may: (1) issue guidance to agencies to ensure that programs are presented at a similar level of detail across agencies and are not duplicative or overlapping; (2) exempt from the requirements of this Act, based on an analysis of the costs of implementation, agencies that are not required to have a chief financial officer and that have not more than $10 million in budget authority; and (3) extend the Act's implementation deadline by not more than one year.

Implementation of the requirements in this bill must be completed not later than June 30, 2019.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
