<bill session="115" type="h" number="2667" updated="2017-07-18T20:15:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Cruise Missile Reconsideration Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Cruise Missile Reconsideration Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To restrict the use of funds for the long-range standoff weapon until the Secretary of Defense completes a Nuclear Posture Review that includes an assessment of the capabilities and effects of the use of the long-range standoff weapon, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Nuclear Cruise Missile Reconsideration Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E722"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Strategic Forces" code="HSAS29" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="574"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Nuclear Cruise Missile Reconsideration Act of 2017

This bill prohibits the obligation or expenditure of more than specified amounts by the Department of Defense (DOD) on development of the long-range standoff weapon or any other nuclear-capable air-launched cruise missile, or by the Department of Energy on the life extension program for the W80-4 warhead, until DOD submits to specified congressional committees a Nuclear Posture Review that includes an assessment of:

 the anticipated capabilities of the long-range standoff weapon to hold targets at risk beyond other already existing and planned nuclear-capable delivery systems; the anticipated ability of such weapon to elude adversary integrated air and missile defenses compared to the B-21 bomber; and the anticipated effect of such weapon on strategic stability relative to other nuclear-armed countries, on the offensive nuclear weapons capabilities and programs of other nuclear-armed countries, on the response of other nuclear-armed countries to proposals to decrease or halt the growth of their nuclear stockpiles, and on the threshold for the use of nuclear weapons.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
