<bill session="115" type="h" number="1914" updated="2017-09-05T15:30:24Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Performance Royalty Owners of Music Opportunity To Earn Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Performance Royalty Owners of Music Opportunity To Earn Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROMOTE Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROMOTE Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 17, United States Code, to grant owners of copyright in sound recordings the exclusive right to prohibit the broadcast transmission of the sound recordings by means of terrestrial radio stations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">PROMOTE Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2017-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-05T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Performance Royalty Owners of Music Opportunity To Earn Act of 2017 or the PROMOTE Act of 2017

This bill amends federal copyright law to provide copyright owners the exclusive right to prohibit performance of a sound recording publicly by a broadcast transmission of a terrestrial AM/FM radio station. Exceptions are provided that allow terrestrial AM/FM radio broadcasts of a sound recording without the copyright owner's permission if: (1) a terrestrial AM/FM radio station pays royalties identical to those paid under the statutory license rates determined by Copyright Royalty Judges for eligible nonsubscription transmission services that apply to digital Internet radio streaming and webcasts; (2) the broadcast is of a religious service, by an educational terrestrial radio station, or by a low-power FM radio station; or (3) the broadcast is an incidental use. (Under current law, the exclusive right for the public performance of sound recordings extends only to digital audio transmissions, such as Internet and satellite radio broadcasts.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
