<bill session="115" type="s" number="1243" updated="2017-09-29T16:58:39Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">E-STOP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Educating Servicemembers in Training on Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Educating Ser&#173;vice&#173;mem&#173;bers in Training on Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require sexual assault prevention and response training for all individuals enlisted in the Armed Forces under a delayed entry program.</title>
    <title type="display">E-STOP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Educating Servicemembers in Training on Prevention Act or E-STOP Act

This bill directs the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Department of Homeland Security (with respect to matters concerning the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service of the Navy) to provide training on sexual assault prevention and response to individuals enlisted in the Armed Forces under a delayed entry program.

A "delayed entry program" includes:

 the Future Soldiers Program of the Army, the Delayed Entry Program of the Navy and the Marine Corps, the Air Force's program for the delayed entry of enlistees into the Air Force, and the Coast Guard's program for the delayed entry of enlistees into the Coast Guard. Such training must: (1) be completed before the individual begins basic training or initial active duty for training in the Armed Forces, (2) meet such requirements as the Department of Defense establishes, and (3) be uniform across the Armed Forces.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the training should be provided through in-person instruction and include instruction on the proper use of social media.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
