<bill session="115" type="h" number="1064" updated="2017-06-19T21:00:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health Care Provider Retention Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health Care Provider Retention Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize an individual who is transitioning from receiving treatment furnished by the Secretary of Defense to treatment furnished by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to continue receiving treatment from such individual's mental health care provider of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Mental Health Care Provider Retention Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2017-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2017-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Mental Health Care Provider Retention Act of 2017

This bill allows an individual who has been diagnosed with a mental health condition and who is transitioning from receiving treatment from the Department of Defense to receiving treatment from in the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to elect to continue receiving treatment from such individual's DOD mental health provider.

Such individual shall receive the same level of priority as members of the Armed Forces at the facility at which the individual has elected to continue treatment. The VA shall reimburse DOD for rendered services that otherwise would have been furnished by the VA.

If the DOD mental health care provider departs the facility at which the covered individual is receiving treatment, such individual may elect to obtain the services of: (1) a different mental health care provider at the same facility, or (2) a VA mental health care provider.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
