<bill session="115" type="s" number="144" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:27Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promise Zone Job Creation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promise Zone Job Creation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the establishment of Promise Zones.</title>
    <title type="display">Promise Zone Job Creation Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2017-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promise Zone Job Creation Act of 2017

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to direct the Departments of Housing and Urban Development and Agriculture, acting jointly, to designate, before January 1, 2019, not more than 40 areas as Promise Zones for purposes of priority consideration in federal grant programs and initiatives. Twelve of such areas shall be outside of a metropolitan statistical area or shall be determined to be rural areas.

A "Promise Zone" is any area with a&#160;continuous boundary and a&#160;population of not more than&#160;200,000 that is nominated by one or more local governments or Indian tribes and designated on the basis of unemployment rates, poverty rates, vacancy rates, crime rates, household income, home ownership, labor force participation, and educational attainment. An application for designation as a Promise Zone shall include a competitiveness plan that addresses the need of the area to attract investment and jobs and improve educational opportunities.

The bill allows: (1) a Promise Zone employment tax credit for wages paid to a qualified zone or resident employee, and (2) expensing of Promise Zone property.

A "Promise Zone property" is a property that is: (1) tangible property with a&#160;recovery period of 20 years or less for depreciation purposes,&#160;water utility property, computer software, or qualified leasehold improvement property; (2) acquired by purchase for use&#160;in the active conduct of a trade or business; and (3) originally placed in service in a Promise Zone.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
