<bill session="115" type="s" number="374" updated="2017-09-27T15:12:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Concrete Masonry Products Research, Education, and Promotion Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Concrete Masonry Products Research, Education, and Promotion Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enable concrete masonry products manufacturers to establish, finance, and carry out a coordinated program of research, education, and promotion to improve, maintain, and develop markets for concrete masonry products.</title>
    <title type="display">Concrete Masonry Products Research, Education, and Promotion Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2017-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2017-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2017-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2017-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2017-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2017-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2017-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-08-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1046"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Concrete Masonry Products Research, Education, and Promotion Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Commerce to issue orders applicable to U.S. manufacturers of concrete masonry products. Any such order must provide for the establishment of a Concrete Masonry Products Board to carry out a program of generic promotion, research, and education regarding concrete masonry products.

An order must also provide that assessments be paid by concrete masonry product manufacturers for concrete masonry products manufactured and marketed in the United States. At least 50% of the assessments paid by a manufacturer must be used to support research, education, and generic promotion programs and projects in support of the geographic region of the manufacturer.

During the 60-day period preceding the proposed effective date of an order, Commerce shall conduct a referendum for order approval among manufacturers.

The bill allows petition and review of an order, and order enforcement through U.S. district courts.

The bill requires a study and a report by: (1) the Government Accountability Office on how the board spends assessments collected, the impact of board activities, and other matters relating to the demand for concrete masonry products; and (2) Commerce on the appropriateness and effectiveness of applying the commodity check-off program model to a nonagricultural industry.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
