<bill session="115" type="s" number="196" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health Emergency Response and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health Emergency Response and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a Public Health Emergency Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Public Health Emergency Response and Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2017-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2017-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Public Health Emergency Response and Accountability Act

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services, upon determination of a public health emergency, to provide for the convening of a group of federal officials to prepare monthly reports concerning such matters as funding, collaboration, and best practices.

The bill makes appropriations to the Public Health Emergency Fund upon determination of an emergency. Funding is subject to a calculation that compares amounts available in the fund to average public health emergency relief expenditures over preceding fiscal years.

The bill amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to exempt the fund from sequestration, a process of automatic, usually across-the-board spending reductions under which budgetary resources are permanently cancelled to enforce specific budget policy goals.

The Government Accountability Office (GAO) must report on:

 the capacity of the public health system to respond effectively to infectious disease outbreaks, the coordination between federal, state, and local government entities when responding to infectious disease outbreaks, the most effective ways to provide or allocate resources for public health emergency response, and an audit of how funds for public health emergencies have been expended within the last two years. GAO must also issue a post-emergency report on response efforts by government entities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
