<bill session="115" type="s" number="178" updated="2017-10-12T04:45:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-03T15:56:31-04:00">PASSED:BILL</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-10-03T15:56:31-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Elder Abuse Prevention and Prosecution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Robert Matava Elder Abuse Prosecution Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Elder Abuse Prevention and Prosecution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Elder Abuse Prevention and Prosecution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Robert Matava Elder Abuse Prosecution Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Elder Abuse Prevention and Prosecution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Elder Abuse Prevention and Prosecution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Robert Matava Elder Abuse Prosecution Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Elder Abuse Prevention and Prosecution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Elder Abuse Prevention and Prosecution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Robert Matava Elder Abuse Prosecution Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent elder abuse and exploitation and improve the justice system's response to victims in elder abuse and exploitation cases.</title>
    <title type="display">Robert Matava Elder Abuse Prosecution Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2017-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2017-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2017-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2017-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2017-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2017-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2017-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2017-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2017-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2017-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2017-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S361-362" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-02-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Grassley without amendment. With written report No. 115-9.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="23">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 23.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-08-01">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4681-4684" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-08-01" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4681-4684" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-08-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04T13:04:47-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Digital Commerce and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-03T15:47:14-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Goodlatte moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-03T15:47:28-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7709-7712" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-03T15:47:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 178.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2017-10-03T15:56:31-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7709-7712" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-10-03T15:56:32-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2017-10-06">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="182"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s742"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2017-08-01T12:32:18Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Elder Abuse Prevention and Prosecution Act

TITLE I--SUPPORTING FEDERAL CASES INVOLVING ELDER JUSTICE

(Sec. 101) This bill establishes requirements for the Department of Justice (DOJ) with respect to investigating and prosecuting elder abuse crimes and enforcing elder abuse laws. Specifically, DOJ must:

 designate Elder Justice Coordinators in federal judicial districts and at DOJ, implement comprehensive training for Federal Bureau of Investigation agents, and establish a working group to provide policy advice. The Executive Office for United States Attorneys must operate a resource group to assist prosecutors in pursuing elder abuse cases.

The Federal Trade Commission must designate an Elder Justice Coordinator within its Bureau of Consumer Protection.

TITLE II--IMPROVED DATA COLLECTION AND FEDERAL COORDINATION

(Sec. 201) DOJ must establish best practices for data collection on elder abuse.

(Sec. 202) DOJ must collect and publish data on elder abuse cases and investigations. The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must provide for publication data on elder abuse cases referred to adult protective services. TITLE III--ENHANCED VICTIM ASSISTANCE TO ELDER ABUSE SURVIVORS (Sec. 301) This section expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) elder abuse involves exploitation of potentially vulnerable individuals; (2) combatting elder abuse requires support for victims and prevention; and (3) the Senate supports a multipronged approach to prevent elder abuse, protect victims, and prosecute perpetrators of elder abuse crimes. (Sec. 302) DOJ's Office for Victims of Crime must report to Congress on the nature, extent, and amount of funding under the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 for victims of crime who are elders. TITLE IV--ROBERT MATAVA ELDER ABUSE PROSECUTION ACT OF 2017 Robert Matava Elder Abuse Prosecution Act of 2017

This bill amends the federal criminal code to expand prohibited telemarketing fraud to include "telemarketing or email marketing" fraud. It expands the definition of telemarketing or email marketing to include measures to induce investment for financial profit, participation in a business opportunity, or commitment to a loan.

 A defendant convicted of telemarketing or email marketing fraud that targets or victimizes a person over age 55 is subject to an enhanced criminal penalty and mandatory forfeiture.

The bill adds health care fraud to the list of fraud offenses subject to enhanced penalties.

(Sec. 403) DOJ, in coordination with the Elder Justice Coordinating Council, must provide information, training, and technical assistance to help states and local governments investigate, prosecute, prevent, and mitigate the impact of elder abuse, exploitation, and neglect.

(Sec. 404) It grants congressional consent to states to enter into cooperative agreements or compacts to promote and to enforce elder abuse laws. The State Justice Institute must submit legislative proposals to Congress to facilitate such agreements and compacts.

TITLE V--MISCELLANEOUS

(Sec. 501) This section amends title XX (Block Grants to States for Social Services and Elder Justice) of the Social Security Act to specify that HHS may award adult protective services demonstration grants to the highest courts of states to assess adult guardianship and conservatorship proceedings and to implement necessary changes. The highest court of a state that receives a demonstration grant must collaborate with the state's unit on aging and adult protective services agency.

(Sec. 502) The Government Accountability Office (GAO) must review and report on elder justice programs and initiatives in the federal criminal justice system. The GAO must also report on: (1) federal government efforts to monitor the exploitation of older adults in global drug trafficking schemes and criminal enterprises, the incarceration of exploited older adults who are U.S. citizens in foreign court systems, and the total number of elder abuse cases pending in the United States; and (2) the results of federal government intervention with foreign officials on behalf of U.S. citizens who are elder abuse victims in international criminal enterprises.

(Sec. 503) DOJ must report to Congress on its outreach to state and local law enforcement agencies on the process for collaborating with the federal government to investigate and prosecute interstate and international elder financial exploitation cases.

(Sec. 504) DOJ must publish model power of attorney legislation for the purpose of preventing elder abuse.

(Sec. 505) DOJ must publish best practices for improving guardianship proceedings and model legislation related to guardianship proceedings for the purpose of preventing elder abuse.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-9</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
