<bill session="115" type="s" number="763" updated="2017-09-11T02:58:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Surface and Maritime Transportation Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Surface and Maritime Transportation Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve surface and maritime transportation security.</title>
    <title type="display">Surface and Maritime Transportation Security Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2017-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2017-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2017-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2017-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2017-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-04-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Surface and Maritime Transportation Security Act

This bill requires the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to: (1) assess, and implement a risk-based security strategy to address, the vulnerabilities of and risks to surface transportation and maritime transportation systems; (2) develop a management oversight strategy that identifies the parties responsible for implementing the security strategy; and (3) submit a report that describes a risk-based budget and resource allocation plan for surface transportation sectors that reflects the security strategy.

The TSA shall establish the Surface Transportation Security Advisory Committee to make recommendations pertaining to surface transportation security.

In addition, the bill:

 directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to expand the TSA's explosives detection canine team program, requires the Government Accountability Office to study specified matters related to surface transportation, expands the permissible uses of railroad security improvement grants, requires the TSA to issue a decision on the use of a passenger vetting system by the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak), requires the TSA to establish a program to promote surface transportation security through the training of surface transportation operators and frontline employees, expands the transportation security card program to allow individuals subject to credentialing or a background check to apply for a transportation security card, and requires DHS to evaluate cargo-container scanning technologies.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
