<bill session="115" type="hj" number="110" updated="2017-09-11T03:02:48Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2017-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hj" session="115" relation="unknown" number="5"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Constitutional Amendment 

This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment prohibiting total outlays for a fiscal year from exceeding total receipts for the year, excluding outlays for repayment of debt principal and receipts derived from borrowing.

The President must submit an annual budget in which total outlays for the fiscal year do not exceed total receipts.

Congress may waive the requirements for any fiscal year in which:

 a declaration of war is in effect, the United States is engaged in a military conflict which causes an imminent and serious military threat to national security as declared by a joint resolution, or a national emergency has been declared by a joint resolution. Any waiver must identify and be limited to the specific increase for the year that is necessary for the military conflict or emergency. Any increase in spending pursuant to a waiver must be offset by a budget surplus within 10 years of the end of the waiver.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
