<bill session="115" type="h" number="3050" updated="2017-10-11T04:29:24Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-18T13:42:05-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-18T13:42:05-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to provide Federal financial assistance to States to implement, review, and revise State energy security plans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2017-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 115-224.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-17" calendar="Union" number="159">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 159.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18T13:31:01-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Upton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18T13:31:02-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5938-5939" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18T13:31:03-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3050.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-07-18T13:42:05-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5938" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-07-18T13:42:07-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-18T12:51:58Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on July 17, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017

(Sec.2)This bill amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to provide financial assistance to states for the implementation, review, and revision of a state energy security plan that assesses the state's existing circumstances and proposes methods to strengthen the ability of the state to have a reliable, secure, and resilient energy infrastructure.

A state energy security plan must:

 address all fuels, including petroleum products, other liquid fuels, coal, electricity, and natural gas, as well as regulated and unregulated energy providers; provide a State energy profile, including an assessment of energy production, distribution, and end-use; address potential hazards to each energy sector or system, including physical threats and cybersecurity threats and vulnerabilities; provide a risk assessment of energy infrastructure and cross-sector interdependencies; provide a risk mitigation approach to enhance reliability and end-use resilience; and address multi-State, Indian Tribe, and regional coordination planning and response, and to the extent practicable, encourage mutual assistance in cyber and physical response plans. In developing a state energy security plan, a state must coordinate with:(1)the public utility or service commission of the state,(2)energy providers from the private sector, and(3)other entities responsible for maintaining fuel or electric reliability.

Upon request of a state, the Department of Energy (DOE) may provide information and technical assistance, and other assistance, in the development, implementation, or revision of a state energy security plan.

DOE's authority to carry out this bill's provisions expires on October 31, 2022.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-224</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
