<bill session="115" type="hr" number="343" updated="2017-09-14T19:30:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restore Democracy Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restore Democracy Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding steps that Congress should take to restore democracy and change the way we do politics in the United States by reducing the influence of money and corporations and promoting the participation of the people in politics and government.</title>
    <title type="display">Restore Democracy Resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="389"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="404"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="429"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="465"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="115" relation="unknown" number="364"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts and representation"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Restore Democracy Resolution

 Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that Congress should enact and the states should ratify a constitutional amendment providing that any right of a corporation or other artificial entity to engage in political activity is not derived from the first amendment but from the laws of the United States and the states, and may be exercised only to the extent provided by such laws.

 Expresses the sense of the House that: (1) the case of Citizens United v. Federal Election Commission opened the door to the corrupting influence of money in politics; (2) Congress should have the power to regulate the raising and spending of money and in-kind equivalents with respect to federal elections; and (3) all political contributions should be publicly disclosed so that voters have complete information about who is paying for political advertisements.

 Expresses the sense of the House further regarding:

 creation of a small donor and public finance system for congressional elections, the power of Congress to implement and enforce campaign contribution and spending limits, the power of Congress to prohibit vote suppression activities, mandatory state online voter registration systems, declaration of Election Day as a legal public holiday, establishment of a federal reapportioment system that would create compact and contiguous congressional districts adhering to the existing standards of equal population, the power of the highest court of each state to reject congressional district maps that do not meet such criteria, hearings and reports on a bill or resolution by each committee to which the measure is referred, resolution of all items of difference by full conference committee membership, simultaneous House and Senate five-day work weeks in Washington and district work periods, and open rules for every bill brought to the floor of the House for a vote.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
