<bill session="115" type="h" number="2777" updated="2017-10-12T07:16:48Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Give Veterans Home Loan Choices Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Give Veterans Home Loan Choices Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To include information regarding VA home loans in the Informed Consumer Choice Disclosure required to be provided to a prospective FHA borrower who is a veteran, to amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize the provision of a certificate of eligibility for VA home loans during the preseparation counseling for members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Give Veterans Home Loan Choices Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000131"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000371" joined="2017-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001304" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001091" joined="2017-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2017-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2017-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001050" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2017-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2017-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000474" joined="2017-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-06">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Give Veterans Home Loan Choices Act of 2017

This bill amends the National Housing Act to require that a Federal Housing Administration mortgage notice for a prospective borrower who is a veteran include, in addition to comparative rate and fee information about conventional loans, similar comparative information about Veterans Administration (VA) home loans.

The Federal Housing Finance Agency shall direct the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) to revise the uniform residential loan application by December 31, 2018, to include: (1) a check box to indicate that the applicant is a veteran; (2) the statement "If you are a veteran, you may be eligible for a VA mortgage"; and (3) a blank line for the borrower to initial and a statement that all applicants must initial such blank line to confirm that they have read such VA mortgage eligibility statement.

The bill requires pre-separation counseling for a member of the Armed Forces who is separating from active duty to include:

 information on the availability of VA home loan services and housing assistance benefits, including the authority of a member to use an honorable discharge certificate as a certificate of eligibility for a VA guaranteed housing loan or to request a specific certificate of eligibility for such loan; and counseling on responsible borrowing practices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
