<bill session="115" type="s" number="152" updated="2017-09-13T12:03:30Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Accountability First and Appeals Modernization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Accountability First and Appeals Modernization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the removal or demotion of employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs based on performance or misconduct, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">VA Accountability First and Appeals Modernization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2017-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2017-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2017-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2017-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="611"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Office of Special Counsel"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-17T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">VA Accountability First and Appeals Modernization Act of 2017

This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to remove or demote a VA employee based on performance or misconduct. The VA may remove such individual from the civil service or demote the individual through a reduction in grade or annual pay rate.

 A demoted individual shall not be placed on administrative leave or any other category of paid leave during the appeals period and can receive pay only if he or she reports for duty.

The bill: (1) establishes an expedited appeals process by the Merit Systems Protection Board, (2) amends the disability benefits appeals process, (3) prescribes restrictions on the VA's authority to remove or demote an employee, and (4) establishes whistleblower protections.

 The VA shall reduce the federal annuity of an individual removed from the VA Senior Executive Service (SES) who is convicted of a felony that influenced his or her performance while employed in such position.

The VA may reduce the federal annuity of an individual who was convicted of such a felony and was subject to removal or transfer from the SES but who left the VA before final action was taken.

 The VA may recoup an award, a bonus, or relocation expenses paid to a VA employee under specified circumstances.

 The VA may suspend, reprimand or admonish an SES employee for misconduct or performance that does not merit removal. Appeals may be made to the Senior Executive Disciplinary Appeals Board (as provided for by this bill).

The bill amends the disability benefits appeals process.

 The bill prohibits payment of an award or bonus to any SES employee during each of FY2017-FY2021.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
