<bill session="115" type="sr" number="87" updated="2017-07-20T17:26:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate concerning the ongoing conflict in Syria as it reaches its six-year mark in March, the ensuing humanitarian crisis in Syria and neighboring countries, the resulting humanitarian and national security challenges, and the urgent need for a political solution to the crisis.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate concerning the ongoing conflict in Syria as it reaches its six-year mark in March, the ensuing humanitarian crisis in Syria and neighboring countries, the resulting humanitarian and national security challenges, and the urgent need for a political solution to the crisis.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2017-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2017-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2017-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1847" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1846-1847" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Condemns: (1) the regime of Bashar al-Assad for committing war crimes and crimes against humanity during the Syrian conflict, and (2) the Assad regime and the government of the Russian Federation for using indiscriminate cluster munitions on civilian areas and infrastructure and for the deliberate targeting of U.N. humanitarian aid convoys.

Urges:

 all parties to the conflict to immediately halt indiscriminate attacks, the imposition of starvation sieges, and other forms of warfare directed against civilians and civilian infrastructure and to facilitate unfettered access to humanitarian assistance throughout Syria; all parties in Syria to support full implementation of U.N. Security Council Resolution 2268, which calls for a cessation of hostilities in the conflict, except with the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL) and al Qaeda, to facilitate the provision of humanitarian assistance and reconstruction of war-affected communities; and the international community to continue to support neighboring countries and host communities who are supporting refugees and internally displaced persons fleeing the conflict. Affirms: (1) the neutrality of medical professionals providing humanitarian assistance and health care on a non-political basis, (2) that the elimination of al Qaeda and ISIS safe havens in Syria is a vital U.S. national security interest, and (3) that the stability of key European and Middle Eastern partners is vital to U.S. national security and preventing the conflict from undermining that stability is a top U.S. priority.

Commends the Syrian Democratic Forces, the Syrian Arab Coalition, and other local, Syrian partner forces for their support of Operation Inherent Resolve and the efforts of the Global Coalition to Counter ISIL.

Calls upon the President to: (1) make it U.S. policy to continue to coordinate a comprehensive and generous response to the Syrian humanitarian crisis, (2) continue active U.S. participation in a diplomatic process to achieve a political agreement, and (3) submit a strategy for providing long-term stability and security in areas seized from ISIL.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
