<bill session="115" type="s" number="317" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:40Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide taxpayers with an annual report disclosing the cost and performance of Government programs and areas of duplication among them, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001069" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2017-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-01">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment. With written report No. 115-34.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="43">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 43.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="71"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Taxpayers Right-To-Know Act

This bill requires that the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) website include an inventory that identifies each federal program for which there is more than $1 million in annual budget authority.

For programs for which there is more than $1 million but not more than $10 million in annual budget authority (smaller programs), the inventory must include:

 an identification of the program activities that are aggregated, disaggregated, or consolidated; for each such program activity, the amount of funding for the current fiscal year and the previous two fiscal years; an identification of the statutes that authorize the program and any major regulations specific to the program; a description of the individuals served by a program and beneficiaries who received financial assistance under a program for the most recent fiscal year; and links to any evaluation, assessment, or program performance reviews by the agency, an Inspector General, or the Government Accountability Office (GAO) released during the preceding five years. For programs for which there is more than $10 million in annual budget authority (larger programs), the inventory must also include specified additional information, including financial information for each program activity required to be reported under the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006.

The OMB shall archive and preserve the program inventory.

The bill requires the OMB to issue initial guidance to assist agencies in identifying how the program activities used in budget or appropriations accounts correspond with programs identified in the program inventory. The OMB may: (1) issue initial guidance to agencies to ensure that programs are presented at a similar level of detail across agencies and are not duplicative; (2) exempt from the requirements of this bill, based on an analysis of the costs of implementation, agencies that are not required to have a chief financial officer and that have not more than $10 million in budget authority; and (3) based on an analysis of the costs of implementation, extend the bill's implementation deadline (June 30, 2019) in one-year increments and by not more than two years.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-34</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
