<bill session="115" type="s" number="1141" updated="2017-10-13T21:15:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-06">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that the United States promotes the meaningful participation of women in mediation and negotiation processes seeking to prevent, mitigate, or resolve violent conflict.</title>
    <title type="display">Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2017-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2017-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-06-08">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker without amendment. With written report No. 115-93.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="123">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 123.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-08-03" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4889-4891" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4889-4891" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04T13:06:38-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-04T14:31:48-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25T15:44:46-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce (CA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25T15:44:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7446-7450" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25T15:44:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1141.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2017-09-25T16:04:32-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7447-7448" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-09-25T16:04:34-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2017-09-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2017-10-06" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="115-68" type="public" datetime="2017-10-06">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 115-68.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2484"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-08-03T15:13:19Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017

 (Sec. 3) This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States should be a global leader in promoting the participation of women in conflict prevention, management, and resolution and post-conflict relief and recovery efforts; (2) the political participation and leadership of women in fragile environments, particularly during democratic transitions, is critical to sustaining democratic institutions; and (3) the participation of women in conflict prevention and conflict resolution helps promote more inclusive and democratic societies and is critical to country and regional stability.

 (Sec. 5) The President, within one year after enactment of this bill and again four years later, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and make public a Women, Peace, and Security Strategy, which shall:

 be aligned with other nations' plans to improve the participation of women in peace and security processes, conflict prevention, peace building, and decision-making institutions; and include goals and evaluation plans to ensure strategy effectiveness. Such a strategy shall include a specific implementation plan from each relevant federal agency.

The President is urged to promote women's participation in conflict prevention.

 It is the sense of Congress that the President should: (1) provide technical assistance and training to female negotiators, peace builders, and stakeholders (non-governmental and private sector entities engaged in or affected by conflict prevention and stabilization, peace building, security, or related efforts); (2) address security-related barriers to women's participation; (3) encourage increased women's participation in U.S.-funded programs that provide foreign nationals with law enforcement, rule of law, or military education training; (4) support appropriate local organizations, especially women's peace building organizations; and (5) expand gender analysis to improve program design.

 (Sec. 6) The Department of State shall ensure that personnel responsible for, or deploying to, countries or regions considered to be at risk of undergoing, or emerging from, violent conflict obtain training in the following areas, each of which shall include a focus on ensuring participation by women:

 conflict prevention, mitigation, and resolution; protecting civilians from violence, exploitation, and trafficking in persons; and international human rights law. The Department of Defense shall ensure that relevant personnel receive training in:

 conflict prevention, peace processes, mitigation, resolution, and security initiatives that addresses the importance of participation by women; and gender considerations and participation by women, including training regarding international human rights law and protecting civilians from violence, exploitation, and trafficking in persons. (Sec. 7) The State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development shall establish guidelines for overseas U.S. personnel to consult with stakeholders regarding U.S. efforts to:

 prevent, mitigate, or resolve violent conflict; and enhance the success of mediation and negotiation processes by ensuring the meaningful participation of women. The State Department is urged to work with international, regional, national, and local organizations to increase the participation of women in international peacekeeping operations.

 (Sec. 8) The State Department, within one year after the first strategy's submission, shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on training regarding the participation of women in conflict resolution.

 The President, within two years after each strategy's submission, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that evaluates the implementation of such strategy and the impact of U.S. diplomatic efforts and foreign assistance programs to promote the participation of women.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-93</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
