<bill session="115" type="h" number="876" updated="2017-08-22T04:28:58Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-25T19:09:15-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-04-25T19:09:15-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aviation Employee Screening and Security Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aviation Employee Screening and Security Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Aviation Employee Screening and Security Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Aviation Employee Screening and Security Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Aviation Employee Screening and Security Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to reform programs of the Transportation Security Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To reform programs of the Transportation Security Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Aviation Employee Screening and Security Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000575" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000132" joined="2017-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2017-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Protective Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-03-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 115-94.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-04-25" calendar="Union" number="54">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 54.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25T17:09:16-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Katko moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25T17:09:33-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2825-2828" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25T17:09:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 876.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25T17:18:17-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25T19:01:47-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2838-2839" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="223" datetime="2017-04-25T19:09:15-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 409 - 0 (Roll no. 223).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2825-2826" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25T19:09:18-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25T19:09:19-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Transportation Security" code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Aviation Employee Screening and Security Enhancement Act of 2017

This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to submit a cost and feasibility study of a statistically significant number of Category I, II, and X airports to ensure that all airport employee entry and exit points leading to secure airport areas are comprised of:

 a secure door utilizing card and pin entry or biometric technology; surveillance video recording capable of storing video data for at least 30 days; and certain advanced screening technologies. The TSA shall:

 work with air carriers and airport operators, vendors, and concessionaires to enhance security awareness of credentialed airport workers regarding insider threats to aviation security and best practices related to airport access controls; assess credentialing standards, policies, and practices to ensure that such threats are adequately addressed; and require the application for a credential granting access to the Secure Identification Display Area of an airport to include the individual's social security number in order to strengthen security vetting effectiveness. The TSA also shall:

 work with airport operators to identify advanced technologies for securing employee access to secure and sterile airport areas; ensure that credentialed aviation workers are continuously vetted through the Federal Bureau of Investigation's Rap Back Service in order to more rapidly detect and mitigate insider threats; identify ways to enhance TSA's ability to educate its personnel on insider threats to aviation security and mitigate such threats; increase covert testing of TSA employee screening operations at airports and measure security effectiveness; establish a national database of TSA employees who have had either their airport or aircraft operator-issued badge revoked for failure to comply with aviation security requirements; and submit a plan for recurring reviews of the security controls for TSA information technology systems at airports.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-94</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
