<bill session="115" type="s" number="234" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Outsourcing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Outsourcing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide incentives for businesses to keep jobs in America.</title>
    <title type="display">End Outsourcing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000607"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2017-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2017-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2017-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="247"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="685"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">End Outsourcing Act 

This bill modifies provisions of tax, labor, and federal contracting laws related to the outsourcing of jobs.

The bill amends the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act to require employers to include an outsourcing statement in the notice that must be provided to employees, state dislocated worker units, and local governments prior to plant closings and mass layoffs. The statement must specify whether part or all of the positions held by affected employees will be moved outside of the United States, regardless of whether the positions are moved within the business enterprise involved or to another business enterprise.

The Department of Labor must publish on its website a list of employers that have included an outsourcing statement in the notice or have incurred liability for failing to provide the required notice.

The bill also amends the Internal Revenue Code to:

 deny certain tax deductions and accounting methods for outsourcing employers; require the recapture of certain tax credits and grants that were provided to outsourcing employers and were related to the design, construction, operation, or maintenance of an outsourced facility; and grant business taxpayers a tax credit for up to 20% of insourcing expenses incurred for eliminating a business located outside the United States and relocating it within the United States if there is an increase in the taxpayer's employment of full-time employees in the United States. Federal contracting officers must: (1) require contractors submitting bids or proposals to disclose specified details regarding the outsourcing of jobs, and (2) take the disclosure into account in awarding contracts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
