<bill session="115" type="s" number="1073" updated="2017-09-26T04:30:36Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize Escambia County, Florida, to convey certain property that was formerly part of Santa Rosa Island National Monument and that was conveyed to Escambia County subject to restrictions on use and reconveyance.</title>
    <title type="display">Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2017-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks" code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="2370"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Escambia County Land Conveyance Act

 This bill authorizes Escambia County, Florida, to convey its interest in any part of the former Santa Rosa Island National Monument land that was conveyed to it by the federal government in 1947 to any person or entity, without restriction.

The bill prohibits any person or entity holding a leasehold interest in such land from being required to involuntarily accept a fee interest to such land in place of the leasehold interest.

 The bill conditions such conveyance on requirements that: (1) all interest of Escambia County in any part of such land that is within the jurisdictional boundaries of Santa Rosa County, Florida, must be conveyed to Santa Rosa County within two years of the enactment of this bill; and (2) Escambia County must preserve in perpetuity the areas of the conveyed monument land that, as of this bill's enactment, are dedicated for conservation, preservation, public recreation access, and public parking. Santa Rosa County shall assume ownership of the non-federal land conveyed to it free of such restrictions.

 Santa Rosa County or any other person to whom such county reconveys such land may reconvey any part of it. Any proceeds from the conveyance of such land by either county shall be considered to be windfall profits that shall revert to the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
