<bill session="115" type="h" number="343" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:18Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Parks Revitalization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Parks Revitalization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish a program enabling communities to better leverage resources to address health, economic development, and conservation concerns through needed investments in parks, recreational areas, facilities, and programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Community Parks Revitalization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001165"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Lighting and heating"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Parks Revitalization Act

 This bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to carry out a community revitalization program of federal grants to eligible local governments located within standard metropolitan statistical areas for various park and recreation purposes, including grants for rehabilitation and construction, innovation and recreation programming, and recovery action programs.

HUD may designate local governments not located in standard metropolitan statistical areas to receive such grants under a partial eligibility waiver.

The bill prescribes requirements, including matching requirements, for rehabilitation and construction and for innovation and recreation grants.

This bill limits to 10% the use of funds appropriated for rehabilitation and construction grants for acquisition of land or interests in land.

A recipient may transfer a grant in whole or in part to private nonprofit agencies for recreational areas and facilities they own or operate which offer recreational opportunities to the general population.

For project approval, an applicant must submit to HUD evidence of its commitment to ongoing planning, rehabilitation, service, operation, and maintenance programs for its park and recreation systems, expressed in a five-year local park and recreation recovery action program.

The bill prescribes requirements for the five-year park and recreation recovery action program under an at-risk youth recreation grant.

HUD may increase federal rehabilitation and construction, innovation, and at-risk youth recreation grants to a state under this bill by an additional match of up to 15% (but not more than 15%) of total project or program cost. The bill limits the aggregate amount of the grant and the additional grant amounts to 85% of total project or program cost.

The bill prohibits the conversion, without HUD approval, of any property improved or developed with assistance under this bill for uses other than for public recreation.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
