<bill session="115" type="s" number="1473" updated="2017-09-11T03:01:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeless Veterans' Reintegration Programs Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeless Veterans&#8217; Reintegration Programs Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for a five-year extension to the homeless veterans reintegration programs and to provide clarification regarding eligibility for services under such programs.</title>
    <title type="display">Homeless Veterans' Reintegration Programs Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2017-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Homeless Veterans' Reintegration Programs Reauthorization Act of 2017

This bill reauthorizes Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) homeless veterans reintegration programs through FY2022. The bill includes among those for whom job training, counseling, and placement services are to be provided to expedite their reintegration into the labor force: (1) veterans participating in the VA supported housing program for which rental assistance is provided under the United States Housing Act of 1937, (2) Indians who are veterans receiving assistance under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self Determination Act of 1996, (3) veterans who are transitioning from being incarcerated, and (4) veterans participating in the VA's rapid rehousing and prevention program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
