<bill session="115" type="h" number="131" updated="2017-05-03T23:51:36Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reaffirm the trust status of land taken into trust by the United States pursuant to the Act of June 18, 1934, for the benefit of an Indian tribe that was federally recognized on the date that the land was taken into trust, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To reaffirm the trust status of land taken into trust by the United States pursuant to the Act of June 18, 1934, for the benefit of an Indian tribe that was federally recognized on the date that the land was taken into trust, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2017-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill reaffirms the trust status of land taken into trust by the United States pursuant to the Indian Reorganization Act before the enactment of this bill for the benefit of an Indian tribe that was federally recognized when the land was taken into trust. Department of the Interior actions to take land into trust under the Indian Reorganization Act are ratified and confirmed as if the actions were taken under a law specifically authorizing or directing them.

The bill applies to all claims pending on, or filed on or after, the bill's enactment.

Land taken into trust that has been ratified and confirmed pursuant to this bill must remain Indian country.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
