<bill session="115" type="h" number="473" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:29Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military LAND Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military LAND Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Land and National Defense Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Land and National Defense Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 54, United States Code, to provide that if the head of the agency managing Federal property objects to the inclusion of certain property on the National Register or its designation as a National Historic Landmark for reasons of national security, the Federal property shall be neither included nor designated until the objection is withdrawn, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Military LAND Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2017-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Land and National Defense Act or the Military LAND Act

 This bill requires the Department of the Interior to notify specified congressional committees if a property owned by the federal government is being considered for inclusion on the National Register of Historic Places, for designation as a National Historic Landmark, or for nomination to the World Heritage List. If any federal agency managing any such federal property objects to its inclusion or designation for national security reasons, it shall be neither included nor designated until the objection is withdrawn.

The bill requires Interior to allow for expedited removal of federal property from such register at the request of the managing agency for reasons of national security.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
