<bill session="115" type="h" number="3083" updated="2017-09-11T02:53:57Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Technical Education And Career Help (TEACH) Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Technical Education And Career Help (TEACH) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for the preparation of career and technical education teachers.</title>
    <title type="display">Technical Education And Career Help (TEACH) Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2017-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001294" joined="2017-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2017-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2017-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001193" joined="2017-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Technical Education and Career Help (TEACH) Act 

This bill amends title II (Teacher Quality Enhancement) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize grants under the Teacher Quality Partnership grant program to be used for secondary school career and technical education teacher preparation programs. The grant program provides funds to partnerships of high-need local educational agencies, high-need schools or early education programs, and institutions of higher education (IHEs) to train current and prospective teachers and school leaders.

The bill requires the career and technical education teacher preparation programs to:

 be available to mid-career professionals or recent graduates of an IHE who have expertise in a program area in which there is a career and technical education teacher shortage; allow individuals to obtain initial licensure and the basic skills required for entry into the education profession, with the option of earning a bachelor's or master's degree; and allow teachers who do not have subject matter expertise in a career and technical education field that is in demand in the local or regional economy to receive the technical skills training they need to teach those skills in a classroom setting. It directs the Department of Education to establish performance measures for the career and technical education teacher preparation programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
