<bill session="115" type="s" number="1653" updated="2017-10-03T04:30:39Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Real Education for Healthy Youth Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Real Education for Healthy Youth Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the overall health and well-being of young people, including the promotion of lifelong sexual health and healthy relationships, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Real Education for Healthy Youth Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3602"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Real Education for Healthy Youth Act of 2017

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), in coordination with the Department of Education, to award grants for: (1) comprehensive sex education for adolescents, (2) comprehensive sex education provided by institutions of higher education, and (3) training faculty and staff to teach comprehensive sex education to adolescents. HHS must enter a contract with a nonprofit organization to evaluate and report on these grants. The bill makes appropriations to carry out the the bill.

Grants may not be used for health education programs that:

 withhold health-promoting or lifesaving information about sexuality-related topics, including HIV; are medically inaccurate or have been scientifically shown to be ineffective; promote gender or racial stereotypes; are insensitive and unresponsive to the needs of certain youth, including survivors of sexual abuse or assault, sexually active youth, pregnant or parenting youth, or individuals with varying gender identities or sexual orientations; or are inconsistent with the ethical imperatives of medicine and public health. The bill amends the Public Health Service Act to revise requirements and eliminate prohibitions regarding the content of educational programs funded through the AIDS prevention program.

The bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to allow funding to be used for: (1) materials or programs that promote or encourage sexual activity, and (2) contraceptive distribution in schools.

The bill amends title V (Maternal and Child Health Services) of the Social Security Act to repeal the program for abstinence education. Unobligated funds for abstinence education are transferred and made available to carry out this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
