<bill session="115" type="h" number="889" updated="2017-06-19T21:00:27Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Human Trafficking Fraud Enforcement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Human Trafficking Fraud Enforcement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of an office within the Internal Revenue Service to focus on violations of the internal revenue laws by persons who are under investigation for conduct relating to the promotion of commercial sex acts and trafficking in persons crimes, and to increase the criminal monetary penalty limitations for the underpayment or overpayment of tax due to fraud.</title>
    <title type="display">Human Trafficking Fraud Enforcement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2017-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E146"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Human Trafficking Fraud Enforcement Act of 2017

 This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to establish within the Internal Revenue Service an office to investigate and prosecute violations of tax laws by persons that appear to be violating specified federal laws prohibiting forced labor, trafficking of individuals, and transportation of minors or aliens for immoral purposes or state or territorial laws prohibiting the promotion of&#160;prostitution or of any commercial sex act. The office must cooperate with the Child Exploitation and Obscenity Section of the Department of Justice and the Innocence Lost National Initiative of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.

The bill allows victims of human trafficking crimes to claim awards allowed for whistle-blowing.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase civil and criminal penalties for tax evasion attributable to income derived from human trafficking and commercial sex acts, and (2) make it a felony to fail to file a tax return including income derived from human trafficking or commercial sex acts.

The bill appropriates to the Crime Victims Fund additional funds equal to the increase in receipts from increased civil and criminal penalties provided by this bill. The funds are provided for victim assistance grants under the Victims of Crime Act of 1984, including crisis intervention, emergency shelter and transportation, counseling, and criminal justice advocacy to victims of crime.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
