<bill session="115" type="h" number="948" updated="2017-08-30T07:15:26Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Common Sense Housing Investment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Common Sense Housing Investment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to replace the mortgage interest deduction with a nonrefundable credit for indebtedness secured by a residence, to provide affordable housing to extremely low-income families, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Common Sense Housing Investment Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2017-08-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2017-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2017-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2017-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2017-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2017-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2017-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2017-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Cooperative and condominium housing"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Common Sense Housing Investment Act of 2017

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax deduction for mortgage interest, to: (1) allow, in lieu of such deduction, a tax credit for 15% of mortgage interest paid in a taxable year for the taxpayer's principal residence and one other residence; (2) provide for a phaseout of the tax deduction for mortgage interest between 2017 and 2021; (3) allow a deduction for interest and taxes relating to land for dwelling purposes owned or leased by cooperative housing corporations; and (4) increase the state housing credit ceiling for the low-income housing tax credit.

The bill directs the Department of the Treasury to apply the savings from the enactment of this bill to the Housing Trust Fund, rental assistance programs, and the Public Housing Capital Fund.

The Department of Housing and Urban Development must revise regulations for the Housing Trust Fund to: (1) increase the limitation on funds that are available for operating assistance for housing, (2) allow public housing agencies and tribally designated housing entities to be the recipients of grants that are allocated to a state or a state designated entity, and (3) eliminate the applicability of rules for the fund that are based on the HOME Investment Partnerships Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
