<bill session="115" type="h" number="1127" updated="2017-08-22T20:30:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Loan Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Loan Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase purchasing power, strengthen economic recovery, and restore fairness in financing higher education in the United States through student loan forgiveness, caps on interest rates on Federal student loans, and refinancing opportunities for private borrowers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Student Loan Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2017-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Loan Fairness Act

This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to establish a 10/10 Loan Repayment Plan that allows borrowers of Federal Family Education Loans (FFELs) and Direct Loans (DLs) to limit their monthly loan payments to one-twelfth of 10% of the amount by which their adjusted gross incomes and that of their spouses (if applicable) exceed 150% of the federal poverty level.

Additionally, it establishes a 10/10 Loan Forgiveness Program that provides FFEL and DL forgiveness to borrowers who, over 10 years, have made 120 monthly payments under the 10/10 Loan Repayment Plan or under another repayment plan that required them to make payments at least as large as those they would have made under the 10/10 Loan Repayment Plan.

It caps the interest rate on new DLs at 3.4%.

It amends the public service employee loan forgiveness program to forgive the DLs of participants who have made 60 (currently, 120) monthly payments on such loans pursuant to specified repayment plans.

The bill includes primary care physicians in medically underserved areas in the public service employee loan forgiveness program.

Certain borrowers may consolidate their private education loans as Direct Consolidation Loans.

It amends the Truth in Lending Act to direct the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau to issue regulations that require private education lenders to sell private education loans to the Department of Education (ED) for consolidation as Direct Consolidation Loans.

ED must pay the interest that accrues on certain student loans due to the borrower's lack of full-time employment for an interest-free deferment period of up to three years.

It excludes from a borrower's gross income for income tax purposes the principal and interest on FFELs and DLs that is forgiven pursuant to income-based repayment plans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
