<bill session="115" type="s" number="91" updated="2017-10-06T05:39:08Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Act of 1992</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Act of 1992</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Demonstration Act of 1992 to facilitate the ability of Indian tribes to integrate the employment, training, and related services from diverse Federal sources, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2017-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2017-01-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-02-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Hoeven without amendment. With written report No. 115-26.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-04-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="32">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 32.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25">
      <text>Star Print ordered on report 115-26.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="228"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2017

 This bill amends the Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Demonstration Act of 1992 to revise the program that provides for the integration of employment, training, and related services programs for Indian tribes. The Act is renamed the Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Act of 1992.

The bill revises the types of programs that may be integrated. The bill revises the process for: (1) federal agencies to grant or deny a tribe's request to waive statutory, regulatory, or administrative requirements to efficiently implement an integration plan, and (2) the Department of the Interior to approve or disapprove an integration plan. A tribe is granted certain hearing and appeal rights if Interior disapproves its plan.

 Tribal authority to use funds to place participants in training positions with employers is revised.

 The Bureau of Indian Affairs must receive and distribute funds for use in accordance with an approved integration plan.

Funds transferred to a tribe must be treated as non-federal funds for purposes of meeting matching requirements, except funds administered by the Department of Labor or the Department of Health and Human Services. Civil liability limitations apply to integration plans.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-26</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
