<bill session="115" type="h" number="230" updated="2017-09-11T03:02:50Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SALE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SALE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shee Atika Land Entitlement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shee Atik&#225; Land Entitlement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure equitable treatment of Shee Atik&#225;, Incorporated, under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act by facilitating the transfer of land on Admiralty Island, Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SALE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1481"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Shee Atika Land Entitlement Act or the SALE Act

This bill declares that consideration received by the urban Native corporation of Shee Atika under the agreement between Shee Atika and the United States must be treated as the receipt of land or interest in land pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act or as cash to equalize the values of properties exchanged pursuant to that Act. (Under the Act, these considerations are not taxed.)

Shee Atika may elect to accept payment from the Department of Agriculture for Cube Cove lands into an account that may be used to purchase property sold at public sale by a federal agency. Purchases made through that account must be considered to be conveyances under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
