<bill session="115" type="h" number="707" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Choices for Seniors Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Choices for Seniors Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act to improve choices available to Medicare eligible seniors by permitting them to elect (instead of regular Medicare benefits) to receive a voucher for a health savings account, for premiums for a high deductible health insurance plan, or both and by suspending Medicare late enrollment penalties between ages 65 and 70.</title>
    <title type="display">Health Care Choices for Seniors Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-27">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-27T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Care Choices for Seniors Act

This bill amends title II (Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish the Medicare Alternative Voucher (MAV) Program, under which a voucher may be used as a contribution into a health savings account and for the payment of enrollment premiums under a high-deductible health plan. HHS must establish a procedure under which an individual otherwise entitled to Medicare benefits may waive such entitlement and be automatically enrolled in the MAV Program.

In addition, the bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the amount of the deduction from gross income for health savings accounts by the amount of the MAV that is contributed to an individual's health savings account.

The bill also suspends Medicare late enrollment penalties for an individual between ages 65 and 70.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
