<bill session="115" type="h" number="701" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Security and Privacy in Your Car Study Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Security and Privacy in Your Car Study Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SPY Car Study Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SPY Car Study Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to conduct a study to determine appropriate cybersecurity standards for motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SPY Car Study Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000795"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2017-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H757"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Security and Privacy in Your Car Study Act of 2017 or the SPY Car Study Act of 2017

This bill requires the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to conduct a study to determine and recommend standards for the regulation of the cybersecurity of motor vehicles manufactured or imported for sale in the United States. The study shall identify:

 isolation measures that are necessary to separate critical software systems that can affect the driver's control of the movement of the vehicle from other software systems; measures that are necessary to detect and prevent or minimize anomalous codes, in vehicle software systems, associated with malicious behavior; techniques that are necessary to detect and prevent, discourage, or mitigate intrusions into vehicle software systems and other cybersecurity risks in motor vehicles; and best practices to secure driving data about a vehicle's status or about the owner, lessee, driver, or passenger of a vehicle that is collected by the electronic systems of motor vehicles; and a timeline for implementing systems and software that reflect such measures, techniques, and best practices.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
