<bill session="115" type="h" number="1883" updated="2017-09-01T15:00:24Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Broadcast Ownership Opportunities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Broadcast Ownership Opportunities Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Federal Communications Commission to take certain actions to increase diversity of ownership in the broadcasting industry, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Expanding Broadcast Ownership Opportunities Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001251"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Expanding Broadcast Ownership Opportunities Act of 2017

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 and the Internal Revenue Code to reestablish a tax certificate program under which the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) certifies a person's sale of an interest in a broadcast station to socially and economically disadvantaged minorities or women in order for the seller to elect to treat the sale as an involuntary conversion for which no gain is recognized for tax purposes or as an unrecognized gain to reduce the basis for determining gain or loss subject to an allowance for a depreciation deduction.

The FCC must adopt rules for the issuance of such certificates to: (1) limit the value of an interest the sale of which qualifies for such a certificate, (2) establish a minimum holding period following the sale during which the broadcast station must remain owned by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, (3) limit the total number or value of sales for which a person may be issued certificates, and (4) require participation by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals in the management of the broadcast station.

The FCC must report on: (1) recommendations to increase the total number of broadcast stations owned or controlled by minority groups or women, (2) annual sales for which certificates have been issued, (3) whether to expand the tax certificate program beyond broadcast stations to other FCC-regulated entities, and (4) whether there is a nexus between diversity of ownership or control of broadcast stations and diversity of the viewpoints broadcast by the stations.

The FCC must also establish a five-year pilot incubator program to grant waivers from ownership rules (local radio ownership rules, local television multiple ownership rules, or radio-television cross-ownership rules) to licensees to enable them to acquire an otherwise prohibited interest in a broadcast station owned by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
