<bill session="115" type="h" number="4000" updated="2017-10-13T18:45:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Loan Relief Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Loan Relief Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of a mechanism to allow borrowers of Federal student loans to refinance their loans, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend the exclusion for employer-provided educational assistance to employer payment of interest on certain refinanced student loans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Student Loan Relief Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001105"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-10-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Loan Relief Act of 2017

This bill authorizes the Department of the Treasury to establish a temporary three-year program to facilitate federal student loan refinancing into the private market, at no cost to the federal government, to ensure payment of lower interest rates on student loans. Private lenders under such refinancing program shall be eligible to receive a federal government guarantee of 95% of loans.

Treasury shall, in consultation with the Department of Education, begin a national awareness campaign to alert student loan borrowers about such refinancing program with a disclosure that a private loan that results from such refinancing is not eligible for income driven repayment or loan forgivingness.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an exclusion from gross income for the payment of an employer, either to an employee or a lender, of any indebtedness of an employee under a qualified education refinance loan or any interest relating to such a loan. The term "qualified education refinance loan" means any indebtedness used solely to refinance a qualified education loan with respect to which the lender offers the borrower protection in the event of unemployment or financial hardship.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
