<bill session="115" type="h" number="2236" updated="2017-09-28T20:00:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foster and Homeless Youth Food Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foster and Homeless Youth Food Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to provide certain alternative eligibility requirements applicable to foster care youth, and homeless youth, who are enrolled at least half-time in an institution of higher education.</title>
    <title type="display">Foster and Homeless Youth Food Security Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2017-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2017-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000580" joined="2017-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2017-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2017-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Nutrition" code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Foster and Homeless Youth Food Security Act of 2017 

This bill amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to modify certain Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) eligibility requirements for foster care and homeless youth who are enrolled at least half-time in an institution of higher education.

The bill applies to foster care individuals or homeless individuals who are over 17 and not over 26 years of age, and enrolled at least half-time in an institution of higher education. The bill exempts the individuals from: (1) certain eligibility disqualification rules that apply to students enrolled at least half-time in an institution of higher education, and (2) SNAP work requirements.

If the individual is enrolled at least half-time in an institution of higher education that provides the individual with housing that lacks an individualized cooking facility, the bill also: (1) modifies the definition of "food" to permit SNAP benefits to be used for certain meals prepared and served by the institution, and (2) permits the individual to be treated as a separate household for the purpose of SNAP benefits.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
