<bill session="115" type="h" number="2965" updated="2017-10-11T22:00:17Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gas Pump Access Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gas Pump Access Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require all gas stations offering self-service to meet certain accessibility standards for individuals with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Gas Pump Access Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000593"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Gas Pump Access Act of 2017&#160;

This bill declares that it shall be a prohibited form of discrimination against individuals with disabilities in a place of public accommodation under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 for a gas station or convenience store to fail to clearly display at each self-service gas pump a decal that includes its telephone number and the words "Call for Assistance."

A gas station or convenience store that is open for business to the public with at least two attendants on duty must provide gas pumping assistance to a qualified individual with a disability who makes a request for such assistance. But it shall not be considered discrimination for a gas station or convenience store with one attendant on duty to fail to provide such requested gas pumping assistance if such attendant notifies the individual that assistance cannot be provided because there is only one attendant on duty.

The Department of Transportation and the Department of Justice must promulgate regulations necessary to ensure compliance with this bill and make graphics for the decals publicly available on their websites.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
