<bill session="115" type="h" number="2454" updated="2017-09-21T04:29:58Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-12T13:05:27-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-09-12T13:05:27-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a data framework to provide access for appropriate personnel to law enforcement and other information of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:59:09-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hurd moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:59:21-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7243-7245" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T12:59:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2454.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-09-12T13:05:27-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7243" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12T13:05:28-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Counterterrorism and Intelligence" code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) develop a data framework to integrate existing DHS datasets and systems for access by authorized personnel in a manner consistent with relevant legal authorities and privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties policies and protections; (2) ensure that all information of a DHS office or component that falls within the scope of the information sharing environment, and any information or intelligence relevant to priority mission needs and capability requirements of the homeland security enterprise, is included; and (3) ensure that the framework is accessible to DHS employees who have an appropriate security clearance, who are assigned to perform a function that requires access, and who are trained in applicable standards for safeguarding and using such information.

DHS shall issue guidance for DHS employees authorized to access and contribute to the framework that enforces a duty to share between DHS offices and components for mission needs.

DHS may exclude information that could:

 jeopardize the protection of sources, methods, or activities; compromise a criminal or national security investigation; be inconsistent with the other federal laws or regulations; or be duplicative or not serve an operational purpose. DHS shall incorporate into such framework systems capabilities for auditing and ensuring the security of information.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
