<bill session="115" type="s" number="623" updated="2017-09-20T04:51:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">READ Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">READ Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the transparency and accelerate the impact of assistance provided under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to promote quality basic education in developing countries, to better enable such countries to achieve universal access to quality basic education and improved learning outcomes, to eliminate duplication and waste, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">READ Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2017-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2017-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2017-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2017-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2017-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="601"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act or the READ Act

This bill amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to state that it shall be U.S. policy to work with partner countries, other donors, multilateral institutions, the private sector, and nongovernmental and civil society organizations (including faith-based organizations) to promote basic education through programs that: (1) respond to the needs and capacities of developing countries to improve literacy and other basic skills; (2) strengthen educational systems, expand access to safe learning environments (including by breaking down barriers to basic education for women and girls), and support the engagement of parents in their children's education; (3) promote education as a foundation for economic growth; and (4) monitor and evaluate the effectiveness and quality of basic education programs in partner countries.

The President shall: (1) seek to improve the effectiveness of assistance by coordinating relevant executive branch efforts, (2) ensure that assistance is aligned with U.S. foreign policy and economic interests, and (3) submit to Congress by October 1, 2017, a comprehensive FY2018 through FY2022 strategy to promote basic education in partner countries.

The bill establishes within the U.S. Agency for International Development the position of Senior Coordinator of United States International Basic Education Assistance, who shall have primary responsibility for the oversight and coordination of U.S. government resources and activities relating to the promotion of international basic education.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
