<bill session="115" type="h" number="1332" updated="2017-09-14T22:30:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Early Childhood Nutrition Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Early Childhood Nutrition Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to improve the child and adult care food program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Early Childhood Nutrition Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2017-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2017-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-02T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Early Childhood Nutrition Improvement Act

This bill amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to revise several provisions related to the child and adult care food program.

Under current law: (1)&#160;an institution that provides child or day care under the program may be reimbursed for up to two meals and one supplement per day per child; and (2)&#160;a&#160;family or group day care home sponsoring organization may receive the same&#160;maximum reimbursement, but&#160;only with respect to a child maintained in a child care setting for at least eight hours per day. The bill eliminates this distinction between institutions and sponsoring organizations, and increases maximum reimbursement for both to: (1) two meals and one supplement or one meal and two supplements per day per child; or (2) three meals and one supplement or two meals and two supplements per day per child, for each child maintained in a child care setting for at least eight hours per day.

Reimbursements to family or group day care home sponsoring organizations must be adjusted annually to reflect the Consumer Price Index for food away from home, rather than the Consumer Price Index for food at home used under current law.

A determination of a for-profit day care center's eligibility to participate in the program shall be in effect for six months.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA)&#160;must issue guidance and, as appropriate, regulations to assist in ensuring a fair and effective process for the identification, review, and&#160;correction of serious program deficiencies.

USDA&#160;shall establish an advisory committee to examine the feasibility of reducing unnecessary or duplicative paperwork for those participating or seeking to participate in the program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
