<bill session="115" type="h" number="3046" updated="2017-09-06T07:13:45Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Help All Americans Save for College Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Help All Americans Save for College Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude employer contributions to 529 plans from gross income and employment taxes and to allow a deduction for individual contributions to such plans.</title>
    <title type="display">Help All Americans Save for College Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000611"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2017-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2017-08-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000171" joined="2017-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2017-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Trade" code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Help All Americans Save for College Act of 2017

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to modify the tax treatment of qualified tuition programs (known as 529 plans) and ABLE accounts. (Tax-favored ABLE [Achieving a Better Life Experience] accounts are designed to enable individuals with disabilities to save for and pay for disability-related expenses.)

The bill excludes employer contributions to an employee's 529 plan or ABLE account from the gross income of an individual, certain employment taxes, and taxes on self-employment earnings.

The exclusions are limited to the lesser of: (1) the compensation includible in the individual's gross income for the year, or (2) $5,000 ($10,000 in the case of a joint return) for each dependent of the taxpayer who is the designated beneficiary of a 529 plan.

The bill also allows an individual to deduct up to $5,000 of the aggregate contributions of the individual to a 529 plan and an ABLE account.

The bill revises the 10% additional tax for distributions from a 529 plan or an ABLE account that are not used for qualified purposes to change the rate to the greater of: (1) 10%, or (2) the highest rate of income tax applicable to the taxpayer.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
