<bill session="115" type="h" number="900" updated="2017-07-25T19:30:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To recognize Puerto Rico's sovereign nationhood under either independence or free association and to provide for a transition process, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To recognize Puerto Rico's sovereign nationhood under either independence or free association and to provide for a transition process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000535"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1248-1249"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Legislative Assembly of Puerto Rico to provide for a referendum in Puerto Rico in which eligible voters shall express their preference between the non-territorial options of either independence or free association.

 An individual shall be eligible to vote in such referendum if that individual was born in, or has a parent who was born in, Puerto Rico.

 The President shall negotiate a Treaty of Friendship and Cooperation and other bilateral agreements with the government of an independent Puerto Rico that will provide for equitable economic relations. Such treaty shall establish the details of the bilateral relations of Puerto Rico and the United States under specified guidelines with respect to citizenship, vested rights, trade, public debt and economic transition, currency, and defense.

The President shall negotiate the terms for a Compact of Free Association with the government of Puerto Rico, which shall be submitted to Congress and the people of Puerto Rico for ratification under specified agreed guidelines with respect to Puerto Rican sovereignty and self-government, the termination of the free association relationship when Puerto Rico becomes fully independent, the continuation of U.S. citizenship for citizens of Puerto Rico, and the continuation of trade relations with the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
