<bill session="115" type="s" number="883" updated="2017-07-20T16:56:22Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Offshore Production and Energizing National Security Alaska Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Offshore Production and Energizing National Security Alaska Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">OPENS Alaska Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">OPENS Alaska Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for reforms of the administration of the outer Continental Shelf of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">OPENS Alaska Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2017-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Scientific communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Offshore Production and Energizing National Security Alaska Act of 2017 or the OPENS Alaska Act of 2017

This bill nullifies the memorandum issued by the President on December 20, 2016, entitled "Withdrawal of Certain Portions of the United States Arctic Outer Continental Shelf from Mineral Leasing." The bill also nullifies any other presidential action to prohibit mineral leasing in certain portions of the Arctic Outer Continental Shelf.

The bill directs the Department of the Interior to establish a Nearshore Beaufort Sea Planning Area in the Outer Continental Shelf within three nautical miles of the seaward boundary of Alaska and conduct one oil and gas lease sale under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) in such planning area and the Cook Inlet Planning Area in each of FY2018-FY2020.

Oil and gas leases under the OCSLA shall have an initial 20-year lease period if they are located in the portion of the Beaufort Planning Area or the Chukchi Planning Area beyond 3 nautical miles of the seaward boundary of Alaska.

The OCSLA is amended to establish a scheme for revenue allocation between the Treasury and the state of Alaska.

Interior shall include in any leasing program at least three lease sales in each of the Beaufort Planning Area and the Chukchi Planning Area, as well as annual lease sales in the Nearshore Beaufort Sea Planning Area and the Cook Inlet Planning Area.

Interior shall establish a grant program for activities to improve the resilience of Indian tribes to the effects of climate change, build Native American communities, and aid the modernization of infrastructure. The bill also establishes the Tribal Resilience Fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
