<bill session="115" type="h" number="1693" updated="2017-09-11T03:02:57Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Contract Procurement for Small Businesses through More Accurate Reporting Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Contract Procurement for Small Businesses through More Accurate Reporting Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to add reporting requirements for certain small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Improving Contract Procurement for Small Businesses through More Accurate Reporting Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2017-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2810"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1773"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-23T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Contract Procurement for Small Businesses through More Accurate Reporting Act of 2017

This bill amends the Small Business Act to require the Small Business Administration to report to the President and Congress an analysis of the number and dollar amount of prime contracts awarded by federal agencies each fiscal year to small business concerns, including those:

 owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans; located in qualified HUBZones; owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals; owned by an Indian tribe, an Alaska Native Corporation, or a Native Hawaiian Organization; or owned and controlled by women. The analyses shall cover all such small business concerns:

 that were purchased by another entity after the initial contract was awarded and as a result would no longer be deemed to be small business concerns for purposes of the initial contract, and that were awarded using a procurement method that restricted competition to the kinds of small business concerns listed here or a subset of any of them.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
