<bill session="115" type="h" number="2774" updated="2017-10-05T13:00:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hack DHS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hack DHS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hack the Department of Homeland Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hack the Department of Homeland Security Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a bug bounty pilot program within the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Hack DHS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2017-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2017-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2017-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2017-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2017-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000477" joined="2017-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies" code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="3868"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1281"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Hack the Department of Homeland Security Act of 2017 or the Hack DHS Act

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a bug bounty pilot program to minimize vulnerabilities to DHS information systems.

 "Bug bounty program" is a program under which an approved computer security specialist or security researcher is temporarily authorized to identify and report vulnerabilities within DHS information systems in exchange for cash payment.

Under such program, DHS shall:

 provide monetary compensation for reports of previously unidentified security vulnerabilities within the websites, applications, and other DHS information systems that are accessible to the public; develop an expeditious process by which computer security researchers can register for the program, submit to a background check, and receive a determination as to approval for program participation; designate mission-critical operations within DHS that should be excluded; consult with the Department of Justice on how to ensure that program participants are protected from prosecution for activities authorized under the program; award competitive contracts to manage the program and for executing the remediation of identified vulnerabilities; and engage interested persons, including commercial sector representatives, about the structure of the program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
