<bill session="115" type="h" number="236" updated="2017-05-04T00:17:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conveyance of certain property to the Tanana Tribal Council located in Tanana, Alaska, and to the Bristol Bay Area Health Corporation located in Dillingham, Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To provide for the conveyance of certain property to the Tanana Tribal Council located in Tanana, Alaska, and to the Bristol Bay Area Health Corporation located in Dillingham, Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="269"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to convey to the Tanana Tribal Council in Tanana, Alaska, all interest of the United States in and to certain property (including all land, improvements, and appurtenances) containing 11.25 acres, in the village of Tanana for use in connection with health and social services programs.

HHS shall convey to the Bristol Bay Area Health Corporation in Dillingham, Alaska, all interest of the United States in and to certain property included in the Dental Annex Subdivision (including all land, improvements, and appurtenances) containing 1.474 acres more or less, also for use in connection with health and social services programs.

Neither the Tanana Tribal Council nor the Corporation shall be liable for soil, surface water, groundwater, or other contamination resulting from the disposal, release, or presence of environmental contamination, including oil or petroleum products, or hazardous substances on any of the properties.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
