<bill session="115" type="sj" number="22" updated="2017-09-11T03:06:22Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-16">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution granting the consent and approval of Congress to the Commonwealth of Virginia, the State of Maryland, and the District of Columbia to enter into a compact relating to the establishment of the Washington Metrorail Safety Commission.</title>
    <title type="display">A joint resolution granting the consent and approval of Congress to the Commonwealth of Virginia, the State of Maryland, and the District of Columbia to enter into a compact relating to the establishment of the Washington Metrorail Safety Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2017-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2017-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1220" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-16">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2955-2959" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2017-05-16" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2956-2959" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17T12:38:05-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-17T20:20:43-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hj" session="115" relation="unknown" number="76"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-16T12:39:46Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Interstate Compact

This joint resolution grants congressional consent and approval for the Commonwealth of Virginia, the state of Maryland, and the District of Columbia to enter into a Metrorail Safety Commission (MSC) Interstate Compact.

The MSC Compact establishes a Washington Metrorail Safety Commission for the safety oversight of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) Rail (Metrorail) system.

The commission shall:

 distribute a written State Safety Oversight Program; enforce implementation of WMATA's Public Transportation Agency Safety Plan, as well as audit triennially WMATA's compliance with such plan; enforce implementation of any Corrective Action Plans; enforce relevant federal and state laws and regulations relating to Metrorail safety; publish annually a Metrorail safety report, including updates of Corrective Action Plans, Commission directives, and on-going investigations; and publish annually a report on commission operations. An independent annual audit shall be made of commission financial accounts.

Any signatory may withdraw from the MSC Compact, which shall constitute its termination.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
