<bill session="115" type="h" number="584" updated="2017-09-22T14:00:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-31T16:10:24-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-01-31T16:10:24-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Cyber Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Cyber Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cyber Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cyber Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance preparedness and response capabilities for cyber attacks, bolster the dissemination of homeland security information related to cyber threats, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cyber Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000625"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2017-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000601" joined="2017-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T16:01:01-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Donovan moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T16:01:09-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H793-794" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T16:01:11-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 584.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-01-31T16:10:24-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H793" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-31T16:10:26-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2922"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-31T13:47:01Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Cyber Preparedness Act of 2017

(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) State, Local, and Regional Fusion Center Initiative to coordinate with the national cybersecurity and communications integration center (NCCIC) to provide state, local, and regional fusion centers with expertise on DHS cybersecurity resources. (A fusion center serves as a focal point within the state and local environment for the receipt, analysis, gathering, and sharing of threat-related information between the federal government and state, local, tribal, territorial, and private sector partners.)

DHS must: (1) provide timely access to technical assistance, risk management support, and incident response capabilities for cybersecurity threat indicators, defensive measures, risks, and incidents, including cybersecurity risks to equipment and technology related to the electoral process; (2) review cybersecurity risk information gathered by fusion centers to incorporate into DHS's cybersecurity risk information; and (3) disseminate cybersecurity risk information to fusion centers.

Fusion center officers or intelligence analysts may be assigned from the NCCIC. Such officers and analysts must assist fusion centers in using cybersecurity risk information to develop a comprehensive and accurate threat picture.

The NCCIC may include, and must share analysis and best practices with, state and major urban area fusion centers.

(Sec. 3) States, local or tribal governments, or high-risk urban areas receiving grants to protect against terrorism under the Urban Area Security Initiative or the State Homeland Security Grant Program may use the funds to: (1) prepare for and respond to cybersecurity risks and incidents, and (2) develop statewide cyber threat information analysis and dissemination activities.

 (Sec. 4) The bill expresses the sense of Congress that DHS should share actionable information related to cyber threats in an unclassified form to facilitate timely dissemination to state, local, and private sector stakeholders.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
