<bill session="115" type="h" number="1086" updated="2017-06-19T21:00:12Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving Public Access to Federal Buildings Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving Public Access to Federal Buildings Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require executive agencies to notify the public and consider public comment before relocating an office of the agency that has regular contact with the public, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Preserving Public Access to Federal Buildings Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000580"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Preserving Public Access to Federal Buildings Act of 2017

This bill requires an executive agency to provide notice and an opportunity for public comment before relocating any agency office that has regular contact with the public. Such requirement shall apply to a relocation proposed by the agency or a reassignment of agency office space by the General Services Administration.

Before providing notice, an agency shall determine if it expects the relocation to impact the ability of the office's clientele to access its services. If so, the agency shall develop an initial plan to address the impact.

If the announced relocation receives substantial public interest, the agency shall:

 conduct an in-depth evaluation of the potential impact of the relocation on the ability of the office's clientele to access services; develop a plan to address such impact or revise the initial plan; and publish the results of the evaluation and a description of the plan on the agency's website. The Office of Management and Budget must issue guidance for agencies on the meaning of "regular contact with the public" and "substantial public interest."</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
