<bill session="115" type="s" number="678" updated="2017-09-20T05:50:02Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">English Language Unity Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">English Language Unity Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to delcare English as the official language of the United States, to establish a uniform English language rule for naturalization, and to avoid misconstructions of the English language texts of the laws of the United States, pursuant to Congress' powers to provide for the general welfare of the United States and to establish a uniform rule of naturalization under article I, section 8, of the Constitution.</title>
    <title type="display">English Language Unity Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2017-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2017-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2017-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001202" joined="2017-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="997"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">English Language Unity Act of 2017

This bill establishes English as the official language of the United States.

Naturalization ceremonies and official functions of the U.S. government, subject to exceptions, must be conducted in English.

The bill declares that all citizens should be able to read and understand generally the English language text of U.S. laws.

A person injured by a violation of this Act may obtain relief, including a declaratory judgment, in a civil action.

English language requirements and workplace policies, whether in the public or private sector,&#160;shall be presumptively consistent with U.S. laws. Any ambiguity in&#160;U.S. laws&#160; shall be resolved in accordance with the rights retained by the people and the powers reserved to states under the Bill of Rights.

The Department of Homeland Security shall issue a proposed rule for uniform testing of the English language ability of candidates for naturalization based upon the principles that: (1) all citizens should be able to read and understand generally the English language text of the Declaration of Independence, the Constitution, and the laws of the United States; and (2) any exceptions to this standard should be limited to extraordinary circumstances, such as asylum.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
