<bill session="115" type="s" number="42" updated="2017-06-19T20:30:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inspiring the Next Space Pioneers, Innovators, Researchers, and Explorers (INSPIRE) Women Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inspiring the Next Space Pioneers, Innovators, Researchers, and Explorers (INSPIRE) Women Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to inspire women to enter the aerospace field, including science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, through mentorship and outreach.</title>
    <title type="display">Inspiring the Next Space Pioneers, Innovators, Researchers, and Explorers (INSPIRE) Women Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="321"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Inspiring the Next Space Pioneers, Innovators, Researchers, and Explorers (INSPIRE) Women Act

This bill directs the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to encourage women and girls to study science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM), pursue careers in aerospace, and further advance the nation's space science and exploration efforts through support of the following initiatives:

 NASA GIRLS and NASA BOYS; Aspire to Inspire; and Summer Institute in Science, Technology, Engineering, and Research. NASA shall submit to Congress a specified plan on how NASA can best facilitate and support both current and retired astronauts, scientists, engineers, and innovators, including early career female astronauts, scientists, engineers, and innovators, to engage with K-12 female STEM students and inspire the next generation of women to consider participating in STEM fields and to pursue careers in aerospace.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
