<bill session="115" type="h" number="746" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Campus Fire Safety Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Campus Fire Safety Education Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Education to make grants to support fire safety education programs on college campuses.</title>
    <title type="display">Campus Fire Safety Education Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2017-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2017-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2017-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2017-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2017-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="246"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-30T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Campus Fire Safety Education Act of 2017

 This bill directs the Department of Education (ED) to establish a program to award grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education or consortiums of such institutions, in a collaborative partnership with a nonprofit organization or a public safety department (eligible entity), for: (1) initiating, expanding, or improving fire safety education programs; and (2) increasing fire safety awareness among enrolled students.

ED shall give priority to institutions that plan to use funds to initiate, expand, or improve fire safety education programs that include educational material specifically prepared for students with physical, sensory, or cognitive disabilities. The bill sets forth provisions regarding grant periods and matching and other requirements. An eligible entity may not be awarded more than $250,000 per fiscal year under this bill.

An eligible entity shall use grant funds to initiate, expand, or improve a fire safety education program that:

 reaches all enrolled students (for an institution of higher education); ensures maximum exposure to, increases awareness of, and effectuates change in behavior regarding, fire safety by students through conducting outreach to students a minimum of twice per academic year and through measures that provide fire safety information to any student upon request; includes minimum instruction regarding fire behavior, fire injury and death, ignition scenarios, fire safety systems and equipment, the importance of means of egress, fire prevention techniques, and actions to be taken if a fire occurs to minimize the potential for death, injury, and property damage; and includes a mechanism for carrying out evaluations of program effectiveness. ED shall publish a report of best practices for initiating, expanding, or improving fire safety education programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
