<bill session="115" type="h" number="1106" updated="2017-06-19T21:00:11Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Tracts Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Tracts Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conveyance of small parcels of National Forest System land and small parcels of public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management to private landowners, State, county, and local governments, or Indian tribes whose lands share a boundary with the National Forest System land or public lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Small Tracts Conveyance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Tracts Conveyance Act

 This bill requires the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for a state (respecting certain public lands) or the Regional Forester with jurisdiction over the National Forest System (NFS) land of a specific Forest Service Region (respecting certain NFS lands) to select an eligible federal lands parcel for conveyance: (1) in response to a request by an adjacent landholder (any holder of non-federal land that shares one or more boundaries with such a parcel and who requests to purchase such a parcel), or (2) upon the recommendation of the BLM District Office or NFS unit that exercises administration over such parcel.

 The Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior shall each create a process by which an adjacent landholder may request to purchase an eligible parcel.

 A conveyed eligible parcel may not exceed 160 acres unless the BLM or the Forest Service approves a request for additional acreage. An adjacent landholder may only acquire one eligible parcel a year, subject to an exception.

 The BLM or the Forest Service, as consideration for the sale of an eligible parcel, shall require a cash payment that is equal to at least the fair market value of such parcel, including the mineral estate, being conveyed.

 The purchaser of an eligible federal lands parcel under this bill shall cover the costs to be incurred, or to reimburse the BLM or the Forest Service for the costs incurred, in carrying out the conveyance.

 A conveyance of an eligible federal lands parcel under this bill is categorically excluded from the requirement to prepare an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
