<bill session="115" type="s" number="464" updated="2017-09-15T05:25:53Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Independence at Home Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Independence at Home Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for a permanent Independence at Home medical practice program under the Medicare program.</title>
    <title type="display">Independence at Home Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2017-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2017-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2017-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2017-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2017-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2017-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Independence at Home Act of 2017

This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to establish a permanent Independence at Home Medical Practice Program, under which a primary care&#160;practice&#160;shall be accountable for: (1)&#160;providing comprehensive, coordinated, continuous, and accessible care to applicable Medicare beneficiaries at home; and (2) coordinating health care across all treatment settings.

Subject to meeting specified quality performance standards, a participating practice&#160;is eligible to&#160;receive an incentive payment under the program if actual expenditures for applicable beneficiaries are less than&#160;the estimated spending target established by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS).

CMS shall terminate a program&#160;agreement with a participating practice if the practice: (1)&#160;for the third of three consecutive years under the program, will not receive an incentive payment; or (2) fails to meet a minimum number of quality performance standards established by CMS.

The bill extends the existing Independence at Home Medical Practice Demonstration Program pending implementation of the permanent program. In addition, the bill&#160;removes the limit on the number of beneficiaries that may participate in the demonstration program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
