<bill session="115" type="h" number="1489" updated="2017-07-05T18:45:10Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Marine Access and State Transparency</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Marine Access and State Transparency</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MAST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MAST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 54, United States Code, to provide for congressional approval of national monuments and restrictions on the use of national monuments, to establish requirements for declaration of marine national monuments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">MAST Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water, Power and Oceans" code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Federal Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="33"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Marine Access and State Transparency or the MAST Act

 This bill amends the Antiquities Act of 1906 to require the President, before a national monument can be designated on public land, to obtain congressional approval and certify compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.

 The bill bars the President from declaring any area of the exclusive economic zone to be a national monument unless:

 such a declaration is specifically authorized by an Act of Congress; the President has submitted a proposal to make the declaration to the governor of each state or territory located within 200 nautical miles of that area; each governor submits to the President a notice that the legislature of that state or territory has approved the proposal; and the declaration is substantially the same as the proposal. The bill prohibits the Department of the Interior or the Department of Commerce, with respect to any area of the exclusive economic zone that is designated as a national monument, from implementing any restrictions on the public use of such a national monument until the expiration of an appropriate review period providing for public input and congressional approval.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
