<bill session="115" type="s" number="183" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:18Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Short on Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Short on Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow for expedited approval of generic prescription drugs and temporary importation of prescription drugs in the case of noncompetitive drug markets and drug shortages.</title>
    <title type="display">Short on Competition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2017-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-20T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Short on Competition Act

This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to authorize importation of life-saving drugs for which there is, or is likely to be, a shortage. For a drug to be imported, the drug's manufacturer must intend to seek FDA approval of the drug as a generic drug. The FDA may deny importation of a drug for reasons related to safety or effectiveness.

Drugs in noncompetitive markets must be treated as being in a shortage for purposes of this bill and for purposes of expedited inspections and review. A drug is in a noncompetitive market if: (1) there are fewer than five holders of approved applications for commercially available brand name or generic versions of the drug, (2) the drug has been approved for at least 10 years, and (3) patents on the active ingredient of the drug have expired.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
