<bill session="115" type="h" number="2691" updated="2017-06-23T20:00:09Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Everglades for the Next Generation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Everglades for the Next Generation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Resources Development Act of 2000 to provide for expedited project implementation relating to the comprehensive Everglades restoration plan.</title>
    <title type="display">Everglades for the Next Generation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2017-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="1234"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Everglades for the Next Generation Act

This bill amends the Water Resources Development Act of 2000 to authorize the Department of the Army, after completing an implementation report prepared for a project under the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan and without any further congressional authorization, to carry out: (1) any project identified in the plan for which a project implementation report is completed that is in accordance with an integrated delivery schedule approved by the Corps of Engineers and the South Florida Water Management District, provided that the report is completed by five years after the date of the enactment of this bill; and (2) any group of projects under the plan that the Corps determines will provide regional or watershed ecosystem or water supply benefits if constructed in accordance with a project implementation report approved by the Corps and the district by such date.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
