<bill session="115" type="h" number="2189" updated="2017-09-27T19:15:14Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trade Protection Not Troll Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trade Protection Not Troll Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 with respect to requirements for domestic industries, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Trade Protection Not Troll Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000460" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2017-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2017-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2017-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Trade" code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. International Trade Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-04-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Trade Protection Not Troll Protection Act

This bill amends the Tariff Act of 1930, with respect to unfair practices in the import trade, to consider an industry in the United States to exist if there is in the United States substantial investment in licensing activities that leads to the adoption and development of articles that incorporate the patent, copyright, trademark, mask work, or design.

If the U.S. International Trade Commission (ITC), at the beginning of an investigation of an alleged unfair practice, identifies a domestic industry as the dispositive issue in question, it shall direct the assigned administrative law judge (ALJ) to:

 expedite fact finding on the domestic industry requirement, and issue an initial determination on this matter within 100 days after the investigation begins. Any initial determination by the assigned ALJ shall stay the investigation pending ITC action.

The ITC may determine during an investigation that exclusion of the articles concerned from entry into the United States would not be in the public interest, and terminate the investigation, in whole or in part, without any further determination, after considering the nature of the articles concerned and the effect of exclusion upon:

 the public health and welfare, the U.S. economy (including competitive conditions), the production of like or directly competitive articles by the complainant and its licensees, and U.S. consumers. Any person adversely affected by an ITC ruling that identifies a domestic industry as the dispositive issue in question may appeal that ruling, within 60 days after all administrative remedies are exhausted, to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.

ITC discretion not to exclude any articles concerned, even though an importer has violated the ban on unfair competition, is repealed. If the ITC also determines that exclusion would be in the public interest, it shall direct exclusion of the articles.

During an investigation, if the ITC determines there is reason to believe that an unfair import practice has occurred, and exclusion of the articles concerned would be in the public interest, the ITC may direct the exclusion the articles concerned, after considering the factors mentioned above. (Currently the ITC may not direct an exclusion until an investigation concludes and it determines, as a result of the investigation, that an unfair import trade practice has occurred.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
