<bill session="115" type="h" number="1254" updated="2017-06-19T21:15:23Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Health ID Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Health ID Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program under which eligible veterans may elect to receive hospital care and medical services at non-Department of Veterans Affairs facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans Health ID Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000554"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Health ID Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out a two-year pilot program under which: (1) eligible veterans may elect to receive hospital care and services at non-VA facilities, and (2) the VA shall reimburse such facilities for the cost of such care and services.

An "eligible veteran" is a veteran who: (1) is enrolled in the VA's patient enrollment system, and (2) resides in a geographic area selected by the VA. The VA shall select: (1) one geographic area within each Veterans Integrated Service Network, and (2) NJ-2 as the geographic area for participation in the pilot program for Veterans Integrated Service Network 4.

The VA shall: (1) issue a unique identification card to each eligible veteran who elects to receive hospital care and medical services at non-VA facilities under the pilot program, and (2) take steps to ensure that such veterans receive such care and services at such non-VA facilities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
