<bill session="115" type="sr" number="150" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:35Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing threats to freedom of the press and expression around the world and reaffirming freedom of the press as a priority in efforts of the United States Government to promote democracy and good governance.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution recognizing threats to freedom of the press and expression around the world and reaffirming freedom of the press as a priority in efforts of the United States Government to promote democracy and good governance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2017-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2725" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-03T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Welcomes the celebration of World Press Freedom Day 2017 on May 3, 2017.

Commends journalists and media workers around the world for their role in promoting government accountability, defending democratic activity, and strengthening civil society, despite threats to their safety. Pays tribute to journalists who have lost their lives or liberty carrying out their work.

Calls on governments abroad to implement United Nations General Assembly Resolution 163 (1963) by investigating and seeking to resolve cases of violence against journalists and by reporting on the investigations.

Expresses concern about the threats to freedom of the press and expression around the world and condemns actions that suppress it.

Calls on the President and the Secretary of State to:

 build upon U.S. leadership in freedom of the press; improve the means by which the U.S. government identifies, publicizes, and responds to threats against freedom of the press around the world; urge foreign governments to conduct transparent investigations and adjudications of the perpetrators of attacks against journalists; and highlight the issue of threats against freedom of the press in the annual Human Rights Reports and year round.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
