<bill session="115" type="h" number="2626" updated="2017-09-26T22:30:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strong Visa Integrity Secures America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strong Visa Integrity Secures America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Strong Visa Integrity Secures America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 and the Immigration and Nationality Act to improve visa security, visa applicant vetting, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Strong Visa Integrity Secures America Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2017-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2017-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-24">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-24">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-07-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-08-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 115-273, Part I.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Border and Maritime Security" code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1757"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Strong Visa Integrity Secures America Act

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of State to assign, in a risk-based manner, State Department employees to at least 30 visa-issuing diplomatic and consular posts based upon the following criteria:

 the number of nationals of a country in which such posts are located who were identified in U.S. terrorist databases, such a country's counterterrorism cooperation with the United States, the adequacy of border and immigration control of such country, terrorist organization activity in such country, and the number of negative security advisory opinions regarding nationals of such country. Such employees shall, in addition to other duties, screen admissions applications against federal criminal, national security, and terrorism databases.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall:

 establish within U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement a visa security advisory opinion unit to respond to State Department requests for visa security reviews; and provide, in a risk-based manner, for remote pre-adjudicated visa security assistance at posts that are not assigned such employees. U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) shall:

 screen electronic passports at U.S. entry airports by reading each passport's embedded chip, and utilize facial recognition or other biometric technology to screen travelers at such airports. Electronic passport screening shall apply to U.S. citizens, nationals of a visa waiver program country, and nationals of any other foreign country that issues electronic passports.

Facial recognition or other biometric technology shall apply to nationals of a visa waiver program country.

The CBP shall, in a risk-based manner, continuously screen individuals issued any visa and individuals who are visa waiver program nationals against criminal, national security, and terrorism databases.

The annual visa overstay report is revised.

DHS shall ensure that certain foreign student information is available at each U.S. port of entry to CBP officers who inspect aliens seeking U.S. admission.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-273</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
