<bill session="115" type="s" number="728" updated="2017-09-11T02:57:56Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RECLAIM Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RECLAIM Act of2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Revitalizing the Economy of Coal Communities by Leveraging Local Activities and Investing More Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Revitalizing the Economy of Coal Communities byLeveraging Local Activities and InvestingMore Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to provide funds to States and Indian tribes for the purpose of promoting economic revitalization, diversification, and development in economically distressed communities through the reclamation and restoration of land and water resources adversely affected by coal mining carried out before August 3, 1977, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">RECLAIM Act of2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000355"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2017-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1997-1999" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="738"/>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="identical" number="1731"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Revitalizing the Economy of Coal Communities by Leveraging Local Activities and Investing More Act of 2017 or the RECLAIM Act of 2017

This bill amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (SMCRA)to make specified funds available to the Department of the Interior through FY2021 for distribution to states and Indian tribes to promote economic revitalization, diversification, and development in economically distressed communities through the reclamation and restoration of land and water resources adversely affected by coal mining carried out before August 3, 1977.

The bill prescribes general requirements for projects to reclaim abandoned mine lands and waters that are likely to create favorable conditions for the economic development of the project site or promote the general welfare through economic and community development of the area in which the project is conducted. Any such project shall be located in a community affected by a recent decline in mining.

A state or Indian tribe that receives funds under this bill may retain a portion of them as necessary to supplement its acid mine drainage abatement and treatment fund for future operation and maintenance costs for the treatment of acid mine drainage associated with individual projects.

The bill increases the minimum amount of funds that Interior must provide annually to states and Indian tribes for reclamation and restoration projects.

The Government Accountability Office must conduct a study on the use of funds authorized by this bill.

The Appalachian Regional Commission may provide grants to individuals or entities in the Appalachian region for projects that have been or that are eligible to be reclaimed or restored under SMCRA.The commission must relocate its headquarters from Washington, DC to the Appalachian region.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
