<bill session="115" type="h" number="2384" updated="2017-09-11T03:03:01Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping America's Pension Promises Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping America&#8217;s Pension Promises Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify certain provisions relating to multiemployer pensions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Keeping America's Pension Promises Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2412"/>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1076"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Keeping America's Pension Promises Act 

This bill repeals the elimination of the pension anti-cutback provisions under the Multiemployer Pension Reform Act of 2014. The anti-cutback provisions prohibit reductions in pension benefits to participants in multiemployer pension plans.

The bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), with respect to partitions of eligible multiemployer plans, to modify the procedures and allow plan sponsors to petition the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) for a partition of additional financially-troubled pension plans.

The PBGC must establish a legacy fund to cover the administrative and benefit costs resulting from a partition. The Department of the Treasury must transfer amounts to the fund that are equal to the increase in revenues as a result of specified provisions of this bill that amend the Internal Revenue Code.

The provisions amend the Internal Revenue Code to impose a .03% excise tax on certain trading transactions with respect to securities.

The bill amends the federal bankruptcy code to assign first claim priority to pension obligations under ERISA.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
