<bill session="115" type="s" number="1097" updated="2017-08-30T04:31:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Armed Forces Reserve and National Guard Dual-Status Review and Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Armed Forces Reserve and National Guard Dual-Status Review and Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to postpone the deadline for the completion of the conversion of certain military technician (dual status) positions to positions of civilian employment by the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Armed Forces Reserve and National Guard Dual-Status Review and Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2918" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2917-2918" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-05-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Armed Forces Reserve and National Guard Dual-Status Review and Modernization Act

This bill postpones the deadline for conversion of at least 20% of all military technician (dual status) positions to positions of civilian employment in the federal government until 180 days after the Department of Defense transmits to Congress the report of the Working Group on Full Time Support of the Reserve Components, established by this bill.

The working group shall undertake a comprehensive review of full time support of the reserve components of the Armed Forces, including:

 an identification of the missions, purposes, and objectives of military technicians (dual status) in support of an operational reserve force; a review of the posture of such positions and their role in meeting such objectives; an analysis of potential workforce restructuring to fully align such positions with objectives for full time support of the reserve components; an identification of such positions the conversion of which to federal civilian positions would best ensure the achievement of such objectives; an assessment of the impact of such conversion on the readiness of the National Guard for domestic operations; and an assessment of costs and potential savings associated with such conversion.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
