<bill session="115" type="h" number="650" updated="2017-06-19T20:45:19Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MANIFEST for Human Spaceflight Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MANIFEST for Human Spaceflight Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mapping a New and Innovative Focus on Our Exploration Strategy for Human Spaceflight Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mapping a New and Innovative Focus on Our Exploration Strategy for Human Spaceflight Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the development of a United States strategy for greater human space exploration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">MANIFEST for Human Spaceflight Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001048"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Space" code="HSSY16" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="identical" number="212"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Mapping a New and Innovative Focus on Our Exploration Strategy for Human Spaceflight Act of 2017 or the MANIFEST for Human Spaceflight Act of 2017.

This bill amends the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 to make it a key U.S. objective to achieve human exploration of Mars, including the establishment of a capability to extend human presence to the surface of Mars.

The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) shall report a strategy to achieve such objective through a series of successive, sustainable, free-standing, but complementary missions making robust use of cislunar space and employing the Space Launch System, Orion crew capsule, and other capabilities provided under specified titles of the Act.

NASA shall arrange with the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) to review and comment on each interim report on the strategy and identify matters the NAS agrees with and matters raising NAS concerns, as well as any NAS recommendations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
