<bill session="115" type="h" number="1534" updated="2017-06-19T21:30:23Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Worker Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Worker Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program that provides dislocated workers with a subsidy or coupon that may be applied towards obtaining broadband Internet access service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">21st Century Worker Opportunity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000624"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Communications and Technology" code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">21st Century Worker Opportunity Act

This bill requires the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to implement a program that provides displaced workers with a subsidy or coupon for a lump sum payment of $500 that may only be applied towards: (1) broadband Internet access service, or (2) remote job training in a profession not likely to be automated in the next 20 years.

A "displaced worker" is defined as an individual who, due to automation of machinery that replaces human labor, has been terminated or laid off from employment or who has received a notice of termination or layoff from employment.

To be eligible for the program, a displaced worker who has been laid off or terminated must submit a certification from an employer that the worker was employed in the manufacturing sector and was laid off or terminated due to the automation of the position of the worker.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
