<bill session="115" type="hj" number="18" updated="2017-09-11T03:02:47Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution requiring that each agency and department's funding is justified.</title>
    <title type="display">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution requiring that each agency and department's funding is justified.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hj" session="115" relation="unknown" number="109"/>
    <bill type="hj" session="115" relation="unknown" number="1"/>
    <bill type="hj" session="115" relation="unknown" number="2"/>
    <bill type="hj" session="115" relation="unknown" number="14"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-04T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Constitutional Amendment 

This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment prohibiting total outlays for a fiscal year from exceeding total receipts for that fiscal year unless: (1) Congress authorizes the excess by a three-fifths vote of each chamber, and (2) total outlays do not exceed a specified percentage of the estimated gross domestic product of the United States. The prohibition excludes outlays for repayment of debt principal and receipts derived from borrowing.

The amendment requires a three-fifths vote of each chamber of Congress to increase revenue or increase the limit on the debt of the United States.

The President must submit an annual budget in which total outlays do not exceed total receipts and that includes justifications and specified details regarding funding proposed for departments and agencies.

Congress may waive the requirements due to a declaration of war, a military conflict, an event that causes an imminent and serious military threat to national security, or a natural disaster.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
