<bill session="115" type="h" number="3542" updated="2017-10-04T15:30:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hamas Human Shields Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hamas Human Shields Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose sanctions against Hamas for gross violations of internationally recognized human rights by reason of the use of civilians as human shields, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Hamas Human Shields Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000795"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2017-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2017-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-07-28T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Hamas Human Shields Prevention Act

This bill states that it is U.S. policy to: (1) condemn the use of human shields by Hamas as an act of terrorism and a violation of human rights and international humanitarian law, and (2) act against those engaging in or supporting the use of human shields.

The President is urged to direct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations (U.N.) to use U.S. influence at the U.N. Security Council to secure support for a resolution imposing multilateral sanctions against Hamas's use of human shields.

The President shall prohibit property transactions and U.S. entry with respect to: (1) each foreign person or entity that is a member of or acting on behalf of Hamas and that is responsible for or complicit in Hamas' use of human shields; and (2) each foreign person or entity and each agency or instrumentality of a foreign state that has significantly facilitated any act with respect to such use of human shields, provided material support to a listed person or entity, or attempted to facilitate or support such acts or persons.

The President may waive a sanction for 120 days with prior congressional certification that such waiver is vital to U.S. national security interests.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
