<bill session="115" type="h" number="1613" updated="2017-06-19T21:30:18Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HELP for Coal Miners Health Care Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HELP for Coal Miners Health Care Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Ensure Long-Term Protection for Coal Miners Health Care Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Ensure Long-Term Protection for Coal Miners Health Care Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to transfer certain funds to the Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">HELP for Coal Miners Health Care Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001108" joined="2017-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2017-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2017-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2017-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="115" relation="unknown" number="176"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-03-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping Ensure Long-Term Protection for Coal Miners Health Care Act of 2017 or the HELP for Coal Miners Health Care Act of 2017

This bill amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (SMCRA) to transfer certain funds to the Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan to provide health benefits to retired coal miners and their families.

The bill expands the group whose retiree health benefits are taken into account in determining the amount that the Department of the Treasury must transfer from the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund and the General Fund of the Treasury to the Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan.

The Government Accountability Office must study the Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan and submit to Congress reports analyzing whether federal funds are being spent appropriately by the plan.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal requirements for current and former signatories to labor agreements with the United Mineworkers of America to pay unassigned beneficiaries premiums or backstop premiums if transfers under SMCRA are less than the amount required to be transferred.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
