<bill session="115" type="s" number="436" updated="2017-09-11T02:39:41Z">
  <state datetime="2017-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">San Juan County Settlement Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">San Juan County Settlement Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to retire coal preference right lease applications for which the Secretary has made an affirmative commercial quantities determination, to substitute certain land selections of the Navajo Nation, to designate certain wilderness areas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">San Juan County Settlement Implementation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2017-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-26">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">San Juan County Settlement Implementation Act

This bill provides that if the Department of the Interior retires a coal preference right lease application under the Mineral Leasing Act by issuing a bidding right in exchange for the relinquishment of such application, such bidding right may subsequently be used in lieu of 50% of amount owed for any monetary payment of: (1) a bonus in a coal lease sale; or (2) rental or royalty under a federal coal lease.

Interior shall calculate a payment of the amounts owed to a relevant state pursuant to such Act based on the combined value of the bidding rights and the amounts received.

Interior shall make such payments to a relevant state from monetary payments received by Interior when bidding rights are exercised pursuant to this bill.

A bidding right issued for a coal preference right lease application under such Act shall be fully transferable to any other person. Such bidding right shall terminate seven years after it is issued.

The bill cancels specified land selections made by the Navajo Nation pursuant to the Navajo-Hopi Land Settlement Act of 1974 and authorizes such nation to make new selections equal in value to those canceled, subject to an acreage cap, specified land exclusions, and a seven-year deadline.

The bill designates specified parcels of land in New Mexico as: (1) the Ah-shi-sle-pah Wilderness, and (2) part of the Bisti/De-Na-Zin Wilderness.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
